<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Perfect Perusals</title>
<subtitle type="text">A Website.</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2013-09-04T17:37:56-07:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Thoughtful 'Quotes']]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/some-thoughtful-quotes" />
  <id>/some-thoughtful-quotes</id>
  <published>2013-09-04T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-09-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am in the middle of writing a big long book this week. And by “big long book” I mean not that very long and by “writing” I mean “just sitting around reading Wikipedia articles and thinking”. I felt myself getting way too caught up in all of the world building so I decided to take some time to re-address this blog and write something. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to write a little bit about a few quotes that I like. “Quote” is a very loose word. Some of these can be attributed. Some others cannot. Some of them I think are just things that I just &lt;em&gt;sensed&lt;/em&gt; that the writer might have said. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;david-foster-wallace---kenyon-college&quot;&gt;David Foster Wallace - Kenyon College&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There should be an entire section dedicated to this &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.archive.org/web/20080213082423/http://www.marginalia.org/dfw_kenyon_commencement.html&quot;&gt;one speech that he gave to Kenyon College&lt;/a&gt;. There is something about this speech that I really took to. I was never a fan of his writing, to be honest. I did not like Infinite Jest. I kind of enjoyed the one he wrote about cruises. I did enjoy his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gourmet.com/magazine/2000s/2004/08/consider_the_lobster&quot;&gt;“Consider the Lobster”&lt;/a&gt;, which was the best article that I have ever read about a food that I cannot eat. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Worship your intellect, being seen as smart, you will end up feeling stupid, a fraud, always on the verge of being found out. But the insidious thing about these forms of worship is not that they’re evil or sinful, it’s that they’re unconscious. They are default settings.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There in fact is. Here are two more: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The really important kind of freedom involves attention and awareness and discipline, and being able truly to care about other people and to sacrifice for them over and over in myriad petty, unsexy ways every day.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And … &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;simple awareness; awareness of what is so real and essential, so hidden in plain sight all around us, all the time, that we have to keep reminding ourselves over and over:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“This is water.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“This is water.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/some-thoughtful-quotes&quot;&gt;Some Thoughtful 'Quotes'&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on September 04, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[That time I lost $12,000 options trading]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/that-time-i-lost-12000-options-trading" />
  <id>/that-time-i-lost-12000-options-trading</id>
  <published>2013-08-28T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-08-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-was-all-gone-&quot;&gt;It Was All Gone …&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My boss once said that I was the only person he knew who bragged about his losses more than his gains. There is nothing interesting about an investing success. You had an idea, got in at the right time, and then exited at the right time. When something goes right, then you do not spend time thinking about the process and whether or not it held up throughout the entire thing. There are many times in which the investing success could have gone wrong. Yet the only times that people - including myself - actually take the time to evaluate what happened is when what could have gone wrong actually went wrong. This is one of those cases. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am looking back at my old Etrade trading records in order to help give some clarity on what happened but much of what is written is through personal memory. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;background-what-is-an-option&quot;&gt;Background: What is an Option?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An option is a type of financial derivative, and although it is a pretty fancy name the concept behind it is relatively simple to understand. It is called a derivative because it “derives” its value from the value of another financial instrument. That can be a company stock or a bond. Because the price of the financial instrument (called the “underlying”) can fluctuate from time to time, the fundamental value of the derivative can vary greatly any given second. This is different from that of a company’s stock because its fundamental value is derived partially by the condition of the company itself. That changes over a very long period of time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The value of an option is very volatile because there is a double market effect on the price. Not only is the market affecting the price of the underlying financial instrument, but the market is also affecting the price of the derivative itself! There are times when a derivative can be under or overpriced by the market just like with any regular stock. The only problem is that this time frame of under or over pricing can last for a very short time because the fundamental value of the derivative changes so quickly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An option is a derivative that gives people the “option” (thus the name) to purchase the underlying asset for a certain price, which financial people call the strike price. There are two types of options. There are calls, which give you the option to &lt;strong&gt;buy&lt;/strong&gt; something at the strike price and there are puts, which give you the inverse. They let you &lt;strong&gt;sell&lt;/strong&gt; something at the strike price. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing about options is that they are assets with limited life spans. The mayflies of the financial world, if you might call it at that (and I believe that I am the first). At a fixed point in the future (called the expiration date), the option runs out and the financial asset becomes worthless. Before the expiration date, the asset is worth something. After the expiration date, if the holder has not sold the asset or exercised it, the asset is worth nothing. So the closer the time gets to the expiration date, the less valuable the asset becomes. I traded weekly options, which are the options with expiration dates at the end of the week (Friday at 1 PM PST). These are the most heavily traded options and - especially with the options with the strike prices closest to the underlying’s current price - have the most volatile swings in prices. People can make relatively small bets on weeklies and then see themselves lose or gain huge amounts of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-beginning&quot;&gt;The Beginning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started on Twitter. I was hanging around the $AAPL tag on Twitter and noticed someone tweeting random numbers just out there. Curious, I soon realized that these were trades that he was publishing. This guy was apparently a stock option trader specializing only in Apple options trades. This makes sense because it allows him to get very good at predicting the price movements of Apple stock, which in turn allows for very successful bets using the options. Of course, at the time the only direction Apple stock traveled was up. The stock had gone from $300 to $600 starting at the beginning of 2012 and had made many people very rich. I had owned some 35 shares at the time and saw the benefits, and the huge paper gains that resulted gave me deep satisfaction during a period of time where there were few such things to be satisfied about. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a curious person and I like to try things. One of my philosophies in life is that you want to say “yes” to things. You would have a life with a much richer experience. I decided that it might make sense to go ahead and try a trade or two. A quick fling. See what might happen. Might lose a little bit of money but I am not going to risk a whole lot of money. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On July 30, 2012 I made my first Apple options trade. I watched the guy’s Twitter feed and when he posted a trade of his I went into my Etrade account and bought the same thing at a price close to what he got when he entered his trade: 2 contracts of the AAPL Aug 03’12 $585 PUT at a quoted price of $2.45 for a total invested capital of $501.51. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me show you how to interpret this particular Apple option trade. This option is a PUT, which means it gives me the option to &lt;strong&gt;sell&lt;/strong&gt; shares of Apple. It lets me sell them at the price of $585. One contract represents 100 shares, that is just how it goes. Part of the volatility in an option contract’s price comes from the fact that it is very heavily leveraged. They only quote the contract equivalent for 1 share of that 100 shares so when you trade one contract, you have to put in an amount of invested capital equal to $(100 x quoted price) so for the trade above was $2.45 x 100 for one contract. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the guy then again tweeted that he had exited the trade, so did I. Not hard. The trade went well as expected and I made $77 for literally 10 minutes worth of work. That is a whole lot of moolah if you think about it. Considering that I only put in $500, this was a pretty good return, over 10%. This quick toe dip in the pool felt great and I really felt that this could be something that could add to my fortunes really quickly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I got too greedy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-crash&quot;&gt;The Crash&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Aug 2, I decided that I was going to go heavy into this and if things unfold the way that it did last time then I could really put a dent into my bank account. At that time I still saw it as a fling. I would try this out for a twirl, rake in a whole lot of money and then cut the bait when the fish is still pulling. Well, I like to think that looking back upon it now. Had Aug 2 turned out well, I probably would have loved the sweet sweet money so much that no sooner than the next day would I be diving right back into the dragon’s lair. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I happened to have the day off from work so I had the time to trade from home, sitting up in bed waiting and watching my Twitter feed for the guy to tweet. I remember the market conditions that day. The market was down a whole lot, some 1% or something like that and even Apple - mighty Apple - was in the red. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He quickly did and I leapt on it in a real big way. I purchased 20 contracts of the Aug 03 ‘12 $600 PUT at $1.88 a share. With commissions, this added up to a total of about $3,785. A huge step up in investments from the previous trade. Already though as I was putting in the order, the only thought in my head was that a 20% gain from this would be a mere $800. Not nearly enough to make for a day worthy of my eventual goal of becoming a stock trading millionaire. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The puts gained value because the market was down that day and went down lower, taking Apple with it. The puts gained value to some $2, making me quite a bit of money. Dreams danced in my head of doing this for a living. But then quickly the winds began to turn. I suddenly found my paper gains vanishing and the price fell to $1.90. I decided that I was going to double down because I wanted to keep this going. The way that I saw it - and this became the crucial mistake - I saw the option as a stock rather than for what it actually was: A rapidly deflating object. I was collecting pennies right in front of the steam roller and eventually my pants leg was going to get caught in the roller. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it did. Quickly the price fell to $1.78, giving me a bigger loss. I was now $300 in the red. This was not how it was supposed to go. Looking to finally play this bounceback, I decided to invest the biggest sum yet. 30 contracts for a total investment (ha!) of $5,400. Total invested capital of $9,000. This would be bigger than almost anything else that I owned in my portfolio. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all quickly vanished faster than I could ever imagine. Within the hour, Apple began - against all rhyme and reason - to rise. This was unprecedented. Apple was probably the biggest company in the world. The market was actually getting worse minute after minute, the SP500 diving everywhere … but Apple somehow against all the factors was gaining ground. It was down $5, then $4, then $2 and then it suddenly was green. I felt green in my stomach. Because a PUT gains value when the stock price goes down, it loses value when the price goes up. Apple’s tiny salmon against the stream move had meant that the price of my puts had deflated from $1.78 per share to $1.15. Then to $1. Then to $.80. I finally sold out at 75 cents for a total loss of $7,000. In just 2 hours, I had lost the equivalent of 4 months of saving and frugal living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not know what I had just done. It felt like I was just playing with fake money. Numbers on the screen and that the game had just went badly and any second now I could just reach out and reset the game console so that nothing gets saved to the hard drive. Unfortunately that was not the case. That $7,000 was real money and I had lost every single dollar of it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose I could at least count my blessings. I still had some money left from the trade, if not a whole lot of it. That could have all gone. By the next day Apple went up a big 1% and the PUT options vanished and shriveled into the wind worthless. I could have lost the whole $9,000 were it not for my own lack of self-control. But such things did not matter when you feel that your entire life has been set back. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clock hit noon. Time to eat lunch. Usually I made my own lunch - something plain-cracker-tasteless and bland - to save money but I figured this time … I sort of deserved something more. I walked out and went across the street from the Sunnyvale apartment in which I was living to a cheap Chinese fast food place. I got a plate of fried rice, chow mein and sweet-and-sour pork for $7.95. I just lost seven grand. What’s another eight bucks? I got my food and sat in the corner by myself with my headphones in my ears and iPhone cradled in my palm, looking ordinary on the outside but feeling devastated on the inside. The entire place was empty except for me and I just sat there thinking long after the food had vanished into my mouth. I was thinking, thinking, thinking. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-rise&quot;&gt;The Rise&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You ever have that feeling where you just have to do something? Like your boss says to you, “Hey this is really hard but …” and then you are suddenly just think to yourself, “Oh, bring it on.” That’s me. I drank the shitty tap water in the restaurant and then walked back to my Sunnyvale apartment. The one I found on Craigslist and was living in pretty much illegally. I sat there on the shitty bed and decided that it was time to get over myself and do something about this. I remember exactly thinking the thought, “Jesus, well, I will get that money back even if it goddamn kills me.” I was grimly determined to make this work. And when I use start using the word “grimly” in my self-conversational lingo, you (I?) know that I (you?) mean(s) business. I wanted to get that money back trading options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am pretty good at fixing my mistakes. Gives me a chance to make new ones, you see. But in light of the Aug 2nd Incident as I took to calling it, I instituted new changes in my behaviors. No doubling down. Risk only $5,000 at a time. Better to cut bait and collect gains early rather than to wait it out for bigger fish. Always be paranoid. Rules that went against the value investing rules that I had relied on for a very long time before now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily the market winds were in my favor. Apple was in my favor. Over the next month, Apple began the last tear that it would ever go on, and I was there with all my weekly options to take full advantage. For the next month things began to change. I traded everyday. The Aug 10 ‘12 $615 calls. Aug 18 ‘12 $635, $640 calls. Slowly but surely I began to grind my way back. It was amazing. Small gains at first. $700. It felt good but I knew it was not enough. I lost $220 in two trades. Ouch but not too bad. I gained $222 in the next one and then $1,600 in two trades after that. Those felt really really good. But still I was not done. That hole was still there and I still had to get out of it. They say that the first thing you need to do when you’re in the hole is to stop digging. I kept on shoveling and somehow found myself getting closer to the top. I was getting close to moving out. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved out of my shitty Sunnyvale apartment and grabbed a temporary rental in Burlingame. A beautiful place. I remember sitting in that beautiful place in the morning sun with this laptop (the one I am typing on right now), executing trades. That day, August 22nd (over a year ago today!), I lost $1,760 because I went to eat a pizza slice and the trade (10 contracts of the AAPL Aug 24 ‘12 $645 puts) fell out of the building but then I made back $1,200 over the course of that same day. Quick hitters that added up. I felt very good. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then on Aug 31, a Friday. I closed a magnificent trade. 50 contracts of the AAPL Aug 31 $665 call. Risking $9,000 and gaining over $2,000 in a single swoop. I had made back my $7,000 and change. I do not think that I had been ever prouder of myself in my entire life for doing what essentially had come out to be nothing. I had moved out of the Burlingame apartment and was taking on a futon in a friend’s apartment living room. I traded on a shitty table that bruised my toes if I kicked against it and a cold drafty ventilation system that froze my extremities, and a crappy chair that gave me backaches. But I felt a joy indescribable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would not even say that it was all about the money, (though it certainly did not hurt). The money was just numbers on the screen. It a number on the screen on Aug 1st and it still was a number on the screen on Aug 31. What it felt for me was a vindication, a relieved lift. For the entire month I thought nothing but about the trades that I made, the trades I could make tomorrow and the rules that I established. Why did I not follow them? Why did it work? Why did it not work? I became someone unlike myself. Ignoring friends, social obligations, work obligations. I did not care about anything but those Apple weeklies. So when that final digit ticked on Aug 31, I felt like someone returning home from a long time away. Whisked away on Aug 1st. Returned home 30 days later. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-bad-sequel&quot;&gt;The Bad Sequel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should be the time when I can write here that I got out of the game right then. That Jonathan got up and took his chips and then walked away with just a cool story and his dignity intact. Unfortunately I wanted to write a sequel and as we always know, the sequel is never as good. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple’s last big surge was in August of 2012. After that it rolled over to a big loss and from there it was all down hill. I am going to spare you a lot of pain and tell you what happened. I finally reached the top of the hill on a Friday and then the monday afterwards, I did a new trade on Sept 4th and lost $2,976 that day. I traded 25 contracts of the GOOG Sep 07 ‘12 $690 call and lost $1,683 on that almost instantly. Then I rode that Apple train one more time for that day - against my rules, which said that I had to cool off if I took a big loss … but I had done it before and gotten away with it, making a gain to come back to almost even - and then lost another $1,290. A single day, a huge loss. I was getting used to it. The shock was wearing away. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to spare you what turned out to be the most monotonous sequence of days. From Sept 4th to Sept 27th, I lost $5,098. Then I stopped for the month of October. Then I picked it up against my own better judgment, losing another $900 before I finally stopped and walked away for good from it on December 12, 2012. Three months of money losing taking me to a cumulative loss of $12,000. Done in 3 months. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did I feel about it the whole time during those sad two months? Mostly, I felt a numbness. All it meant to me was nothing. I got obsessed with the idea of coming back. I had done it before and I kept telling myself in my heart that I could take it back to where it was. Perhaps coming back from that $7,000 was the worst thing that could have happened to me. It put in me the wrong-headed assumption that I could do it. That I had it in me. Perhaps it is better that they snuffed it out of me. No misconceptions. Tear the bandaid off. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thinking-about-it&quot;&gt;Thinking About It&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They say that the way to create good content on a blog is to do something and then write about it. With that particular person, I believe that they were referring to writing code but I think it applies here to life experiences too. I did this. I have to own it. So I wrote about it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that there are people out there who can do this for a living and that they are good enough to make a healthy living out of it. They might in fact even be rich from it. I am not one of those people. I realized a long time ago that I did not have the patience, mental acuity and the sheer instincts to do well from it. It is just not in my wheelhouse, and I paid a good tuition to the market for learning that particular lesson. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Dec 12, 2012, I had gone into that day knowing that this would be the last day. Unlike before, this really would be it. If I do not make some good green, I would take it as a message from the gods. I almost immediately lost $679 on 10 contracts of the AAPL Dec 14 ‘12 $530 Put. The first and only trade I made on that day. I sat there at the office with my head in my hands, a headache already at 7:12 AM. And then I stopped thinking about it and I walked away. For good. I started following a procedure that has done well for me many times before: &lt;img src=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Damnatio_memoriae&quot; alt=&quot;Damnatio memoriae&quot; /&gt;. Every twitter person I contacted about options advice. Gone. Every record I kept of my options trades, archived. Etrade’s emailed trade confirmations. Deleted. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sometimes get the temptation to trade again. I try not to think about it. I eat peanut butter. I go take a walk. I open up my iPhone and read some articles. Or what works the best, I think about the nights I would feel when I am in bed staring at the ceiling because I cannot sleep because that morning I lost some $2,000 - $3,000 of life savings. Or being back at that Chinese food shop, with crappy chow mein in my face and the total lack of appetite. That usually does the trick. &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/that-time-i-lost-12000-options-trading&quot;&gt;That time I lost $12,000 options trading&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on August 28, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking Over 6 Years Of Resume Evolution]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/looking-over-6-years-of-resume-evolution" />
  <id>/looking-over-6-years-of-resume-evolution</id>
  <published>2013-08-25T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-08-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first resume I ever made felt so dearth of material that even at its wordiest, biggest font barely stretched to half a page. God, it was ugly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been making resumes for years now and I have tried to instantiate the same information in dozens of different ways for many different reasons. These resumes have been sent literally hundreds of times to a number of varying results. Regardless of how the resume has looked over time, the goal has always been the same: Present what is there in an eye catching format with quick-hitting, well-written points so that I can stand out over the dozens upon dozens of people who send in their resumes along with mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not an easy task and as a result, it has led to some unusual choices and some weird directions with regards of both how I decided to design said resume as well as the content I put on it. Some of these choices worked. Other times, they did not. I wanted to take the time to write a little bit (ha!) about why I made these choices, how they worked in the job applicant market, and what I would have done differently. I do not believe that my resume experience is any different from that of other college students and young professionals entering the job market. If by reading this they can help avoid some of the errors that I made then I would be quite happy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;may-2007&quot;&gt;May 2007&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started Berkeley in 2006 and after the first year wanted to put myself out there in the work environment. By then I was wanted to major in business at Berkeley’s Haas Business School. That means you have to go out there and start getting some internships for yourself. I had never worked a job before up until then. Never did any clubs in high school. Never even worked a McDonalds job or anything like of that sort. So I had almost literally nothing on my resume. I was not sure what to do then. It is that age old chicken-and-egg problem: In order to get a job I need to get experience. But I cannot get experience without that first job! What is a kid to do? I dug as deep as I could, exercised every creative muscle, and eventually went with this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/resume2007.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This resume is so sparse and violates so many rules that I feel a little ashamed presenting it right here for you to read six years after the fact! So much wrong. But let me walk you through it bit by bit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“The Short Version”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This part is especially embarrassing and later on some people called me out on it. This resume is already plenty short as it is. Why would I put in a section headed “the short version”?! I had seen this in another resume that I googled online (one that turned to be something actually long and legitimately needed a “short version”) and figured that it would be a pretty interesting way to catch a recruiter’s eye. I did not have a lot of work experience on the page, but I did feel that I did have some strong intangible capabilities. This “section” would give me the chance to write that down for someone to take into consideration. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It eventually worked in getting me that first unpaid internship, but in the end I dropped it out as my resume gained lengthiness and legitimacy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus negative points for giving my old high school email address on the top right. Unprofessional email addresses are a definite NO NO! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work Experience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering that I did not have a lot of it. I should have put it at the bottom. Without club experience or anything of the sort, I should have been clear to people just how green I actually was. I did have URAP - Undergraduate Research Apprentice - research experience but even considering that I did a poor job of presenting that information. My URAP experience would be better emphasized if I had decided to break it up with bullets. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also an extraneous hanging comma on “Academic”. These sorts of things bother the hell out of me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education should have been the thing that went right under the “Short Version” section, being the best thing about myself to exhibit. I had a relatively high GPA (and this would be the case for the rest of my time in college) and did it at a school known for tough grades. If I were to do this resume again, I would take the education section up. I would also set the GPA section in bold and with a bit larger typography (in order to make it more noticeable). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layout&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not excited about this layout. This one came through one of the templates from Microsoft Word. At the time I did not know what I should do to make a good resume. Guess it was fine as I lacked the design taste to make something look good as well as the Word proficiency to create it anyway. I really did not know any better. I am glad though that I quickly pivoted away from such a thing in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that I have learned over the years is that a lot of resumes look the same. They almost always have the same stupid layout and I think that is tiresome. If you are a recruiter looking through so many resumes with the same set font and look then it means something if you have something just off enough to catch their eye and make them stop. Nothing TOO crazy mind you (and I will make and show you some crazy ones later). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outcome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This resume looked terrible but somehow through the will of the Lord it got me my first unpaid internship at BTI Group, which was something like a glorified call center with a nice title. However experience was experience and after a few other more qualified people dropped out, I managed to do some time there and get some good experience as well as make some friends. This gave me the first crucial line item in my resume that I needed in order to be qualified for better jobs in the future. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nov-2007&quot;&gt;Nov 2007&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was learning a little more about what makes a resume a good one by now as well as improving my own skills at Microsoft Word. At BTI they had resume sessions and I got some good feedback in terms of what should stay and what should go. My earlier resume had been so bad that when people first looked at it they started laughing! Their feedback did help out a bunch and before long I had revised it to look like this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;feature&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/resumenov2007.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/feature&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is definite improvement here from the previous iteration, as well as much more that can be done in order to make it yet better. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work Experience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not know it at the time, but at the time I actually had a fairly decent amount of work experience for someone of my age. It probably did not need to be all the way at the bottom (though being the largest section it remained quite prominent) and should be moved up above at least the “Profile &amp;amp; Skills” section (which itself needs to be renamed to something like “Interests”). However, my reasoning at the time was that though I had 3 entries in that section, not all of them could be considered to be “real” work. Real work meaning that I could say that it took place in an office with supervisors and company revenue banking on it. I also had not been paid for any of the work that I had taken on up until then. That was a real issue for me. It is not real work until money gets deposited into your bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is the temptation to say a whole lot about your work experiences and achievements there. Later on I found that it did not matter so much the sheer number. Rather, it is what you did there and the substance of your achievements that mattered. Much of what I did at BTI Group people did not really care for. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most especially, the number and percentages look really dumb looking back on it today. Too round and even in order to be believable. They look manufactured for the sake of impressing a recruiter. In my later lives as a resume reader for positions, I automatically disregarded any term of phrase that goes like: “[verb] deals/students/applicants/events/revenue by [x]%”. Nobody keeps track of that. Not even the revenue stuff because if you are a college student is anyone at a real company going to give you the power or influence to actually grow revenue by that much? Nope so you probably should not be taking credit for it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In my later lives as a resume reader for positions, I automatically disregarded any term of phrase that goes like: “[verb] deals/students/applicants/events/revenue by [x]%”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus negative points for giving the actual names of my supervisors in the bullet points in my BTI Group experience. Unless it is someone famous, there is no need to have it there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the right idea here moving education to the very top. It became clear to me early on that it was the thing that I should be emphasizing the most. When you do not have a lot of work experience (or even relevant work experience), what should be done is to talk about what you do well. I studied well and picked good classes and my GPA reflected the hard work that I had done. I probably did not need the denominator there “/4.0” and it should be left off the page. Most people understand that this is out of the 4.0 scale. This is not high school where people have like 5.0 GPAs (what the hell was up with that anyway?!). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people say that it does not make sense to have an SAT score there. However at the time I still felt very insecure about what I had done up until now and wanted additional “padding” in order to have a resume that seemed “long” and “complete”. I am pretty sure that this was a good choice. Having a short resume like I did back in 2007 was pretty glaring. It stands out but not in that good, “I want you to notice me” sort of way. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus negative points for having the “May 2010” randomly hanging there. Mostly this was because I had no idea how to fiddle around with the spacings in Microsoft Word (not as proficient in the Office suite products as I thought I was …) and get them closer together. Regardless, I should have bolded it to give additional emphasis. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layout&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Layout was definitely improving by now. I had learned enough Microsoft Word to create columns that would add more air and space to the setup. Where before I had the dates of employment and the job title on the same line, which made it tough to figure out exactly how long I was at which place, I had created two columns in Word and arduously aligned the dates and the job details on approximately the same line. It is much easier to read and understand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I note that this is an impractical thing to do because in the course of job applications, you should be very nimble. You should spend time tweaking the resume before submitting to the listing. This could include things like taking out achievements, adding keywords from the job listing into the resume, or simply adding relevant details like if they do ask for SAT scores (a few do). These tweaks would mess up the formatting and spacing of the column-based resume and you end up wasting more time fixing the alignment of your tweaks than what really matters: Creating good content on your resume. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Might not seem like it matters, but with a resume like this - and there are still a lot of things going against it - I recall anecdotally that I got about 1 callback for every 12 resumes that I sent out. You need to put out a lot of resumes in order to get that job and the time spent tweaking every resume version piles up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outcome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I mentioned above. I got about 1 callback for every dozen resumes that I sent out. The jobs that I applied to were in general finance related, because that I was interested in, but also spanned the gamut to also analyst and scientist lab technician jobs too. The lab technician jobs I was not at all qualified for (and it is ridiculous that I even tried looking back at it) but the analyst type jobs and the finance type jobs eventually bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this resume, I eventually landed my first “real” job getting paid $9 an hour at a company called FMV Opinions as a private company valuation intern. This was a real “get” because it is a company well known amongst the business types as a feeder position into an internship at an investment bank. But God how good it felt to get some money into the bank! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other Notes: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I was definitely not conversant in Mandarin. When you use that phrase, you have to be good enough to be confident that you can do the interview in Mandarin and not sound like a damn idiot &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Should have spent more time on the interests, because that often turns out to be the topic of conversation in your interviews&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bonus negative points for giving my parents’ home phone number in the top right&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;october-2008&quot;&gt;October 2008&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not do a whole lot from the fall of 2007 to October 2008 that required me to revise my resume so it laid fallow for a while. I spent more time applying myself to school - getting good grades on my academic work as well as the undergraduate research apprenticeship from a year before. Also the economy had started to get worse and the callbacks petered out. Things were not definitely not good … but I was not aware that such a financial crisis was just around the corner. Not that I could have done anything about it anyway. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the crucial junior year internship period approached (crucial because it is the last summer where you can get workplace experience before you start recruiting for full time jobs out of graduation), I had this resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;feature&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/resumeoct2008.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/feature&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now you can see that the time I had spent working on my Word skills were paying off and that a definite look and style has started to set in. Many of the concerns that I pointed out in the previous section had been addressed by this iteration. It is surprising. I am writing these recollections (and criticisms) resume by resume - not looking at the next one until I finished with its earlier iteration - and am surprised to find that almost point by point what I notice to be an error is being corrected in future versions right down to the weird spacing in my graduation date (May 2010). It goes to show you just how glaring some of these errors are that I can spot them again so many years after they were made. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I especially like with this revision is that I swapped out the previous font for a better one. Times New Roman is a font trusted by many people but God it is ugly and squished up. Switching to Cambria created a much more spaced out and relaxing-looking resume that is easier to read. Recruiter eyes are now spared. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work Experience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My previous job experience was still making me nervous in terms of what I had done there and whether it was relevant to the kind of work that I was aiming for at the time (mostly jobs related to finance and analysis). Thus, the verbosity. Most of what I had in there in terms of how I phrased my achievements were rolled over from the previous iteration. However I did make some changes like cutting down on the number of bullet points. Four is probably the most anyone should ever go and if each bullet point is already at 2-3 lines that is a lot of text being spent on something that should not be going that long for a 2 month stint. By now it is time to start transitioning out of the “I need to pad and fill white space” phase and start being more judicious about what stays on the resume page and what goes off. It just does not make sense to go crazy especially by then I had held 2 legitimate internships at that point. I should also not have a work experience from a year ago be the longest and most complete thing on my work experience section. This should be reduced and the resultant space be dedicated to my latest work experience at FMV. It is all about the “what have you done lately?” attitude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;By now it is time to start transitioning out of the “I need to pad and fill white space” phase and start being more judicious about what stays on the resume page and what goes off&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was learning better how to adjust the spacing, but the column approach continued to dog me when it came to tweaking resumes. Note that the dates for BTI Group are lower than how it is for FMV and Haas School of Business. I do not think that I figured it out for several years how to actually fix that issue and eliminate once and for all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About the bulleted text that goes below the job title in Work Experience. It is good that I bolded the title of the job and made it all caps, but now you have all these words that you expect the reader to read below that title. At the same time, the text is actually TWO pieces of information in them with different goals in mind. I wanted to: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Explain my role there at the company, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Exclaim my notable accomplishments &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think one thing that could be improved is to break out the text that does job no. 1 and separate it in some way from the text that does no. 2. This psychological “trick” makes it easier for someone to read, comprehend and retain the entirety of both pieces of information rather than just random bits and pieces of both. It is easier for someone to understand/retain two smaller pieces of information than it is for them to do the same for one big piece. In this case, what I want them to remember is that the work I have done in my previous jobs is in line with what they are looking for AND that I can do it well for them too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, this is the type of stuff that I think about when I write and make resumes. I’ll bring it up again in the Education section coming up next. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education remains the top of the resume as it should be. I resized the font and size of the name of the university and the college GPA then proudly added the “Bachelors of Science in Business” below it. Not sure if this is relevant but should probably add that I went to the Haas School of Business rather than putting the name of the Bachelors. For people who recruit out of Berkeley exclusively (like they use the university recruiting system), the Haas name has cachet. No such cachet exists when you enter the real job world though, so it is just a short term fix. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coursework I think is too long and verbose. It could use some cutting down as well as some work to space out and make more readable. Right now you have this long four-line block of text that is dense and hard to quickly parse out. If that information is valuable, it is important to add some sort of flair or style that would break the monotony of plain text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layout&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the beginnings of the layout that I am going to use from now on. Knowing how my resume looks today, I can see the seeds of its birth there! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that should be considered with this resume is color. Right now this is very monochrome. Very black and white. What can definitely help and improve this resume is adding a conservative amount of color in order to make it easier on the eyes. A dark red or blue line (replacing the plain black ones that undergrid the headers) might help, as those colors print well in a printer but when viewed in a PDF it helps eliminate part of the harshness of seeing black text on white backgrounds. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general I think the main flaw of this resume is that it is too text heavy. It is going to be hard for people to read and imbibe all of it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outcome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This resume did slightly worse than the last one in terms of callbacks, something like 1 out of 20 that I sent out got callbacks. This eventually would lead me to make some changes in order to improve the callback ratio, realizing that if things were to continue then I would not have anything to do during the essential junior year summer internship period. I picked up a small unpaid gig during the Spring 2009 semester so that I can add something else to the resume, but that was a small thing and would not make a long term dent in my career arc (though the experience personally I found to be quite enriching). I was getting seriously worried. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other Notes: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The text on the top right is aligned weird. There should be more space for my name, which seems a little cramped &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I would prefer to have my full name there too by the way, as it is unique enough to be remembered&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I would probably remove the SAT scores though I recall a few listings still asking for it &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;may-2009&quot;&gt;May 2009&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, concerns were growing in me that I was not going to be able to secure an internship over the summer. The economy was as bad as it had ever gotten and improvement still seemed far off into the horizon. This is the resume that I had going into the summer internship recruiting season. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;feature&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/resumemay2009.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/feature&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get a sense of the general approach that I took with this iteration: SHOTGUNNING! I had no idea what I am going to keep on or off my resume so I was just going to go big or go home. Believe me I was closer to going home than going big. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing in particular that I felt was holding me back (and this was reflected in feedback I received from several colleagues) was that though I had plenty of work experience under my belt at the time, I did not do all that much on campus. I never joined any clubs, never got into the frat scene, or even played an intermural sport. I hardly spent any time on campus outside of stuff done for class or studying (and I did the majority of my studying at home). Thus, I created a new section for Activities, hoping to shore up that particular weakness. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I am not sure that an “Activities” section really accomplishes the goal that I set out to achieve. For one thing, it is less about what you do but how well you do it while you were there. I never participated in any leadership-type positions on campus. The stock market team case competition did not last long and if you did not win then it probably should not go on the resume. I do not think that people really cared all that much about what I put down for activities. I should not have cared so much myself but I was concerned that without this bit of information I would be a far inferior applicant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humble-brag here. I believe that winning case study was for something like Caterpillar, which has sucked since 2008. I would like to note that my stock pick choice Hansen Natural Corporation (HANS then, but they switched to MNST in 2012) has returned some 400% since I gave that presentation in November of 2008. Yeah I can pick them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layout&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest issue here is the lost space from carving out the Activities section in my resume. It is not so much about the fact that I cannot stuff any more job positions in but rather it does not allow me to say a lot about each particular piece of experience. In addition, the contortions that I put myself when it came to fitting as much as I could onto the page meant that this whole thing looked squished and compact. It feels almost foolishly compressed. It takes away from what should have been my strength &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outcome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a few callbacks from investment banks with this resume, but in general they passed me by after a first round interview. I was not “banker” enough for them even though on paper it seemed like I had done all the right things. But the education I got both in the office and in the classroom benefitted me in the end as I managed to get a short summer internship at an asset management research firm called Hall Capital Partners. This turned out to be a blessing in disguise as I was able to see the fund investing world and learn many brilliant things. It was also a nice bump in pay for me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other Notes: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Much of the other criticism I had about the resume still apply here. There should be some color to the lines and some more spacing apart of everything. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The coursework in education is just too busy for me right now. There has to be a better way to present all that information - the name and final grade of the course. Even better, why do you need to indicate that you got a good grade on the course? Is that not what transcripts are for? It should probably be removed. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jan-2010&quot;&gt;Jan 2010&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a great time at Hall Capital Partners and shortly after I left, I felt that the resume needed a complete overhaul underneath the hood. I wanted to apply to a whole lot of places and I found that the document’s structure interfered with that. This new update would create the layout that remains at the heart of my current resume. At the cost of being cheesy (then again, I am writing a 6,000 word essay on the changes of my resume, that threshold has long been crossed), I would consider it the iPhone of my resume world! Hah. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;feature&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/resumejan2010.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/feature&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This iteration addresses a lot of the issues I had pointed out as far back as the 2008 version. I still think that layout-wise it looks very good. There would be no problem for me to send it out into the business world as it is. I can address the benefits in the Layout section below. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said about the aesthetic, there are still things that I can quibble about with regarding the actual content of the document. Let us go over some of them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layout&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2010 I decided that it was time to restructure the entire resume and start from scratch. I had played around with tables while I was at Hall Capital and decided that it might be a great tool for making an entire resume in Word. The advantages would be that it would create a document that is very well spaced-out and customizeable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with the exception of the header - with the name and the address information - the entire document is actually one big table. For the sub-headers, it is easy to color and add flair with the use of shading and cell color-fills. Not only that, the date signifiers are all now placed consistently at the middle of the column without any hassle from me. This removes a big headache. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general I could describe the entire resume as being very segmented. What does that mean? It means that I can make changes in one section, really wild changes like perhaps including an image, and not have to worry about how it might mess up the formatting in another section because all my wreckage is being committed in a self-contained area of the resume that could be undone and deleted with a single keypress. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I can make changes in one section, really wild changes like perhaps including an image, and not have to worry about how it might mess up the formatting in another section&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of colors stayed on the conservative side, which I believe kept it tasteful yet attractive. Just looking at it above, you assuage the sense of harshness that one might feel when looking at some of the other resumes in this (increasingly longer) post. The gray shading also helps break out of a monotony of black and white, which has the appearance and impression of being Xerox-ed. This feels in contrast like you are looking at a sparse but multi-colored web page. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work Experience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest change I made here and one that persists to today is the use of the italics to undergrid both the job title and the place of work. The goal is to give the reader a quick way to understand exactly what I did and where at. The structure is pretty simple. The first sentence gives an overview of the company and the sentence after that would tell them my job description. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did have issues with the spacing and how many lines should I skip over below and above the italics. This turned out to have tradeoffs. I wanted to include as much as I could in the work experience section, because I felt that I needed to be as impressive as I could be. However, I also felt that presenting a big wall of text to the readers would be counter-productive. When the human mind feels overwhelmed by the sheer amount of information being presented to it, the default action is not to grid down and trudge through it but to simply skip the whole rigamole entirely. Considering the fact that people spend like about 30 seconds to a minute skimming through a resume, this is disastrous. Looking back on how this whole thing is presented, I can afford to take out a few line items like BTI Group, increase the size of the font, and space out things a little bit more. I would look less impressive on paper, but that is what LinkedIn is for, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remain ambivalent about the use of the Activities section here. My time at strive_for was not very long and my role not all that involved. I did help come up with the name but beyond that my contribution was limited. Considering that not all that many people care about your college activities once you actually get that first job I felt that the space could be better used in some other capacity. I am pretty sure that once I got that first job I dumped this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new structure and layout allowed me to edit and change the coursework in the education section very easily. This means that if I wanted to apply to a real estate job, I could quickly swap out Marketing with the Real Estate class that I took several years ago. This allowed me to make a whole bunch of custom resumes very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outcome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This resume saw almost immediate success. I would snag a great internship and a full time job with particular iteration. I received a full time offer from Ernst &amp;amp; Young as well as an internship at KKR, a private equity firm. From what I recall, this got a callback as often as third of the time that I sent it out to a job listing. I ended up circulating this format around to many of my friends, who all saw benefits from using it for their own resumes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nov-2011&quot;&gt;Nov 2011&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stopped looking at my resume when I started my full time job at Ernst &amp;amp; Young, but soon enough I realized that my life was not where I wanted to be. I was desperately unhappy doing accounting. So after about 8 months there I left to write a novel. So I did. Left without much of a plan, really. I stayed for about 3-4 months writing my book but then realized that I did not have enough savings to live for very long. I had to go back into the job market. I felt like a retired car heist artist in a Fast and Furious movie: “Just when I thought I was out, they dragged me back in.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now I was pretty much used to the process of getting a job or an internship. God I have done it so many times anyway. So I went ahead and dove back into the resume-making process. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;feature&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/resumenov2011.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/feature&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked off the most successful iteration of my resume, looking to simply add MORE stuff on. Because I have done so many things at so many different places and I was simply unwilling to drop them, the only way that this could accommodate was to shrink the font and go microscopic. The result is a truly full wall of text that only the most dedicated and interested would ever read through. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has not changed all that much from the 2010 version. I had graduated already and wanted to indicate that I had a high GPA in a relatively competitive major. However, I felt that as soon as I had left college and entered into my first job that it might make sense to move this down below work experience. Once you are out of college, people do not really care all that much beyond your GPA, major, and the name of university you matriculated from. I should also take out the coursework section. I have never been asked in an interview - a non-technical one, anyhow - about the classes that I took while I was at university. There seems to be a tacit acknowledgement that whatever I learned there would be useless at the workplace. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work Experience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got to cut down on that sheer wall of text and get something that is readable here. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should say that the most recent work experience should be the one most expanded upon in a resume. I did not spend a whole lot of time at Ernst &amp;amp; Young, but leaving all that information off the page because of the “shame” that I felt at having stayed there for such a short period of time is probably a mistake. It might lead people to think that I left for reasons related to my job performance. Also, I only spent 4 months at KKR, why would I have so much detail on what I did there? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FMV Opinions is also really old job experience that should be cut out of the page entirely. I also would take some steps to cut out one or two of the bullet points in my Hall Capital Partners experience. Things two or three jobs ago should not take all that much space on the resume. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outcome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This resume was much less successful in getting callbacks for fulltime jobs. I ended up drifting for a bit before taking some freelance work with a startup in San Francisco. I had come about their attention through a crazy resume that I posted on the Berkeley jobs site. In a future post, I’ll review some of the experimental resumes and think about the design/stylistic choices that I made for them as well as the results from that work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jul-2013&quot;&gt;Jul 2013&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the latest iteration of my resume that is complete. I do have an iteration cooking right now in my DropBox but I am still unsure as to what to say about the content in the most recent job experience. Therefore let us take a look at the issues with this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;feature&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/resumejul2013.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/feature&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few things to be said about how this looks (and they are things that I directly addressed in the new version that I am cooking up. Things are being fixed!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layout&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not sure about the use of the colors here. While the use of the blue and the gray was tasteful and worked, in this case it seems almost gimmicky here. It interrupts the eye’s flow and the colors clash in an irritating way. In the next iteration, I should probably reconsidering dialing it back a little bit so that people do not get distracted by the weird colors on the page. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work Experience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CareDox was a great experience, but I should word-smith this down to a few lines. Not telling a novel here. Just want to get the basics of information down. The basics were that I ran a customer acquisition campaign for six months and grew subscriptions from 30 to 300 monthly. However, after this trial period ended, I did an analysis and found that consumer pursuit will be ultimately unsustainable. Thus, I recommended a new direction and the company did that. That should not take 10 lines to say. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before CareDox and after Ernst &amp;amp; Young, I spent a lot of time working as a freelance marketer for a number of different startups. Some of these gigs did not last more than a few days or weeks and often less than a month. I remain unsure about how to depict this information, which I feel is valuable to potential employers. That being said, I am aware of the problems I had in previous resumes when there was just too much information on the page. There has to be a delicate balance to be struck and to be honest, I have yet to achieve that balance. It still is pretty much up to the job listing. If I have done work before that might align with the experience or the industry, I’ll opt to include it. Luckily the document’s layout makes it easy to make these changes quickly on the go without pain. I also keep a “mother-document” that lists every position that I have worked at and lists my accomplishments there in huge detail. This means that I will not have to wrack my brain trying to remember what I did at this or that place. I just have to go back to the mother-document (or any of my older iterations) and copy that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had moved the Education section down to below the work experience. It is time to acknowledge that nobody cares about what school I went to. Should also consider removing the “courses” information. In speaking with employers in and outside of interviews, I never got the sense that they cared about the specific courses that I took. And I never got a callback to an analyst-type job because I took this or that particular course. It is still important information, but I feel that the real message of the resume should be on the particular work experience that I might have that aligns with what they are looking for in a candidate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this being the case, I only have about one line in the education section, which might warrant me eliminating it altogether and rolling it under the skills/interest header. This will free up yet more space and allow the resume more “room” to breathe. I had colored the “University of California, Berkeley” header in the Cal colors, but now I think people will not note it enough and instead just find it distracting. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layout&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have not sent this out into the job market, but previous iterations (modified to match the job listing) have gotten about a 50% callback ratio. This high ratio is mostly due to the fact that I sent resumes out very selectively. If I were to go back to mass-spammage, this ratio would likely fall to something in the neighborhood of 20-30%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other Notes: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My name header’s font is different from that of the rest of the resume. Fix that&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the address header on the right, there are too many links to outside pages. I should probably look to cut those down. Three lines seems to be the most I can do in this particular setup without getting too crowded&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I always fiddle with the interests sections because it is the one that I find most important in an actual interview. People tend to touch on it during an initial phone screen. You have to be weird, quirky, and passionate about what you do without coming off as a freak &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post turned out to be much longer than I at first expected. I was sure that this was going to be just about 1,000 words or so. However, I had been making resumes for a long time, considering every little part of it, and I leapt at the opportunity to talk about the accumulated knowledge that I have built up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that some people are going to roll their eyes on my talk about “breathing” and “space”, mostly because I have a limited view point on what is going on in the heads of people looking at the actual resume. I acknowledge 100% that there is a bias on my end. Much of the design choices that I talked about here in this long post come from my own viewpoints and I have design preferences that gravitate towards a clean, sparse simplicity. That being said, I am confident that my sentiments are not peculiar and being someone who has reviewed 100s of resumes, I think that even these little things can help put your resume out on the top if you find your resume just one in a sea of similar applications. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I skipped a lot of iterations at the end from 2010-2013, partly because I was gainfully employed during that period and I did not need the resume all that much but also partly because the resume is beyond the point where I can make improvements to the callback ratio through aesthetics and arrangement. By now it is about the experience and whether or not I am qualified for the job that they are advertising for. You can do a whole lot to the look and the feel of the resume, but in the end if you do not have the right education or work experience for the position, you would be hard pressed to assume that you’ll be hearing back any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/looking-over-6-years-of-resume-evolution&quot;&gt;Looking Over 6 Years Of Resume Evolution&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on August 25, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking Back on App Academy]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/thoughts-on-app-academy" />
  <id>/thoughts-on-app-academy</id>
  <published>2013-08-22T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-08-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;From May to July 2013, I decided to take a two month intensive course in web programming, learning the entire web stack from the front end (with JavaScript, HTML and CSS) to the back-end (with Ruby on Rails) with the sole intention of getting a job in web development. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been about a month since then and while transferring posts from the Tumblr where I wrote them to this particular blog, I got to read and reminisce back on what I was doing back then. I wanted to sit down and do a little writing about what I thought of the whole thing now that it is all over. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;solving-fizzbuzz&quot;&gt;Solving Fizzbuzz&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first came across App Academy on HackerNews. They had posted some sort of thread that talked about a free iOS programming class. It was an intensive course and it was free up front. You would not have to pay anything until you actually got that job. It does not take a raging hurricane of knowledge to like that particular proposition. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that point in my life, I was working for a startup doing analytics work. I handled angry phone calls from angry customers who wanted their money back but a boss who was not excited about giving any sort of returns back to the customers. Fires abounded everywhere, and every new one was the 100% top priority until the next one arrived. We moved like we were flailing on the Titanic and the ship was sinking … except that the sink was nearly 8 months long. I wanted to do something else. I looked over sideways to the cubicle next to me at my friend and coworker Paul. Paul was a developer. Paul knew how to make shit. Paul spent the majority of his day tapping out runes of colored text into TextMate and throwing the football while he was “deploying” the site. Paul got all kinds of offers every day. Paul never had any issues with getting a job. Adam, my roommate with a computer science masters, gets 2-3 offers a day from LinkedIn. I wanted to know more about this mysterious life of a developer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sent in an application, and it took about 5 minutes to do. I did it during lunch, with a few questions that were not all that tough. Just information about like my history and what I was doing in life. I wrote as honestly as I felt I could be and then submitted. Thought nothing more of it. I had done several of those already previous in the year. I like to open the doors and see what comes into the room. Occasionally an opportunity would be interesting enough, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several months I got a random email from nowhere. Apparently I had been accepted as some sort of provisional student. They wanted me to fill out some of the codework that they had attached. If I did then they would go ahead and accept me. With a raised eyebrow, I took a look inside. The problems were relatively simple and with the limited amount of Ruby that I actually knew I was able to write some solutions. I struggled for a week on these simple exercises and then sent them back. It took some time but I enjoyed working on them. I like to solve coding problems especially if they were in Ruby. Ruby is fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They called back and arranged an interview over Skype. Recalling it back then, it was on a Monday in January 2013. I had scheduled for it to be after work at 5 PM. I am always nervous before any sort of interview, but in this case I was more nervous than usual. I do not like to lose. The guy on the other side walked me through a few coding interviews. The first was FizzBuzz, which was something I was pretty familiar with. I remember that I used the “upto” method a whole lot. This was probably not the best way to do it. Then they asked me a “cat and hat” problem. I went ahead with that, not saying all that much and then finished thinking that I might have done alright. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few days later, they sent me an email letting me know that I was accepted for the May 2013 cycle. I had 7 days to accept and had to cough up $3,000 as a deposit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a lot of time to think about whether or not I was going to do this. I talked to a lot of people including from my family and inner circle of friends. Generally their response went along the lines of this: “Why do you want to do development? Why do you want to be a developer?” In general, most of my friends have known me as an Excel maniac. They were puzzled as to why I would suddenly career switch at 25. Some of them were definitely in the “Need-the-Degree” camp. They said that I would only just contribute to the pool of crappy developers out in the job market. Their words were pretty discouraging, but I wanted to make stuff. I wanted to be able to write code. I did not know it yet and though I was a pretty good autodidact, I was also good at distracting myself. Doing this would put me to the test, focus me 100% and make sure that my attention does not embark down the dark path. And also I am not going to lie if all the doubt got my blood going. I like to do things that people would not expect of me. The weirder, the better. Just that type of person. If you want me to try something, just tell me not to. God I am just such a sucker for that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-course&quot;&gt;The Course&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I commute from Redwood City to San Francisco, somewhere on Rincon Hill. You have to be there by 9 AM or you get fined some amount of money. There was the option to sleep and live in the App Academy complex but I turned that down. I enjoy my privacy. So I commute on the CalTrain. I have to take the 7 AM Caltrain so that I can hoof it down to the App Academy place by 9 AM. I am almost always early so I take the time to read some of the reading and prepare my mind mentally for working hard and thinking through complex computer science projects. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My memories of the first day went along the lines of this: “My God this place has a lot of men.” Out of a class of 40 or so, there were only about 5 women. I could hardly make them out. Being out of a business background, I spent the majority of my time around women. I connect better with them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bunch of guys showed up at the front of the room and started introducing some of the beginning curriculum. What to expect. What a typical day is going to be like. Introduced Ned. The head honcho. The main teacher who was going to help all of us learn how to code. I would describe him in one word as disheveled. In on phrase as “like a magpie’s nest full of bottle caps and gold wire”. In other words, he was a guy with black hornrim glasses, furry goatee, and Jesus hair like as if he rolled his way out on Easter Sunday morning came up just yesterday. He had this tinny voice that sounded with manufactured authority, talking like as if he had to consciously dedicated memory in his mind to rolling his r’s and getting his words done right because if he did not we would not understand him. When his words came out his lips curled up, giving me an impression of a particularly jolly person. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They pretty much started from the get-go. The course is 9 weeks long (though they extended it to 12 after my cycle) which means that there is an awful lot of stuff to learn and get through. I was talking to some of the other students and they told me that you basically learn stuff in one day that most other people in schools take several weeks to review and understand. It is complex stuff. Here is a sample from the Javascript curriculum, which basically happens over the span of a week: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You are introduced to server-side Javascript in day 1-2, you read 6 chapters from a number of Javascript books as well as finish the entire Codecademy JS curriculum &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Day 2: Closures and scopes, you learn callbacks, ‘this’ and ‘that’, how you organize JS libraries, and then how to call a function. Five things in a single day, things which are all pretty essential and I have seen many times in interviews &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Day 3: Arguments, prototypal inheritance, client side javascript and the concept of asynchronous &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Day 4: JQuery, which includes manipulating the DOM &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Day 5: AJAX&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then you learn Backbone.js. To be honest, the sheer deluge of material that a single person in App Academy has to absorb in order to keep up with the curriculum is stunning. It is true that not everything sticks. There is a lot of stuff that falls through the cracks. You might think then that, how does Ned and his bevy of Teaching Assistants know how to manage his students? How does he know if they struggle or not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mostly, it is the honor system. He expects that the people in the course - since they are doing their best to learn as much as possible to get that developer job - are incentivized to be honest and forthright when they are struggling. They then get the right attention from the TAs and the instructors. But that is not the only safeguard. There are going to be people who struggle and just stay with it, hoping not to get noticed. This is where the assessments come in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-assessments&quot;&gt;The Assessments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember how nervous I was about the first assessment. The assessments are billed as a way for the instructors to evaluate the students and identify the ones who are not doing so well. In other words, if you do not do well at the assessments and you fail too many of them in a row they ask you to leave App Academy. I imagined that they would turn you out into the cold shivering. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first assessment I took was in Ruby and it was in the first day of the second week. You come in at 9 AM as usual and then they email out the assessment to everyone at 9 AM sharp. You get one hour to write as much code as you can and get that code out the door so that it passes the automated tests that are wrapped into the zip file. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do the assessments work? Part of the format is that they are written with Rspec tests. It is as much an exercise to read and interpret the tests as it is to formulate and tap down the code. There are a few people who struggled in the assessments because they were unable to read and understand the tests that were written. Ned had to go and help them interpret that code. Personally I would have considered that part of the assessment and leave them to it, but it seems like they are not that type of people. Some coders were so weak and needed so much hand holding that they practically were walked through the whole assessment. That being said, this was rare and for the most part the majority of the students were able to get through the assessments with a passing grade. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leads me into my next topic about attention time and span. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;attention&quot;&gt;Attention&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first class size was about 20 but very quickly things began to grow. The AA cycle that I was a part of “May 2013” was about 34 people and then the one which came after me was about 45ish. I expect that the next one is to be yet bigger. And that is just the San Francisco class. There is also a New York City class that is being run at the same time concurrently. I would imagine that even though Ned, the co-founder and head instructor - is not there in person, the organization is expanding the size of the classes over there too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand why they do that. For one thing, the larger the classes are, the more likely that some of them get developer jobs. At the beginning, the admission rate was something like 80% but it has declined from then. In order to grow their revenues and keep up with all the costs of teaching people, renting out the facility, and buying the rather expensive Mac Minis and monitors for the students to use in light of the fact that the admission rate is not as high as it was when starting out, you have to expand the number you are multiplying by. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are issues that come with expanding the classes. For one thing, getting attention from the instructors and from the Teaching Assistants. There is only 1 Ned (his co-founder runs the business side and does not help all that much with the teaching) and there are only 3-4 TAs. This means that there is only so much tutoring time that can go around and they are incentivized to spend it judiciously. App Academy makes more money if everyone passes because time and money is being invested in these students. If one of them washes out because they are not able to make the cut then that is a loss. The result is that they spend a lot of their time working on the weaker students - those who are not bad enough to wash out completely but too weak to keep up with the rest of their fellow peers. They might not be able to remember how to roll their own authenticiation system in Rails, remember what a closure is in JavaScript, or be able to work with the canvas in HTML. They do work certainly hard, but just for some bizarre reason they cannot keep up with the rest of the class. These are the students who see Ned and the TAs the most, getting detailed one-on-one tutoring to keep their heads afloat. It is natural after all. App Academy does not get a single penny if they just fall behind indefinitely and are unable to get the skills to do the job. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of strong students who are so good that I question why they are bothering being here in App Academy in the first place. They quickly get bored with the material - that is how good they are - and then they want to explore further and deeper. However there is only so much time to go around and if you are doing well or even just alright, you are left on your own devices. I quickly established myself as one of the people in the latter during the first few weeks and from then on I hardly met with or spoke to the TAs or Ned. I basically just auto-didacted through the whole thing, not knowing if I was doing it right. The only feedback I would get came from the “solutions” laggardly posted on Github (you are expected to read and “understand” the solutions, whatever that might mean, in addition to the reading that you already should have to do) or from the feedback from my pair programming partner, who often times was not quite sure himself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-job-search-and-conclusion&quot;&gt;The Job Search and Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the nicest things about being a developer in a job search is that you do not have to do all that much work to get leads. People will call and reach out to you, which is something I was not very used to. They never do that for business majors. You get a call or a random email with an opportunity and you just feel so special. However, I would have to say that once I told my story - that I was a former business major who wanted to transition into development through this intensive course called App Academy - the calls quickly went to nowhere. It seemed like you had to get the professional experience or that legendary computer science degree. A 9 week course did not cut it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there were the technical interviews. App Academy ended my cycle with 2 weeks being spent on final projects. I feel that people would have been better served (and I think this is indeed the case after I graduated when they expanded the cycle to being 12 weeks long) if one of the two weeks were ditched and instead we spent time just interviewing. Hell that seems to be all we needed to have learned. Just interview like hell. Some of these questions were difficult - related to algorithms or bizarre, obscure parts of Rails - and I struggled to keep up. A few of them, like the ubiquitious “What is a closure in Javascript?” I kind of answered but not so well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it is just me but in the end, I never really got over the imposter syndrome that permeated through my entire time at App Academy. My friends outside of the course never saw me as a developer and said what they felt was obvious, “How can anyone expect that 9 weeks of learning can compensate for what some people need to do in 4 years?” My roommate who is a front end developer with a masters from Berkeley flat out said that he would never want to work with anyone with an App Academy-like experience and that the recruiters’ jobs should be to “keep people like you out”. That was sort of disheartening. Elitist and of dubious accuracy … but disheartening nevertheless. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;[He] flat out said that he would never want to work with anyone with an App Academy-like experience and that the recruiters’ jobs should be to “keep people like you out”.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then the rejections just got to me. Too many interviews and calls ending the same way with a “We will get back to you” and then a quick rejection via email. It was depressing and though Ned and my other classmates in the cycle were pretty optimistic, telling the same story and circulating resumes to the same listings wore me down. We were all going for the same jobs. I would talk to some of the other people in the cycle and we would refer to companies by name. We knew them all because we were going to the same places to apply to them. It felt like a cattle rush … and then we all knew that we had to secure that job before 9 weeks was up because then there was going to be a whole new batch of App Academy people released onto the market and that batch would be EVEN LARGER! You end up then just picking whatever came along and offered the most money. Some people were alright with that. I guess it just wasn’t right for me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized in the end that this frantic burst of recruiting energy - if it were applied in the same way with my old job - then I would have done fine with good money and the same non-crazy working hours. (As it turns out, my previous startup in which people were expected to work from 6 AM to 8 PM for months on end was sort of unique.) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not like that the entire experience would be considered a waste of time. It certainly worked for a lot of the people in the class. I get emails almost everyday about the job search, announcing with glee when people get offers for web developer gigs. There are still a lot of people waiting for that offer, but for others it worked exactly as advertised. For the right person, it is the right thing. As for myself, I learned a lot about Rails, picked up a fascination with JavaScript and gained a lot of experience in something that I am interested in on the side. It is valuable knowledge and in the end it would be used … just not professionally. &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/thoughts-on-app-academy&quot;&gt;Looking Back on App Academy&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on August 22, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anime Review: Kotonoha no Niwa]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/review-kotonoha-no-niwa" />
  <id>/review-kotonoha-no-niwa</id>
  <published>2013-08-18T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-08-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally posted Aug 18. Updated Aug 21&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A faint clap of thunder, &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Clouded skies, &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Perhaps rain comes, &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If so, will you stay with me?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above quote is a Japanese poem from the Manyoshu, which is a 8th century collection of over 4,500 Japanese poems. It is identified as a tanka and kind of like its more famous cousin the haiku, it is set in syllables, 5-7-7-7. This one in particular is &lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.com/books?id=1o41bL7QbVoC&amp;amp;lpg=PA58&amp;amp;ots=jOAFYnvsQS&amp;amp;dq=Manyoshu%20rain%20thunder%20stay&amp;amp;pg=PA58#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=Manyoshu%20rain%20thunder%20stay&amp;amp;f=false&quot;&gt;a dialogue poem numbered&lt;/a&gt; [XI:2513-4]. It is featured prominently in the movie and along with the weather plays a crucial role in the plot of a beautiful, utterly beautiful movie called Kotonoha no Niwa (Garden of Words). This is a movie worth watching not for what it says, but for what it shows. There is something fleetingly, hauntingly beautiful in its scenery and imagery that is tough to put your finger on until long after the end credits have passed. I really enjoyed this particular movie and would highly recommend it to anyone who has an appreciation for what it means to be isolated and lost in a sometimes alien, fast-moving world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this review, I want to spend some of our time (both yours and mine) thinking about what this movie is trying to say to us and how what we learn from it can enrich our lives as a whole. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;art--animation&quot;&gt;Art &amp;amp; Animation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kotonoha no Niwa does amazing things with the rain. It is hard to describe. It is not photorealistic in that the animators simply went ahead and took images of real rain and drew over it. Yet at the same time, it is not quite the rain that you see in any sort of anime. There is a sort of sheen over it that is half animation, half real but stays out of the uncanny valley. Does that make sense? No, right? Then you just have to see it to get a sense of what I mean. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://24.media.tumblr.com/be900a389ea243f9df19913de65051e0/tumblr_mrpcyrG2761snfl86o4_500.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Courtesy of Tumblr&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://31.media.tumblr.com/e90d7afa08f9796ad9533a6d5a7127b1/tumblr_mrnzkfhNss1sro4tgo1_500.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Courtesy of Tumblr&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more for good measure. This one is one of my favorites. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://31.media.tumblr.com/2b0a123dd9b4a1a25d4ace9f0b8f0e8e/tumblr_mrpcyrG2761snfl86o5_500.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Courtesy of Tumblr&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is one word to describe the look and feel of this entire movie, it is “beauty”. This flick is seriously good looking. It has this dream-like feeling to the whole thing. With such a style, there is the temptation to go too far and make the viewer fall into a stupor. However Kotonoha avoids this. The colors and quality are just too rich. When you look at this, there is instead the atmosphere of timelessness. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://24.media.tumblr.com/2b8489f2fb58223064564519046c922e/tumblr_mrh9esLg5L1steu17o1_500.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Courtesy of Tumblr&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Craft seems to have been applied to even the most mundane and un-artistic things. A cellphone for example. It is perhaps the most troublesome of items. Looking at it not only reminds you of just how the interconnected the world has become, but also how it isolates people from each other. It is an item many people are intimately familiar with. They know every nook and crevice of their cell phone. And it is an item that at first glance is not really fit for stylizing. It is a metal and plastic box with a screen on it. What is there to animate? It is just there all the time, buzzing and beeping to bring plot details to the characters. But one thing I really noticed and enjoyed in Kotonoha is how they managed to make even the main character’s cell phone glow and symbolically resonate with all of the character’s hopes, fears, and dreams. It becomes a lot more than just a simple exposition machine. It says something without any lines. It looks as lovingly and lushly animated as any supporting character in the movie. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://24.media.tumblr.com/f053a3487e0c41dba8d8519eec46d74c/tumblr_mrai7crd7A1qlzg7ho2_500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Courtesy of Tumblr&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The human characters also sort of glow. It is definitely not human-realistic and seems to be a stylistic choice by the director and the animators. If you look at the main female character, Yukino, you can get a sense of why these choices work. For example, take how her hair has been rendered. It is almost simplistic in the brevity of the strokes. No flowing strands. No hundreds of dark and darker shades for shadows. In fact the color is almost flat and uniform. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://24.media.tumblr.com/023f632e452ea56fb5f3f5854aa2db58/tumblr_mrai7crd7A1qlzg7ho1_500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Courtesy of Tumblr&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There, that is the word: Flat. There is a flatness in how the human characters look, and because the actual colors they did allow you to see are so jarring and unique you cannot help but find it beautiful. I have never seen color interplay of greens (greens so delicious it feels like that I have died and gone to heaven), peaches, and blues like this ever before. Who ever thought that it could possibly work to shade a green in the shadows of a person’s hair? It is just crazy! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://24.media.tumblr.com/c49534f23cddec9fa128fd9f2a698ec2/tumblr_mrg9rqkk401qgfld8o2_r1_500.png&quot; alt=&quot;Courtesy of Tumblr&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet it works. Every tiny bit of it. Kotonoha is something you want to see on a very good television panel. Character designer Tsuchiya Kenichi did a fantastic job and I hope to see some of his other work in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sound&quot;&gt;Sound&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is not a lot of music in the movie but whenever it does appear it is used very well. The piano pieces sync well with whatever is happening on the screen. I did find at some times that it would go ahead and get a bit off track. However it speeds up at tense moments and recedes whenever you simply need the silence. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sound is detailed and rich. I feel like they went out for hours and hours collecting sound samples of rain hitting different items. I am not a sort of sound snob but I noted that the rain has its own particular theme depending on the mood. There are times when the rain is gentle, pleasing but other times when it is angry. It is almost like expressing its own character feelings throughout the movie. Tiny touches like that really help establish the atmosphere without the use of blunt expository dialogue. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About the dialogue, the voice acting is pretty good but is not without its flaws. The guy is nothing much to write home about. I feel like his voice sounded the whole time a little too breathy for my tastes. I am kind of aware that this is how many people talk and I guess I could accept it but I just found it distracting from the actual words that he was saying. He is a very experienced VA with work in Tsubasa Chronicle and Bungaku Shoujo (where incidentally he also starred with Kana Hanazawa). Speaking of Kana Hanazawa, her voice is so distinct and unique that hearing it come out of this older woman’s lips is definitely distracting. It is one thing that jars you out of the plot. She does her best to match it to the older, more mature look but I am not sure that she succeeds. It might have made more sense to have someone more experienced like Ayako Kawasumi or even the ever-present Maaya Sakamoto do this particular role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said about the roles, they are not the main instruments through which the director expresses his intentions. The VAs do not say much, because what they say is pretty simple and the scenery and imagery does so much for them already.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;story-and-character&quot;&gt;Story and Character&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story is pretty simple, which makes sense since this is only a 45 minute flick. I enjoy the fact that it is not meant to be something deep and twisting. This is a simple story told, and in some ways that can be really hard. You have to be ruthless in what needs to go and what needs to stay. You have to stay out of cliche but at the same time deliver what the viewer might already expect from the storyline. I am glad that they did a good job. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://24.media.tumblr.com/c2ba2e87c8097e59abac8ed05bf3713b/tumblr_mrlo2d6o921rlajeko1_500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Courtesy of Tumblr&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are strong themes held including the weather and the aforementioned tanka that matter to the story and help enrich the experience. Even though the story is very short and simple in that it can be summarized in a single line, there are tiny rich details that justify you going back and seeing it again and finding those last details. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to be a rolling theme in Japanese media (of all types) that endings should not be definite. This is something that is very different from western media. I was reading a Japanese detective mystery in which they track down a woman from her mysterious disappearance. The main characters hear nothing but stories about her for 400 pages but then finally track her down. The author chose to end the book at the second the protagonists finally touches her shoulder and she turns around to look at them. What an infuriating ending that was! It is much the same with Kotonoha. There are details that many viewers would want and almost demand to know. The ending! Did it end the way I wanted it to!? Tell me! But I think that is not the purpose of this particular style of telling a story. I do not want to sound like a university commencement speech giver but it is not about the ending it is about the journey. The story is told in how the seasons move, how the two main characters gaze and not gaze at each other, and how they reveal tiny bits of themselves as they slowly bind themselves to each other for safety in a cruel, uncaring world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another theme - and one that I never get enough of - is that of loneliness and feeling “stuck” in life. There is a certain isolation in this particular storyline. The main characters are lost. The real world is all around them, with people going about their existences and moving forward to whatever they have set out for themselves to achieve. In public, all you see are people’s best faces and for many people, they show only their own happiness. Surrounded by so much happiness (sometimes called the Facebook effect), for the people who have their own internal demons - who consider themselves frozen in a moment of time waiting for something (or someone) they want - it takes them down a dark, cold path. And for those people the only way they know how to find the peace and health they crave for themselves is to run away from it all. To run away from their societal duties. Their work duties. Their school duties. To wrap themselves off in their own little world. This is a story about two such people and I am not going to lie, I sympathize so hard that I am an automatic sucker for these stories. I cannot get enough of this bittersweet story. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;value-and-enjoyment&quot;&gt;Value and Enjoyment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Even when no thunder sounds&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And no rain falls, if you but ask me, &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then I will stay beside you &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved this short novella of a movie. You can take screencaps as desktop backgrounds and fill entire televisions with scenes from this movie. The story is sparse but beautiful. I enjoyed the imagery and not only just how beautiful the scenery looks (it makes me want to go see the actual gardens the movie takes its scenery from) but the people too. This is a great movie and I highly recommend it to anyone whether or not they consider themselves anime fans. &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/review-kotonoha-no-niwa&quot;&gt;Anime Review: Kotonoha no Niwa&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on August 18, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making SEC Research with RubyMotion]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/making-sec-research-with-rubymotion" />
  <id>/making-sec-research-with-rubymotion</id>
  <published>2013-08-16T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-08-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.github.com/jonathanstyu/resume/master/images/secresearch/secresearch.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;SEC Research&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time I had the idea of creating an app that would help me read filings from the SEC database. If you are not quite sure what I mean by that, every publicly traded company has to send filings every so often to the SEC. There are quarterly filings and there are annual filings. Each of these filings have information about the company’s business and its financial performance. The SEC collects these and then posts them for the public to see. Anybody can go and read them. They are public information. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of bitching and moaning from organizations about how much it costs to hire accountants and have them audit a company’s balance sheet and financials. However this is one of the most valuable services that was ever provided to the US economy by the government. Back before the SEC was created, all information belonged to the companies themselves and the banks who lent to them even if they were public. It kept people from knowing about the companies that they were investing in. The result was that people invested in crappy companies and they all lost their shirts during the Great Depression and the Market Crash of 1929.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/a/a9/Depression-stock-market-crash-1929.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Courtesy of Wikipedia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is just my own opinion but some of these financials are actually fun to read. They are pretty interesting and it is chockful of information about the company’s industry, its financials, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-problem&quot;&gt;The Problem&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sec.gov/edgar/searchedgar/webusers.htm&quot;&gt;The SEC’s website&lt;/a&gt; is not easy to navigate and it was not fun to parse through the website and get information on the filings available. It is not mobile optimized which means that I would be best served by going to the website on the desktop, download the PDFs and HTMLs, and then put them on DropBox for reading later. The task did not excite me so I wanted to get an iPad app for it. I love to read on my iPad and an app would help a lot, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem was that there was just 1 app available on the Store and it was not cheap at all. It also had a whole bunch of different little features that I was not sure that I wanted to use. Most of them are social and highlighting features that were pretty useful but I would have hardly noticed if they disappeared. For this set of features, I had to pay a pretty penny. Good for them, because it seems like that they have a good thing going, but it thus seemed to me that you could make something that does a whole lot less and then sell it for a whole lot less. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus came my idea for SEC Research, the app. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rubymotion&quot;&gt;RubyMotion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have tried to code stuff in Objective C before, trying a bunch of different tutorials, reading all kinds of books before finally collapsing into a steaming heap of whatever. I was totally confused about how to even go about creating a new app. It just seemed like there was no real easy to start guide. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alasdairmonk.com/journal/from-idea-to-appstore-in-2-weeks/&quot;&gt;a great blog post&lt;/a&gt; by some dude about how he made an iPhone app with Rubymotion. This blog post got me thinking again. I went ahead and bought Rubymotion and then threw myself into the task of making some apps. Two weeks after I first bought the product, I had created JumpShot, which was the first app that I ever made. I was extremely proud of it. It had a cool interface that let you swipe to assign players to teams and cute colored buttons that you could tap alternatively in order to let you assign stats to players. I enjoyed the work I did making this particular app. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SEC Research would be an extension of what I did in JumpShot. It would be the first app that I made that would require me to actually connect to the internet. It also had to be something simpler and better to use. It also would have to have a good reading experience. It is not something that you can just open and close whenever. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people ask me about my experience with RubyMotion. I can give those later on this post. For now, you will have to be satisfied with my chronicling of how I created SEC Research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;making-sec-research---starting-off&quot;&gt;Making SEC Research - Starting Off&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core functionality, that which I was most concerned with, was that of the actual summoning of the SEC query, putting it on the screen, searching, and saving. That was what I wanted. JumpShot had a lot less functionality but when I was making that particular app I was concentrating more on the look and feel of how it worked. In this case, I just wanted SEC Research to be able to do what I wanted it to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Objective C has a bunch of gem-like libraries called Cocoapods. RubyMotion is cool in that you can use them inside your project with the use of the RubyMotion gem &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HipByte/motion-cocoapods&quot;&gt;motion-cocoapods&lt;/a&gt;. I had used a number of different Cocoapods while making JumpShot and wanted to bring them into the loop this time for a second go around: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/samvermette/SVPullToRefresh&quot;&gt;SVPullToRefresh&lt;/a&gt;. This is the first CocoaPod that I was ever able to get working and my struggles with it taught me a whole lot about how to handle them in general. When I first started using this, I was not quite sure how to use it. I was in fact very confused. There was not a lot of documentation about how it was going to work. It basically just said, “You can use this too.” I ended up Googling through the world and finding &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hendrikswan/motioncasts-pull-to-refresh&quot;&gt;this code snippet on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. I copied what this guy did very closely. It still did not work. Then after a lot of fumbling around, I found out that if I was to add any new sort of CocoaPod to my project (it is done in the RakeFile), then I would have to go and delete the entire Pod folder under the Vendor directory in my project and then run rake again so that it could redownload the entire set. Weird behavior, but &lt;em&gt;consistently weird&lt;/em&gt;. Consistently weird is always something that you want and can handle when dealing with computers. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/siuying/NanoStoreInMotion&quot;&gt;NanoStoreInMotion&lt;/a&gt; See below with the section on Motion Model to get a sense of why this was eventually helpful. NanoStore is an Objective C data store that is non relational. NanoStoreInMotion helps me use it in my RubyMotion project. I cannot set up things like associations and such or callbacks, which is a pain, but its serialization and data storage is rock solid. This was enough for me to use it over Motion Model. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alikaragoz/AKTabBarController&quot;&gt;AKTabBarController&lt;/a&gt;. Drop in easy to use. It basically invalidates several hours of me fussling with a number of different photo imaging programs to make the image SVG or PNG look good for the tab bar at the bottom of the app. Before I used to have to be like, “Oh this is 48x48 pixels so let us go and change that …” Hilarity ensues as it does not work as planned. AKTabBarController just takes any regular PNG, shrinks its down to size and then applies a sort of monochrome filter to the image so that you can get a nice sheen to it. It looks professional and it really is the easiest thing ever to use. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing for me to do was to start off with a bunch of different gems and such so that I could get a sense of what I could just plug in and what I might need to start from scratch on. I quickly found a collection of cool gems: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/siuying/hpple-motion&quot;&gt;HppleMotion&lt;/a&gt; This is a gem that seeks to be the Nokogiri of the Rubymotion world. It has nowhere near the functionality that Nokogiri has though. It basically takes in a string of HTML/XML and parses it in a certain way. I used it a lot when I was parsing XML and HTML that returned from the SEC’s queries and web pages. I wish it had more functionality, similar that of Nokogiri, though. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/clayallsopp/geomotion&quot;&gt;GeoMotion&lt;/a&gt; Geomotion is great. It simplifies the way that you can position and move around certain objects. You can place UILabels in relation to one another in a simple and easy way. You can also create frames for objects in a very easy way: CGRect.make(x: …, y: …., height: …, width: …). This is pretty awesome. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stuff-that-did-not-work&quot;&gt;Stuff That Did Not Work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so all the good stuff out of the way. Let us get to the real work. The way that I code and make stuff is pretty simple: Find out what does not work and then do not do that. Unfortunately I do not have enough brains and knowledge to do it the Tesla way. I call it the Edison style. Just make the nonworking light bulb 999 times and eventually you’ll even screw up the task of doing it wrong. Backing ass-front forwards into the right way. While I was making SEC Research, I tried a whole lot of things and found that they did not work. They only contributed to my knowledge of RubyMotion and my eventual loss of hair. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sxross/MotionModel&quot;&gt;Motion-Model&lt;/a&gt; Motion-Model is something that comes up a lot. Basically it gives you a bunch of methods that lets you call ActiveRecord-like methods on a RubyMotion model object. This is pretty cool. You call a “Filing.all” method and then you can go and find all the Filings that are in the data store. I loved using Motion Model for the most part. The main problem came about when I started needing to close and open the app.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motion Model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with MotionModel is in the serialization. The instructions to using the serialization part of Motion Model are pretty simple: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;@filing = File.serialize_to_file(‘filings.dat’)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way that I understood it, calling this class method for any sort of MotionModel object would cause the application to serialize every instance of the object into the phone’s storage. Not the most ideal way to do it, but what can you do? When creating the favoriting functionality, I decided that it might make the most sense to create a Favorite filing class that would be created when someone touched the “Favorite” button. Then when someone closes the app, I would automatically have it call the serialize_to_file method through the &lt;em&gt;applicationWillResignActive&lt;/em&gt; method in the app_delegate file. When the app was opened then I would have it call the &lt;em&gt;deserialize_from_file&lt;/em&gt; method&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem began when I started playing around with that functionality. Somehow the functionality had changed since the last version. Serializing no longer meant that it would simply “replace” all current objects on the data file with brand new ones, it meant adding to them. So if I had 3 favorites on the disk and then opened and closed the app again, then there were 6. And so on. This would eventually crash the app, much to my amusement. I never figured out how it worked even when I went into the gem’s code, so I decided that enough was enough and went back to NanoStore, which was more stable and left me without a lot of the cool ActiveRecord-like methods but did the more important serialization thing just fine. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tyrauber/sec_query&quot;&gt;SECQuery Gem&lt;/a&gt; This is a gem that is in Ruby that does a lot of the hard work for you. You can search the SEC for specific entities, companies, and people and then read the filings associated with them. It sounds fantastic! Combined with the below gem, this would be perfect right? But well … let us see … &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/archan937/motion-bundler&quot;&gt;Motion-Bundler&lt;/a&gt; This is a RubyMotion gem that seeks to solve a very real problem. There is a huge library of Ruby Gems out there in the world. However, not all of them can be used in RubyMotion for whatever reason that it might be. There are a few gems that cannot work because they depend on other that do not work in RubyMotion. The best gems for RubyMotion are the gems that have no such dependencies. Very few gems are like this. Motion-Bundler attempts to make it so that you can use non-Rubymotion gems in RubyMotion. It sort of tries to mock up a bunch of the dependencies so that they are usable. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motion Bundler and SEC Query&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with Motion Bundler is that it was very limited in what it could do. I wanted to use the SEC Query gem in my RubyMotion project. However, the problems began. The project would not compile correctly. It would basically crash with an unspecified error that is not helpful at all. Something about a weird character in the code. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is unfortunate because it would have been awesome had I been able to actually just plug SEC_query into the app. This did not turn out to be the case however. I eventually decided that it might make sense for me to pull some of the gem’s code into my own app. However, it seemed like this program used Hpricot, something that would not have been able to work on RubyMotion. I ended up tearing out whatever I could find that might have worked including URLs and such that suited my purposes. I feel sad that I was not able to use such a beautiful product, but that is the trade off that you make so that you can use Ruby to write iPhone apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thoughts-on-rubymotion&quot;&gt;Thoughts on RubyMotion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like using it. People ask me occasionally about what it is like coding in RubyMotion. Well, it is not like I am an ultra experienced coder. One thing that I can be sure of is that I was never able to create something in Xcode and Objective-C. The farthest I was able to get was to tap out stuff in a tutorial. I was much more familiar with Ruby and RubyMotion helped me a whole lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I did felt after using it is an emptiness. I felt like even though I had been able to do so much that there was still a whole lot lacking. The only problem is that I wonder if this is because I am simply not familiar with how the thing works or I lack design assets or anything else. It just makes me wonder. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a later post, I will write more on specific things that hung me up. &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/making-sec-research-with-rubymotion&quot;&gt;Making SEC Research with RubyMotion&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on August 16, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Pretty Good Investment: VYM]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/a-pretty-good-investment-vym" />
  <id>/a-pretty-good-investment-vym</id>
  <published>2013-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I wrote From Zero to Sixty on Hedge Funds, I deliberately kept from giving any sort of investment advice. It was not that kind of book. Investment advice is tough and most of the time it requires some sort of time stamp. It also spoils quickly. Something that sounds good when you write about it in March becomes the butt of jokes in April. But after a while, I came across something that I think is pretty interesting and when incorporated into the context of a proper investing mindset and style, would work many times out of ten. I want to write about it in this post here. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-parable-of-the-little-sister&quot;&gt;The Parable of the Little Sister&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me start with a parable about my little sister. Back in 2009 she had come across a little bit of money and she had no idea what to do with it really. She figured that she would do this “investing” thing that she had heard about. Up until then I had been investing my own money on the side since 2005. I thought that I had known what to do with it. My little sister, who knew virtually nothing about investing, asked me to pick some stocks for her. I knew a few things about my little sister. One is that she would be affected by the swings in the market. She is one of those people who just did not care. She hardly knew what a stock was other than that you can sell it. She also would not be happy if she lost money in the market. She would not be able to buy boba drink and food. The last thing I knew was that she would not be needing the money for a very long time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, she is a conservative, wait-it-out investor. I figured then that the most conservative, stable stocks would make sense for her. I figured that the portfolio would not grow, but it would not lose a lot of money either. It would be like one of those ovens that you see on the television. Set it and forget it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ignored everything that was buzzing about my brain at the time - stuff that I do not even remember myself - and just picked for her the most ordinary stuff. It literally took 10 minutes to set her portfolio. Some Procter and Gamble (PG), Johnson and Johnson (JNJ), and the crown jewel Vanguard Total Market Index (VTI). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My little sister still has those stocks now, four years later. And they have grown over 60+% for her. More if her broker lets her reinvest dividends. It unfortunately does not (for godssakes never use Bank of America Merrill Lynch and she is just too lazy to switch brokers). She literally has not spent more than 5 minutes a year thinking about this portfolio. She might have missed out on the higher returns that some other people, but in terms of return per unit of stress, she wins hands down. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;making-it-simple&quot;&gt;Making it Simple&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simplicity of my little sister’s approach is part of why it works. She knew exactly what she needs or does not need to do in order to make her investing life successful. As long as she plays her game, then she is unbeatable at it. Out of my entire family, my sister is the one whose portfolio has grown the fastest per ounce of energy spent. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her success got me thinking. I had just come out of a three month sequence where I day traded Apple, PriceLine and Google weekly options, which are complex financial derivatives that are known for their extreme volatility. I lost over $12,000 in this market in just 3 months, which is pretty incredible. You will hear more about this story in a future but it took a lot to quit. When I finally did, I was exhausted. I was tired of seeing the eTrade screen and wanted to just move away from it for good. I was ready to take the Little Sister approach. I started to research companies that I wanted to invest for a long time and not care about. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was interested in something that had all the stocks that I wanted to buy for my little sister but package them all into just 1 ticker, making it easier to buy and easier to recommend. Rather than saying, “Oh a little bit of this and a little bit of that”, I could just say, “Hey buy this then.” It would be the stock that I would recommend if I ever get that generic question, “Hey I have some money to invest. What should I buy?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This investment would be safe enough for me to comfortably recommend to friends and family. These are people I personally know who may lose money from what I pick! It has the potential to be very awkward. It also has to be really simple to explain. I should be able to explain the reasons to own this particular investment without using a chart or a lot of complex financial theory. At the same time the investment has to offer enough reward to not make this utterly boring. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because I think that at some point you just need to find something that is decent and stick with it. You can do better on your financial and mental health if stay with something decent for a long time rather than something phenomenal but drives you crazy and you are constantly stepping in and out of. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to settle with VYM and I am going to tell you why below. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vym&quot;&gt;VYM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VYM is the stock ticker for the Vanguard High Dividend Yield Fund. It has $9.5 billion under management. This does really mean anything except to indicate that the ETF is pretty liquid. This is good because it lets you buy and sell the shares very easily on the market without having to sell/buy at the wrong price or wait too long for your order to fill. It is run by Vanguard. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way that I can use to describe an ETF is that it is kind of like a company except its sole goal is to hold other companies’ shares. You would buy the shares and through owning one share of this ETF, you own a proportion of shares of other companies. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My criteria in selecting VYM as the aforementioned “generic recommendation investment” is the following: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An ETF With Low Fees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had to be an ETF to help diversify your risk and get as much of the market’s performance as possible. This meant that it had to have very low fees. You do not want to pay a lot of money in fees the ETF’s provider. A high fee count (usually 1% or higher. 2% is hedge fund status) sucks away your investing performance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.businessweek.com/ss/08/09/0904_first_jobs/image/vanguard.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Vanguard Group&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked Vanguard for a few reasons. First is that they are a very large fund family. They are pretty no-nonsense and I like their philosophy of low cost indexing. Second I also like that their incentives are aligned with the investors. The other big fund families are iShares and WisdomTree. Both are publicly traded. iShares is owned by BlackRock (BLK) and WisdomTree is WETF. This is pretty cool, but it means that they are never going to be fully incentivized to deliver the lowest fees to you. Vanguard is not a publicly held company. Its shares are held by the very funds that it manages. So when you are a VYM shareholder, you not only own the shares in the ETF, but you own a bit of Vanguard too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, the fees are really low. They are charged as a percentage of how much you own in shares. If you own $100, then 1% means that you pay $1 a year. VYM charges 0.1%, which is pretty much the lowest you can go in terms of anything other than the total stock market (which is something like 0.05%). So this means that if you own $100, then you pay 10 cents a year. That is fairly low. Better yet, the fees trend lower than higher. Every so often Vanguard cuts their fees. A few years ago it was at 0.14%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Portfolio is Good&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VYM holds 388 companies with a median market cap of $115 billion. This means that companies in the index are not likely to disappear anytime soon. It is evenly distributed across a number of industries with at least 10% in Consumer Goods (15%), Financials (12.8%), Health Care (12%), Industrials (14%), and Oil/Gas (12%). These companies are weighted to the SP500 and are selected for their higher than average dividend yield. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was looking for companies that return capital to their investors often. If you dive in the financial theory, there is an argument that you can make for investing in companies that do not pay a dividend like Berkshire Hathaway, where a company can do better with the excess capital than you can. However, in reality, there is little psychic dividend that you can get from a dividend-less company. Receiving a dividend credit for holding shares in a company is immensely satisifying even if mathmetically you are doing nothing more than deducting from the principal stock price of the shares. For many people, I consider that more important because it contributes to good investing habits. Having that mental satisfaction means that people stay invested for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was looking for companies that are the backbone of the US economy and boast huge moats. Even if they did not, then it does not matter. If such a company would start to decline and vanish, the index would remove them from the ETF. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top five holdings are: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Exxon Mobil
2) Johnson and Johnson
3) General Electric 
4) Chevron
5) Microsoft
6) Wells Fargo 
7) Proctor and Gamble
8) JP Morgan Chase
9) Pfizer 
10) AT&amp;amp;T &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these companies pay a good dividend, are dominant in their field and exhibit low volatility. Low volatility means that the prices are less likely to swing a lot from day to day. This is important because maintaining prices means that if there comes a time you need to sell your shares for whatever reason, it is likely that you are not selling into crippingly low prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Dividend is Decent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A high dividend yield ETF should do better yield wise than that of the SP500, which is generally the standard people go by as the market. It changes from time to time, but the SP500’s dividend yield as of August 2013 is about 2%. Right now VYM yields about 1% more than that with 3%. Yeah that is not a lot. I am going to admit that. However it builds up over time. And when the stock price goes down, the yield goes up. There is an opportunity then to buy a lot more shares. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, it is not like Annaly or AGNC’s 20% yield. But unlike those companies, the yield from VYM is stable. Wherever I have looked for something with a higher yield than that 3%, the things that I have found also have issues that concern me. 3% seems to be the best you can do without delving into things that might keep you up at night. I am through with that crap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-use-vym&quot;&gt;How to Use VYM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not going to just tell you the name and then leave you to fend for yourself. I am also providing user instructions. No diagrams, though because I cannot draw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Buy when the price goes down&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Reinvest the dividends, which come once every three months&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If the price goes up and you have some money, buy some more &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sell when you absolutely need the money. Otherwise, leave it alone &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In fact, do not even look at the price quote from day to day. It’s not going to change a lot&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;simple-strokes-for-simple-folks&quot;&gt;Simple Strokes for Simple Folks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some great things that I have heard about investing over time: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Trading is hard and it should be done by people who care for it. Not everyone does. That is okay. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hedge funds charge high fees. They are not always deserving of these fees. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Action is the enemy of the investor. The less you do, the better. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You are not going to get rich investing. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Doesn’t really matter what you do. Just that you stick with it. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Buying stocks should be like buying a car for most people. Do not opt for the yellow Beetle with the Pikachu tail. Buy the Corolla. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the last one the best, especially as someone who cares very little for cars. You do not buy the exotic electric vehicle if you need it to help you get to work and the grocery store everyday. There is a time and place for it. Same with stocks. Buy the Corolla for investment vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many in my peer group who are big on real estate. Their entire young adult lives they are saving so that they can put down that $60-80K for that 20% down payment. I am not excited about that particular prospect myself. If that is how you want it, then yes you should go buy that first house. There is merit in your approach and the more important thing anyway is how you raise money for that investment - steady saving and living below your means - but I have been a stock guy for a very long time. I like that it is a living, breathing asset - an entity that does not die or get injured. A share of stock does not get hit by a volcano in Hawaii. Does not get older or tarnished. It keeps its freshness over time. I think that is something pretty valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for putting my money where my mouth is, VYM is the second largest investment that I have in my portfolio. &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/a-pretty-good-investment-vym&quot;&gt;A Pretty Good Investment: VYM&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on August 15, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Attack on Titan Episode 18]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/attack-on-titan-18-breakdown" />
  <id>/attack-on-titan-18-breakdown</id>
  <published>2013-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.myanimelist.net/images/anime/5/44560l.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Image courtesy of MyAnimeList&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am really enjoying the series Attack on Titan. I enjoy not just the fact that it is a very interesting world - low fantasy with a bit of steampunk - but I also love that it is just a very good action series. The source material strikes the right balance of action, suspense, and “oh crap” moments. Cliffhanger after cliffhanger month after month. Sometimes the tricks are cheap. Sometimes they are brilliant. The author does a good job of just doing crazy stuff month after month after month. I have heard that he has planned out the entire story before even sitting down to start a single panel of the manga. Such planning, if true, is evident in the huge amount of foreshadowing in early volumes that, when you go back to read them again, are now oh so obvious once the scales have fallen from your eyes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The anime follows the manga’s plot closely and in general does not try to mess up a good thing. The main problem is that there are only 48 chapters in the manga out right now (one a month, and it has been going for about 4 years now). Because of the artist’s rather slow pace (due to his drawing style and its action packed tone), the anime has to deal with the fact that if it were not careful then it could go really too fast and overtake the manga, creating a Game of Thrones like problem that will be unpleasant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early episodes, it seems like the studio is having trouble getting its feet under itself. There are copious amounts of still images and frames where it seems like they are rushing to get this done in time and falling behind in animating the entire show. Or perhaps they just did not have a budget. The studio was a spin off from a much larger, more established production studio and they were probably also dealing with logistics issues from the very beginning. Not only that, the head producer has said that he was not sure that this would be a hit. In &lt;a href=&quot;http://animediet.net/conventions/transcript-george-wada-producer-attack-on-titan-press-conference&quot;&gt;an interview&lt;/a&gt; he said: “&lt;em&gt;To be honest, in Japan, the most popular anime are the ones with moe characters, a lot of girls in it, and no cruel scenes. I thought these were the shows that would make it big, so initially I thought Attack On Titan would be a minor hit at best.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The show turned out to be a whole lot more than that and it has caught on very quickly. Presumably, an increased budget and more stable footing has come along with this unexpected popularity. The result has been quite clear in how dramatically the production values have improved in the second half of the season, the female titan arc. The story is one of the gut wrenching arcs in the entire print series (there are admittedly only 4). Now animated, it has probably the best action scenes that I have seen in a series since Full Metal Alchemist Brotherhood. In this post, I want to break down one sequence in particular from episode 18, the chasedown of the protagonist Eren and his group of fellow squad members by the eponymous female titan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This scene begins at roughly 19 min 53 seconds into the 24 minute episode. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;setting-the-tension&quot;&gt;Setting the Tension&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entering the scene, there is sense of dramatic irony overhanging the show’s characters. What is dramatic irony? It is a narrative device in where the viewer is given a piece of information that at least one of the characters in the narrative is unaware of. The female titan has already made its appearance to the viewer in episode 17 and it has already been shown earlier in episode 18 destroying a number of the scout group. Furthermore, it was discerned and revealed to the viewer that the titan is seeking the protagonist Eren for reasons unknown. The viewer is aware of this but Eren is not. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building further and adding yet more to the tension, Eren and the group of titan-hunters he has been grouped with do not know just how dangerous this particular female titan is. That it has so far killed over a dozen of their comrades with relative ease. The only indication to them that there is something wrong are the constant sending up of black smoke flares that do little to actually convey the sheer danger they are in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tense enough yet? Well, beyond what the viewer already does know is what he doesn’t, layering on a classic atmosphere of Hitchcockian suspense. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://s1.ar-static.com/images/tumblr/Shingeki_no_Kyojin_-_18_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Courtesy of Tumblr&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the episode, the commander approaches a dense forest of old growth trees and passes orders down to his entire troupe to split up. Eren’s group would travel through the forest while the rest of the team is told to stay in the trees and keep watch over the perimeter. This does not seem to make sense. Eren looks around and is shocked to find that the rest of his group mates, who he looks up to and respect as very experienced titan-killers, to be just as puzzled and confused over the mysterious set of orders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://31.media.tumblr.com/a3e989b446b1734d7d022c44aeaa2dc1/tumblr_mrcfmft0Pd1qbqk5qo2_250.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Courtesy of Tumblr&quot; /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sets a tension that is permeated throughout the entire scene to follow, that of uncertainty. The commander has passed down orders that at the surface seem incomprehensible and certain to lead to death. It is within this uncertainty that they are expected to finally face down the thing that has been killing their groupmates. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing that we as viewers do not know is the female titan’s actual location. It is not shown entering the forest. Thus the viewer is kept in suspense about how close it really is to Eren and his group. Up until the scene begins we do not know its location. Only another black smoke flare, accompanied with a pounding ominous music, gives a rough approximation of its location. It could very well be meters away from Eren himself. Wisely, a la the shark from Jaws, the director keeps the titan’s placement veiled until the absolute last moment for the big reveal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-bomb-under-the-table-ticks&quot;&gt;The Bomb Under the Table Ticks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scene begins with the hiss of black smoke. Like the floating yellow shark barrels in Jaws, they are a sudden signal that the peace is over and things are about to happen. It is a declaration. We immediately hit the ground running. Eren and his five comrades are riding horses through the forest, led by their corporal Levi. Levi leads the way, not looking back. He gets himself battle ready (by pulling out a pair of swords) and warns the rest of the troupe that when the threat arrives it will be seen for a very brief second. He is wrong in this assessment, but the viewer (and Eren too) does not know that. Thus the viewer is set in a tone of mood that his eyes are darting across the entire screen. He watches everything. Looks for everything. Anything that might be a threat. It puts us on high alert, draining our energy and coiling our stomachs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The music plays its part as well. A strong rhythmic beat begins, accelerating. It meshes with the patter of the horses’ hooves, adding its own part to the rhythm. We are not sure what is going on. We cannot see it, but we can hear it. The music is at just the right rhythmic speed that it puts us on edge. It is faster than our own heart beat and subconsciously our brain adjusts our heart beat to match it. This physical action has a strong emotional impact and the suspense starts to get to us in a real bad way. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly we see a lone soldier break into view from a patch of trees. He is not looking at the screen, facing away towards another direction. It instinctively makes us look away too. We want to see what we cannot. This is the same situation as that of Eren. Eren cannot see what this single soldier is seeing. We want to see what it is. How close is it? When will it finally appear?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The music dulls and slows down, mimicking those momentous events in our lives when we suddenly remember everything in a single second. In reality, our brains are not really recording everything in slow motion. It is in fact a post-event effect of our memory. Our brains have marked this particular event as truly important so it makes a point to enter every second of it into memory. And when we play it back in our minds, we see so much more detail. The result is like taking high speed footage of an event and playing it at a regular 60 frames per second. It is slow. Filmmakers try to emulate this technique to try to stimulate a similar response. We need to take in everything. We need to pay attention. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then suddenly the female titan makes her appearance in a fast, real fast burst. The camera jolts and jerks (note this for future reference) and the perspective suddenly twists about. We are not sure what is happening and disorientation sets in. We are confused and in that instant of confusion, the titan appears from behind a tree and smacks down the unnamed soldier like so much a fly. The music announces her presence with a loud explosive BANG. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://31.media.tumblr.com/84f33f7274ae2123c6827892e3ad08cb/tumblr_mri085MSTj1qlpa51o3_500.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Courtesy of Tumblr&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-titan-appears&quot;&gt;The Titan Appears&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things suddenly move very fast from here. Levi shouts out the order to “Run!” and the music picks up the pace. The viewer feels tense and on-edge from a suspenseful scene because they are aware of their own lack of knowledge about the development of something meaningful on the screen. The source of the suspense has changed. The focus is no longer on where the titan is, but instead on the chase. The female titan is now present on the screen so that tension has been relieved. However, several other elements are added. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The titan has appeared and Eren’s group mates quickly fill in some necessary exposition in order to inform Eren and the viewer of the gravity of their situation. The Titan is fast. Though it starts quickly behind them, it is faster than their horses can cover. It quickly gains on them. Camera-wise, the animators help ground this feeling with one particular scene that establishes the relation of distance between the female titan and Eren. After quickly killing the soldier, the camera cuts to several closeups of the characters, but then switches to one extended action sequence where the camera pans away from the group quickly to the left to show the titan running at pace with them at a distance away. The titan then abruptly changes direction to approach the fleeing group from the right side. She leaps through a tree in the way smashing it into wooden bits and there is a quick instant where she hovers over Eren in slow motion. She reaches for him but misses and falls behind them. However she quickly recovers and rejoins the chase. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a great sequence with many of the slow-mo elements we have seen earlier. However it is included for more than to just show off the animators’ talents. This particular sequence definitively establishes their relational positions in space between the relevant characters in the scene: The female titan and Eren’s group. If you notice, because of the sheer scale of the players, we do not have context references for who is what and is where. This “pan back” distance type shot lets the viewer know immediately that the titan is right on their tail and is not very far back. We know that this is no gimmick of the camera (in other words, no cheap cuts). The titan is right there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This establishment of relational positioning is important in keeping the viewer from getting confused about who is where. Without scenes and references like this, someone can get too bogged down in the question of “What is going on?” and be distracted from the feeling of “Oh no, what is going to happen now!” In addition, knowing exactly where the titan is in relation to where Eren is lets the viewer extrapolate in their own heads about just how much time they have left before they are overrun. The more extrapolation &lt;strong&gt;intentionally&lt;/strong&gt; left to the viewer, the more suspenseful and tense the scene turns out to be. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And do not forget that there is still one major tension lingering in the background of the viewer’s mind: The viewer remains unaware of whether or not the appearance of the titan has been planned for. In other words, whether the commander - who, if you remember, passed down specific orders to split up the troupe and send only Eren’s group alone down the forest path despite the apprehensions of Eren and even many of his more experienced soldier peers. Their tension is shared by the viewers as well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;grab-pull-and-die&quot;&gt;Grab, Pull, and Die&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the scene is established. We know exactly where Eren and his pursuer is. We know what we are to be uncertain of and why. It is time to escalate the stakes. Three soldiers appear from behind the female titan, offering reinforcements. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://24.media.tumblr.com/ca7f995bb2c5d8828335f98fb88fcfbf/tumblr_mrdt3oDWhf1ql41ypo1_500.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Courtesy of Tumblr&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at both the clips above and below, we note a few things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we get flash second glimpses of the soldiers’ faces before they killed in a bloody burst of a cloud. This is a deliberate choice by the animators. You would think at first, “Wait a second, why bother to spend time to give tangible facial expressions to something you would see for less than a split second?” These take time, money and investment to design, draw, and animate. It is not just an attention to detail. It is about taking advantage of our ability to subconsciously process imagery very quickly. We see their faces even though we do not “see” them. Not seeing them would take us out of the scene and we would break the emotional impact. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, notice that the entire scene (despite the gifs breaking it up into two) is just one cut. This is also deliberate because it then gets to show off the camera’s jolting movements. What path is it following? Let us track it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The soldier fires off a pylon and the camera tracks its movement, quickly it propels itself backwards away from the soldier at a fast speed. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It bursts through the female titan’s hair, just barely missing it and the camera seems to follow the pylon right through the spread of her hair &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The camera would continue along but suddenly the female titan grabs the wire attached to the pylon and arrests its movement&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;She pulls and the camera stays fixed and suddenly the helpless soldier is brought into the briefest of focuses very very quickly before being crushed against the tree in a cloud of blood&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The camera slows its movement to give extra emphasis, slowing down the sequence events so that viewer can absorb the details. However, the camera does not linger too long. Now comes the immediate next scene. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://31.media.tumblr.com/a5c1d6b04cc160205a692f19f45132b1/tumblr_mrdt3oDWhf1ql41ypo2_500.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Courtesy of Tumblr&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The female titan spins on her heels (in a nice bit of flair from the animators). The camera pulls back far far away from her. It is almost like as if the camera, echoing our own thoughts, wants to get as far away from her as possible. We want to escape too. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The second soldier swings into view and gets close to the camera and we see his face and it seems like as if he might get away&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The camera stops its backwards movement and suddenly we are being pulled back towards the female as she grabs the soldier’s pylon-wire and drags it back towards herself&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The soldier is crushed between the female titan’s fingers and the scene ends with her eyes filling the entire screen gazing out towards the viewer &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in this quick sequence the camera bursts backwards, stops abruptly, then pulls backwards again faster before quickly reversing and exploding forwards. This short sequence seeks to emphasize the female titan’s agility, intelligence, and brute strength. The movements she executes the viewer experiences through the camera’s jolts and they reverse quickly and always convey a sense of great movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-cliffhanger&quot;&gt;The Cliffhanger&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speed and quickness with which the reinforcements were dispatched does the job it is meant to do. It  is shocking. But to add to the impact, the immediate next cut shows Petra, one of Eren’s team members, looking back off screen at what we presume to be the scene we just saw, turning her head forwards to Corporal Levi and asking in a cracking voice for orders. This reaction shot - a shot that shows not the actual event but observers’ reactions to it - is a powerful mood setter. Recall Darth Vader’s first scene in the movie the Empire Strikes Back. He slowly walks towards a group of Imperial Officers and the camera focuses not on him but instead on the facial expressions of everyone else around him … watching him. By watching not the subject but rather the reactions of other people &lt;em&gt;in the scene&lt;/em&gt; we are subconsciously influenced to mirror those feelings. In the case of Petra and Eren, the moods we are influenced to mirror are simple: abrupt shock and sheer fear. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scene ends with a cliffhanger, but the rampup to it is handled expertly. Near the end of the scene, they flash to a high perspective, looking down on the group as they flee the approaching titan and the way that the camera is set up the approaching titan is mere meters away from them, creeping up from the bottom right of the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the group call out to Levi, who up until now has not said a single thing. While the rest of Eren’s groupmates nearly break out in panic, the leader has remained silent. He is a naturally silent and stoic character. Does he know what to do? Is this all part of the plan? It is not for certain, and when Levi finally reacts and does something, the scene abruptly ends with cut to black. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Action scenes are tough to coordinate and direct. This is because action in the real world is not nicely coordinated. It is marked with craziness and chaos. The movie director’s job is to bring order to that chaos with good camerawork and expert but sparse dialogue. This simple scene in Attack on Titan has a simple premise: The female titan is chasing Eren and closing quick. However, the nuances underneath its execution demonstrate something really impressive. &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/attack-on-titan-18-breakdown&quot;&gt;Attack on Titan Episode 18&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on August 14, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple in 2013]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/apple-in-2013" />
  <id>/apple-in-2013</id>
  <published>2013-08-11T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-08-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/fa/Apple_logo_black.svg/200px-Apple_logo_black.svg.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Courtesy of Wikipedia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2012, I published a book on Amazon called “Apple and Samsung: A Love Story.” It had first started as a book in where I take a deep look at the entire company, its environment, and its products. That part of the book was quickly overtaken by the section on Samsung Electronics, which I had then identified as Apple’s foremost challenger in the cell phone space. Samsung is a company that does not have a lot written about them by journalists and such, but there was a lot of case studies and academic material available on Google Scholar and I was able to mine that for a lot for information about the company’s culture, its structures, and its history. Some great papers include &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0024630107000714&quot;&gt;“Samsung Motors”&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/0022-1082.00115/full&quot;&gt;“Samsung’s Ownership Structure”&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=556923&quot;&gt;“Samsung’s Mobile Phone Business”&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of what I wrote in the book about the company’s culture of innovation and relentless competitiveness is still relevant. After all, Samsung has taken a big bite out of Apple’s iPhone market, which I identified as pretty much the only revenue/profit engine that matters in the company. From what I understand though, it seems like some new factors have started to be thrown into the mix. I did not want to go back into the book and write it all out so here it is as a post on the site. The first one since I left App Academy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summarizing-the-book&quot;&gt;Summarizing the Book&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book, I suggested that Apple should take its iPhone schedule and split it into two. At the time as it is now, Apple releases 1 iPhone a year. This used to be in July or so (with WWDC) before switching it to the fall with the iPhone 4S presumably so that it could take advantage of the holiday buying season. The problem with this is that an entire year goes by without a new iPhone. There are advantages to this of course. The new iPhone is always hard to make (The CEO of Foxconn, Apple’s supplier, has said that the iPhone 5 in particular is the most difficult product that the company has ever put together) and the long season gives them time to get it down to an art, improving yield. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with this schedule is that it is just too much time in between new products on the market. It gives opportunity to Android competitors to iterate and come out with a lot of features, leaving the iPhone behind. I suggested that Apple should switch the iPhone to a two-tiered schedule. The “S” version of the phone - the ‘4S’, ‘3S’, and such where the upgrade is on the software side rather than the hardware side, would be released in July and the hardware upgraded phone - a numbered iPhone - would be released in September/October (September better than October. The 4S was in October and it was late even then). This way there would be two phones every year that could be sold to the market. Apple did not take up this schedule. The new iPhones continues to be released 1 year apart, though it might seem to be the case that there are two models this time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/d/da/China_Mobile_Logo.svg/200px-China_Mobile_Logo.svg.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;China Mobile - essential to Apple in China. Logo courtesy of Wikipedia.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second thing that was essential to Apple’s growth and continued dominance would be its performance in China. Apple in 2011-2012 had been absolutely growing gangbusters in China. The performance of the Asia Pacific unit had grown from some several hundred million to $8 billion in Q2 2012. To continue this growth, I wrote that Apple should look to open a whole bunch of new stores (they talked about dozens several years ago) as well as complete a deal with China Mobile, the biggest telecom operator in the world. Considering that China Mobile is larger than Unicom and Telecom combined and the new iPhone 5 has shown itself capable of connecting to and using the telecom’s unique cellular standard, it seemed that it was important that Apple was to get on that network and that the company knew it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-the-iphone-to-apple&quot;&gt;What is the iPhone to Apple?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The statistics have not borne this out though, as the gross margins have declined from last year and the first quarter with the new iPhone 5 on the market and net income for the 3 months ended June 29th declining some $2 billion from the previous year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It used to be that the iPhone was the company’s main driver of profit growth. The 4S version of the phone had some 50% gross margins and sold in the millions. Because of the unique arrangement it has with the telecom operators like Verizon and AT&amp;amp;T, the iPhone was a $800 product that sold like it was priced some $500 less. This is pretty much unique in the consumer electronics world. The 5 though is something different. It seems like the gross margins are much lower for this product. I checked through the cost of the bill of goods and it is not all that much different from that of the 4 and 4S so it probably has something to do with the yield of the phone’s manufacturing. If yield is low, the bad products’ costs are rolled into the costs of the phones that do make it to the market. The iPhone’s scratchable metal case and really thin screen seems to have impacted its manufacturing yield. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It used to be that when Apple sells a lot of iPhones, it makes a whole lot of money and we did not have to worry about anything else, so overwhelming did the iPhone’s profits dominate the company financial condition. In 3Q2013, this did not seem to be the case. Apple overperformed on the iPhone, selling over 31 million when some analysts were expecting in the twenties. What happened though was that this did not immediately lead to a huge beat in the net revenue numbers. In fact, it missed those estimates. People are buying the cheaper 4S over the 5 as ASP declined. It is true that it is cheaper to make a 4S than a 5, but that does not seem to be enough to outweigh the drop in price (usually about a $100 decline from one model to a year older).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only that, the decline in profits from the shift from the iPad Jumbo to the iPad mini seem to be hitting the bottom line. In the book I argued that the iPad’s profits were nice but did not move the needle. The margins, which were estimated to be something like 30%, were too small in comparison to the iPhone. Well I did not expect the iPad Mini - a product I love a whole lot personally by the way - to start a downward trend in profit margin. The product was popular and the result was a decline in profit. The profit we expected to come from the iPad division was lost and it was not made up by the iPhone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now instead of having two great products delivering profit, there are two headaches. The iPhone is getting older and its product line is maturing. Customers no longer need to have the latest model. And the iPad tablet computer space has grown faster than any product before, but as I feared in my heart, it was not because the market was necessarily bigger. It was because the infrastructure - from the retail stores to the Foxconn assembly line - already existed to make tapping that market faster. The stats that talked about the iPad growing faster than the iPhone ever never really did say anything about the legitimacy of the entire market. It grew faster than anything else before but that only meant that it hit the wall that much faster. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-china-issue&quot;&gt;The China Issue&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7009/6684953659_f8276b8da4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Courtesy of Elizabeth Phung on Flickr (http://www.flickr.com/photos/lizphung/6684953659/)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for China, the once-growth engine is now a drag on growth. In 2012, Apple delivered $8 billion in a single quarter from its Apple sales. One year later, &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2013/07/23/apple-international-q3-2013/&quot;&gt;revenues in that area has dropped some 43%&lt;/a&gt;. It has been a year and none of the things that we pointed out should happen strategically in Apple has happened. There are still only 8 flagship Apple stores in China, a country with over 1 billion people. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the iPhone remains missing on China Mobile. Who knows why this is the case. Since the technical hurdles have largely been cleared, it seems to be something about the terms of the agreement. Perhaps there is some sort of demand that Mobile wants that Apple is absolutely not willing to give like a China Mobile branded iPhone or pre-installed apps on the home screen. Whatever the reason and however legitimate such a reason would be, iPhone’s competitors from Xiaomi, ZTE, and Samsung are on that platform and being actively sold. Considering that I wrote in the book that I considered Apple’s biggest strategic dropped ball was to allow the rise of Android by not releasing a Verizon version of the iPhone as soon as possible, this is probably hurting Apple in China. To what extent? Who knows. Not all of China Mobile’s customers can afford an Apple iPhone and the majority of the network’s customers are not on 3G either, which cuts down on the number of potential customers available. However, it still means much that the iPhone is not on the biggest network on the planet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New issues have arisen in China. The government has criticized the company for its arrogance, tarnishing the brand and forcing the company to issue an apology for some of its actions over there. Personally I found the actual tiff - something about return and guarantee policies - just that, a tiff, but it seems that it was the ripe thing for the government to take advantage. In the end it could have been anything but it seems like having an American company dominate such a vital part of the Chinese market was troubling to the Chinese. They took efforts to curb Apple’s growth in China, something that I thought about while writing the book but did not mention. In my heart, I suppose I did not want to believe it. In light of the new revelations about Apple’s cooperation with the NSA and other American government agencies for intelligence, the Chinese government is going to take bigger and bolder steps to curb Apple’s growth in China. Many tech companies I knew were going to get hurt by these revelations, but Apple - so reliant on the China market - had the most to lose. It lost badly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The Future&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://allthingsd.com/20130810/circle-sept-10-on-your-calendar-for-apples-big-iphone-event/&quot;&gt;AllThingsD broke the report&lt;/a&gt; that the new iPhone was to be announced to the world September 10th, 2013. It is the first set of news to come out in a while. Will people line up for it as they did for the 5 or the 4s? In some numbers yes … but enough?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had scarcely thought about Apple’s new products in 2013. For the entire year they had basically vanished and stayed under the radar. They released just 1 new memorable product, the new 12 hour MacBook Air in the summer (I guess the new Mac Pro too but few people are going to buy that). It is troubling to think that the company has gone through nearly 9 months in 2013 selling the same thing that they sold back in November 2012. True they went through a near total refresh that holiday season, but it seems like that they had shot their wad too soon. The benefit from having all those refreshes in the holiday season led to their biggest revenue quarter ever, but it left them spent for the rest of the year and the loss in mind share probably outweighed the financial gains of having all those bullets in the air during the holidays. The biggest Apple stories in the first half of 2013 to me was their huge buyback, their bond sales, and increased dividend. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not really have answers for the future of Apple and the iPhone. I sold my stock a long time ago so I no longer have a financial interest in the company but I still like Apple products. I write apps in RubyMotion and sell books on their iTunes Bookstore. I could suggest a few things, but I do not think that Apple will take any of those suggestions. I could suggest some sensible things, but I am not sure that the company will take up even those. It is tough to project what the company will do in the future, a negative sort of uncertainty that I think is troubling. Very troubling. It is more likely that they will do nothing and stay the course, whatever that may be in their minds. Who knows what it might be in their minds. &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/apple-in-2013&quot;&gt;Apple in 2013&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on August 11, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elysium]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/elysium-review" />
  <id>/elysium-review</id>
  <published>2013-08-10T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-08-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Saturday I went to go see a movie called Elysium, directed by a guy named Neil Blomkamp. Do not ask me how to pronounce that, because I cannot. Wikipedia has a pretty good description of how the movie goes but here is the total plot summary. It is the 22nd century and the world is overcrowded and running out of resources. The sort of Malthusian nightmare that people have nightmares about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-plot&quot;&gt;The Plot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of interesting world building here. Los Angeles is majority hispanic and there is a lot of language switching between English and Spanish. You get to meet a whole lot of different characters from Los Angeles, the riff raff of the world who look like ordinary folks, cuss and fight. There is a thriving “criminal” organization that tries to illegally transport people from the earth to Elysium, presumably so that they can use the medBay, some sort of MacGuffin of a device that heals people in a single instance. They set this up with a desperation run early in the movie. Three space ships make a blatant run for the Elysium border. Jodie Foster has a sleeper agent (who would later be a villain in the movie, played by the protagonist from District 9) shoot two of them down with a ground to space missile. It was played to be cruel and merciless. It definitely was, however all I could think while watching was how the missiles could have enough fuel to reach space and why they did not send said missiles from Elysium itself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This incident causes repercussions in the system and Jodie Foster, who plays the ultra hawkish Defense Secretary, gets fed up with the system. Irritated by her reprimand, she goes and engineers a deal with the CEO of a defense contractor. The defense contractor will go and reboot the entire system of Elysium and that would make her the President. The President would then go and hire the CEO’s company for all the product that they would make in the future, guaranteeing riches and shareholder profits ad infiniteum. This is illustrative of corporate greed and the defense-commercial self-feeding beast. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, Matt Damon plays a criminal on parole. He was arrested for boosting cars. He meets the childhood friend of his, and is looking forward to a date with her when suddenly he gets caught in a radiation vault at his work. The radiation vault gives him a fatal dose and now he has 5 days to get to Elysium so that he can use a med bay. He arranges a deal with a former contact in the underworld, the same people who organized the blatant run to Elysium that we saw earlier in the movie. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty interesting setup, and it is the first few scenes of the movie. You would think then that the rest of the movie blossoms and blooms into a deep introspection of the relevant issues. The repercussions of a secret deal between a corporation and the government organization that hires it. The morality of breaking the law to save your own life and that of those you love. The dilemma between maintaining resources for posterity and the evil morality of withholding them from people who need them. The place for the everyman in a technologically advanced where droids can do the majority of the work that humans can do. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas, none of this is hit upon. The movie mostly runs on these few premises to make Matt Damon run around, fight people and shoot guns. He wears a metal frame and then fights people. Then Jodie Foster is killed by her own sleeper agent employee, and decides that she would rather die than live to face the consequences of the world she created. Matt Damon gives control of Elysium to the underworld boss who shows himself to have a heart of gold by instantly making every citizen of earth a citizen of Elysium for free which causes the automated system to send med ships to the surface so that everyone can get healed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-issues&quot;&gt;The Issues&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are elements of the plot that very consciously make the story such that the dystopia that you see in front of you in the movie universe defies common sense. We never meet any of Elysium’s citizens or get a sense of how they act towards people. They are apparently conditioned to be like the French elite at the eve of the French Revolution. They do not care about the poor and live their own lives, presumably paid for by the income generating assets that they own. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly is the metaphor of advanced health care, which is represented by the all-healing Med Bay. It is a pretty awesome device. It can heal anyone who is not dead even if they are just slivers away from it. What a product! I would love to see how it works. Presumably it goes to show the miracle of modern medicine, which can make diseases that were once fatal now curable. However, modern medicine is not like this. There are costs associated with making this product. There are tools and instruments that have to be paid for. There is expertise that costs money and investment to develop (in the form of doctors). But the med bay is automated. It presumably uses no other resource but energy. It also is instanteous. What the hell? Why haven’t the citizens and hospitals of the world simply replace all their nurses and casts with one of these bays and just cycle people in and out all day? This is a product that supposedly is owned by every rich person on Elysium. What if just one of these rich people grows a heart and decides that he would just send his own to earth once a month to heal like a million people? It would certainly satisfy someone’s ego to know that they are a sort of a savior. This seems to be common sense and perhaps such a dystopia is defined by the lack of said common sense, but it puzzled me as a viewer of the movie. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue I had with the movie was its depiction of the Malthusian apocalypse. In this dystopia, the world has become such that now there are not enough resources for everyone. People have been talking about this sort of thing happening forever (it for example shows up in that new Dan Brown book Inferno). I am not sure what to think about such an event. I feel that the system that has been created and put into place today more than guarantees that are enough resources for people. There have been many times that people and analysts would put a constant growth rate on something and simply assume that in the not so distant future that the reckoning would finally come about. Disasters are rare. They are acts of God. In reality, life changes and adapts. Agriculture adapts and becomes more productive. New technologies are developed in order to create new opportunities for making more of the resources that we have or use entirely new types. Peak oil was huge. I read a book called “Twilight in the Desert” by Matthew Simmons and in it he talked about the decline of the Ghawar oil field in Saudi Arabia, which would then lead to the decline of Saudi Arabia as the provider of cheap oil, which would then cripple the economy. The book was convincing and indeed it seems like Ghawar, the biggest oil field ever found, is on its way out. However then came the rise of “Saudi America”, where fracking and other new alternative energy technologies have emerged to replace the loss of oil from Ghawar. New externalities can still occur to replace virtually anything that we have lost. For example, what happens if that hair-brained idea from the Google guys works? The one where they land a satellite on an asteroid and mine its resources? These examples are easy to rebut right here, but the point remains solid: That systems are robust and adaptable. They change in according to the forces acting on them. Life finds a way. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-conclusion&quot;&gt;My Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the movie. The melodrama made me cry, something that a lot of movies have been doing to me lately. The action was satisfying. It needed more robot stuff to satisfy the lizard brain “smash head with rock” side of me, but I still think that it did a fine job. Not everything can be Pacific Rim. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one thing that I did not enjoy was the world building that tried to do more than it could. The Med Bay is just one example, but it was the most glaring. What a device! It is the least plausible thing for me to swallow. That being said, it is a movie and a technically well made one. &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/elysium-review&quot;&gt;Elysium&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on August 10, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anime Review: Sakurasou no Pet na Kanojo]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/sakurasou-pet" />
  <id>/sakurasou-pet</id>
  <published>2013-08-04T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-08-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Crunchyroll calls this the Pet Girl of Sakurasou, which brings up an uncomfortable imagery. For the sake of brevity, I will call this SPK. This is a highly enjoyable series based on a 10-volume set of light novels. I have not read all that much of the light novel series (the tone of which I found somewhat bizarre and a little conventional), but I found that this series did a phenomenal job of adapting the series. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;animation&quot;&gt;Animation:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SPK is a beautiful looking series, which is all the most intriguing considering that it has an urban setting. There are a lot of great looking series out there but many of them are set in great looking places like some sort of ocean town. Sola is an example that comes to mind. However, there are not a whole lot of series that manage the act of creating beauty from an otherwise unbeautiful thing: the city. There are places where you just have to pause the video and take in the imagery. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of the characters are memorable with Mashiro standing out most of all. I think Mashiro - who herself vaguely resembles the cats that Kanda takes care of - is the best looking character I have seen in all of the series that have come out of 2012. Considering what she looks like in the light novel illustrations, in where she looks like a pretty ordinary - if occasionally confused - girl, this is incredible. Probably the biggest gap in anime-novel design since the work Akio Watanabe (of World God Only Knows fame) did in Bakemonogatari (Senjougahara in the novel illustrations looked absolutely bizarre). I took a look at the work character designer Masahiro Fujii did in other anime and found him having also done timeless, classic works like Zero No Tsukaima and Yumekui Merry. How about that? You never know where talent comes from. The rest of the characters are well designed in a way such that they are memorable. You will not find yourself wondering as to whether or not you have met this character already. This is a big deal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of this in of itself are not a huge deal. There are plenty of series out there that are very good looking. The standards of the new decade have become such that even the worst of the crap that gets put out into the new season have great looking character designs and scenery. So it means a lot more that this sort of stuff is backed with a great story and performances as it is with SPK. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sound&quot;&gt;Sound:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The character acting is great. Ano Hana’s Ai Kayano does a great job here taking the other side of the temper bar for Mashiro. This is a different role from what she has done for Hyouka, Servant x Service and even Say You Love Me. She takes the same type voice tone in Guilty Crown but … let’s not talk about that again. In SPK, she does a great job. Her Mashiro has a dry boke humor and delivers ridiculous lines in a level tone that is pretty hilarious. And when the mood changes, her voice cracks with a certain twinge of emotion that is absolutely heart breaking. She was the right VA for the role and it is hard to imagine anyone else taking this sort of role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the cast is incredibly great as well. This is not a series that requires someone to give the same performance over and over again. People laugh, cry, fall in love, and break their hearts. Yoshitsugu Matsuoka’s Kanda does funny, stupid and angry in all the right ways. His voice is also very distinct unlike how it is with many other male characters. Mariko Nakatsu has a phenomenal voice as the Aoyama. Like Attack on Titan’s Yui Ishikawa, I hope that she is just at the start of her career and goes on to do some other great roles into the future. Natsumi Takamori is completely 100% unrecognizeable as the dour, dark girl from Another (coincidentally also named Misaki). I like to imagine that it is the same Misaki in both series and that she commutes between both stories every other week, taking off her eyepatch and turning into this crazy sounding Genki-girl. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The music is ordinary and not at all that memorable. It does not stand out on its own but supports the story very well. Writing from my own perspective of having watched the series a bit ago, there are no pieces of background music that caught my attention. The OP and ED are great, following the Toradora formula in taking a happy light tone at the start and then transitioning into something darker and more serious in the second half. I especially enjoyed OP1, with an opening hook that reminds you of the pounding heartbeat you get when you meet your first love. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;story-and-character&quot;&gt;Story and Character:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I combine these. This is probably the one big series surprise of 2012. In fact it takes on the dream that any author should have with their own work. It starts out with a premise that had the potential of being something real stupid but then unexpectedly transitions itself into something much deeper and more rewarding. But if it were that stupid then this story would never have gotten 26 episodes. The directors knew how to handle this property and they did it well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It starts out with this premise that Kanda has to take care of this girl named Mashiro, who is an art prodigy. She is great at what she does but otherwise has no idea how to take care of herself in the real world. She is so quiet and foolish that it almost hinges on autistic territory, and I found myself at first uncomfortably taking on these comparisons. Were they aiming to make fun of autistic people? But the best way to fight these sort of comparisons is to deliver a deep, fulfilling and rich story and flesh out these characters from their empty initial husks. SPK did this. Very quickly they advance the story and just as speedily I left behind these thoughts and misgivings. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read the first volume of the light novel and found it awkward and clumsy in how it handled the story. The author may have been trying to get himself into the right tone and setting. The directors of the anime, well aware that they had the time and luxury to create a great story here, revamped a lot. They were not afraid to mess with the source material to get the best story that they can get. For a non spoilery example, in the novel Kanda is told from the very beginning that Mashiro is a great and famous painter. This is not the case in the anime, where this is hidden from both Kanda and the viewer until the very end of the episode, whereupon it hits you with a lot of force. There was also a whole lot of fan servicey stuff that was taken out from the books, which I think did much in making the story move faster and flow much better. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of series that do a great job of creating story and characters on their own terms. For example, my favorite yardstick is always Ga-Rei Zero, which has this ridiculous universe in where you have spirits and monsters but crafts a beautiful, touching and heartbreaking story from it. It just goes to tell you that the best stories happen anywhere. They are great not because of where they are set, but because of the way that bring out our essential humanness. For many series, they have to create this universe and brings us into it. Very few series try to bring a great story into our own world. Even fewer succeed. SPK does. This is the most “real” series that I have ever watched since Hataraki Man (which was depressing in its own way). Barring the ridiculous premise of an art prodigy and what not, it is not hard to imagine a story like this happening in our own real world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The directors knew from the very beginning what sort of tone and theme they want to hit with SPK: that of growth and togetherness of family. No series does a better job of talking about family and togetherness than Full Metal Alchemist but this is a close second and I give it honorable mention because FMA created its own universe. The challenges and tribulations that these characters go through - which I think people can sympathize with so closely - that there are times when I am not sure whether or not they are talking about the characters or myself. We have all gone through disappointments, failures, and uncertain futures. SPK’s characters do the same. They try their best, fall short, and sit in the dark, setting sun wondering whether or not that they are good enough in this world to survive. Just like any of us. These are the same real world disappointments that we all have to live through. It is just part of being human. The way that these people get past it and live to live another day should inspire. They are lonely, bizarre souls lashed together in the midst of the turbulence of a cold, cruel world. Only by holding to each and one another can they survive. Same should be for us. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that SPK has a great story. It is a story that will catch your attention. You will love these characters and want them to succeed. You will keep tuning in again and again to see if they do. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;value-and-enjoyment&quot;&gt;Value and Enjoyment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the surprise of 2012 and worth the time to watch. Unfortunately it did not seem to be such a huge hit and this is probably the last we will see of SPK. This is eminently disappointing because the story at the heart of this series is better than much of the crap that we see dumped into the market. There are a lot of series that make first choice for recommendation but I think this is a good dark horse choice for those who want to see something different and unconventional.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/sakurasou-pet&quot;&gt;Anime Review: Sakurasou no Pet na Kanojo&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on August 04, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Integrating With Craigslist]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/integrating-with-craigslist" />
  <id>/integrating-with-craigslist</id>
  <published>2013-07-11T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-07-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-a-form&quot;&gt;Creating a form&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rene and I had talked about one of the challenges of creating a rental form collection product would be that when it comes to marketing, there is nothing that beats Craigslist. Craigslist is the end all, be-all when it comes to marketing rentals and trying anything else would be a waste of time. So one of the challenges is that there is no Craigslist API. There is no automated way to put a listing onto Craigslist. So the only way is to do it through human effort. But while it is not possible to do this automatically, we can try to make it as easy as possible. Rene suggested that we would be able to provide HTML templates of the ads. You would pick a Craigslist List template and it would spit out the HTML that you could then just copy and paste right into the entry. This is the major challenge that I was urged to work on today.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/integrating-with-craigslist&quot;&gt;Integrating With Craigslist&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on July 11, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fleshing Out Form]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/fleshing-out-form" />
  <id>/fleshing-out-form</id>
  <published>2013-07-10T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-07-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;fleshing-out-a-powerful-client-side-form&quot;&gt;Fleshing out a Powerful Client Side Form&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have created a few forms before for Rails and I have played around with Backbone before too. However this is the first time I really have gone heads first with creating a complex, single page application that would help create an applicant for a rental by collecting its parts, saving them, even validating them, and then submitting them all on the client side. It is kind of amazing if you think about it. Once Rails sends down the JavaScript code to the browser, there is not a single bit of interaction between the server and the user until the user is ready to send up the data and the data is complete in a way that is ready to receive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having worked on a similar product before in CareDox, I found that the less interaction between the user and the server, the quicker and better. Paul had implemented a bit where the data would constantly be sent and updated on the server side but since the server was so slow, it took forever to get anything done. I would type something into a box then wait impatiently for about 2-3 minutes. It by itself did not take all that long but in the end since the form is so long it would take forever and it was incredibly demoralizing. I decided then that for the rentForm I wanted a product that basically did all the validations on the client side and did not touch the server at all until the thing was ready to submit. And when it was done, then it would send it all up in just one big hash. This was the goal. How can someone go ahead about that? Yesterday was the easy part, just creating the forms on the HTML. Now it is time to actually make them functional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with creating a number of models in Rails that would represent the parts of the form that would eventually be modular. These were the incomeDetails, emergencyContacts, personal references, and rent histories. These would all be models that “belong’ to the applicant. Then the applicant model would accept a nested attributes for these individual parts. There were no validations on the backend because God knows what I would do in that case if something came back bad. Seems like a pretty thin tightrope so the code on the front end is going to have be really air tight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the front end, I put a Backbone app into the page but unlike how I did it with all the other Backbone apps that I created in the earlier days, I was going to tweak the formula. When I initialized the router, I created one Backbone model, which represented a single applicant. Eventually I will be able to have multiple applicants in a single submission (using collections) but I figured that can wait until later. For now we have to be happy with what can be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Becuase the app has a sidebar and advances throughout the page, I wanted data to be capable of being “saved’ and persisted to a single instance of the Backbone model. This way, the single Applicant would be built over time and then submitted with a single AJAX call. When I first wrote the form I wrote it in a traditional way. The name of the input would be something like “applicant[name]’ or in the case of a nested attribute “applicant[nested_attribute][0][name]’. But then I found that when someone hit the button and I made the call to Backbone to “set’ the attributes, that the applicant attributes would not “build up’. Instead, the latest one would replace the earlier ones. This is because of the way the “set’ seems to work. Because the attributes are all nested under “applicant’, I found that it would simply reset the entire set of the applicant attributes. Deleted everything that I had done before! I was displeased and Googled for a bit for a solution. Did not find one. So I decided upon a hackish roundabout way. I took out the “applicant’ in all the name fields of the form so that I could set the attributes raw. This made sure that nothing got overrode because Backbone.model.set only looks at what is different. So the Applicant.attributes would have like “nested_attribute-0-bunch of stuff’. I then overrode the to_JSON for the Applicant model so that it would take all the attributes and then wrap them in a single applicant object and return that. This did the trick. Now all the params are in a proper format so that Rails can accept them and use them to create a complete Applicant model instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I was not done. I wanted to have validations. Validations is built into the model class but there were two problems that made it unamenable to what I wanted to do. First, validation is called only upon “save’. So that it would be such that nobody can see that they are doing it wrong until they hit the big red button at the end of the entire form! Imagine how irritated you would be if you would spend 15 minutes on a rental form, hit submit, and then suddenly find that it had spit back a whole bunch of crap errors at you. You want to know about these errors as soon as possible. Also, since the sections like personal reference and such are all actually representative of separate models from the actual applicant model, it would have made me to go and create separate Backbone models for all those individual things and that was just going to go drive me insane. So I decided that I would roll my own validation set for this page. I created a “validate’ funct that would be called and I passed to it the serialized form data created at the click event as well as a callback function that simply sets the attribute and handles the rest of the other stuff that successfully saves. Not DRY at all since this is a feature that needs to be in all of the Views that I have throughout the Backbone app but without work I am not excited to do I am not particularly excited to refactor it. For now we shall have to live with it. I also made arbitrary decisions on what should or should not be required. In the future, I would like to see this customizable and I do see a way forward to it. Would have to be on the backburner for now though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The form product continues to need some work but I am going to turn my attention elsewhere tomorrow as I am going to spend some time working on the dashboard and what the landlord is going to see as he goes about finding tenants. I am interested in seeing how this is going to work especially if I might tag particular applicants as acceptable or not. PerfectPerusals was in my opinion rather simple and really was just a project. I want RentForm to be something real. Something that customers might actually want to use. I really want this product to be something that can actually be impressive. But that means I am going to have put a lot of work into it. Just keep at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I Should Do: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Refactor some of the code that would simply validate for presence so that a user can eventually just pass in a number of attributes that they want the app to validate for and it would simply do that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/fleshing-out-form&quot;&gt;Fleshing Out Form&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on July 10, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Near The End]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/near-the-end" />
  <id>/near-the-end</id>
  <published>2013-07-08T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-07-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-projects&quot;&gt;Final Projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today some people decided that it would make more sense to continue working on their final projects. Some of these apps that I have seen are really really good. Quite impressive if you ask me. However in my case I decided that I would like to move on and work on a different app. GoodReads is cute but I have been thiking for a long time about a particular app that I think might be good to be looking at. The app that I decided to work on is a rentform app that I think is going to help people collect the forms and help budding land lords collect forms for a particular listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core functionality of this app is going to be the collecting of a form. Simple enough, but this thing is going to be very freaking difficult because there are going to be so many different parts of the form and that they are split up between the different parts of the whole application. There are personal references, employment history, emergency contacts, rent history, and personal information. I am going to spend some time and think about how this should be executed. My thinking right now is to split this up into a whole bunch of different models that are going to be submitted together as a single thing.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/near-the-end&quot;&gt;Near The End&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on July 08, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tightening Up]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/tightening-up" />
  <id>/tightening-up</id>
  <published>2013-07-05T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-07-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-projects&quot;&gt;Final Projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s chronicle, Jonathan spends time cleaning up and tightening the screws on PerfectPerusals. I am pretty satisified with much of what was done but I still think that there are a few flaws here and there that would require some research to competently address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main issue regards how I want to implement the Friend Feed. The way I am doing it right now is to have a number of disparate objects which the back end collects and pukes out at the client. I then wrote client side code that would let the browser interpret all that and put it together in a simple organized way. To me this seemed like a pretty hackish way but for just displaying the friend feed it worked. Can’t really complain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, then came the real issue. I realized relatively later that people can comment not only on Reviews but also shelvings of books and adding of friends. What the heck? I have never seen this sort of functionality before. Does this make sense at all? Well it is there so I have to implement it. Now the way I could probably do it is just to create separate “comment” objects. That would be a dangerous way to do it and I was not excited about that. The other way is to use inheritance, namely multi table inheritance, which is something that is going to be pretty cool. The parent class would have its own table but not only that there would be children and those children have their own tables. It is awesome, but it is not standard and though it is too late to use it for PP, I would think that it would be nice to try it for my next project.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tightening-up&quot;&gt;Tightening Up&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on July 05, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[More Things]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/more-things" />
  <id>/more-things</id>
  <published>2013-07-04T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-07-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-perfect-perusals-not-this-blog&quot;&gt;Creating Perfect Perusals (Not this blog)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first half of my two final projects, I decided to create a clone of GoodReads, which is a service that I greatly enjoy and like using. It is indeed quite of the most used products out there on the web. I use it more than Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The part that I felt was more like cheating was that GoodReads is not all that much of a single page app. It is in fact feels much more like something that almost entirely serves up its pages through Rails and has little if any JavaScript to do heavy client side stuff other than pop ups and scrolldowns. I wondered if a straightforward clone of GoodReads would be enough to challenge myself and create a product that would be something that be a great learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PerfectPerusals is something different. It is still heavy on the Rails stuff. It is not something ridiculous like Trello. This is in accordance to my interest and better comfort with Rails than Javascript. It is going to use Rails to serve up a lot of pages but from time to time I am going to use a dollop of Backbone in order to update and keep the server going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most challenging part of the entire project has been trying to figure out a right way to do these things that would make things easy for the future features that I want to build and implement in the future. I look at the finished GR product and I marvel at all these features. I end up thinking real hard about a simple easy way to get all of these into PerfectPerusals, like as if there is one single path that would just gracefully ice skate in between these Scyllas and Charybidses. I doubt that there is ever one such in the world. You can only look ahead ever so many steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not looking to implement every one of GR’s features. In this demo I am looking to focus on a few:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User profile pages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Author profile pages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Signup and Sign in&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Book profile pages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Book shelves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reviews of Books&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Comments on Reviews of Books&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Friending (maybe)
I started the project on Sunday and so far I have made encouraging progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User and Author profile pages were implemented with a single model User. I created a number of different filters in the User Controller that would look at whether or not a user had published any books, provided an email, and as such would then render the right page. I spent a lot of time getting the logic right and making sure that at least the right pages would show up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signup and Signin were done without BCrypt, which I do think is a flaw but could be easily remedied. It had been some time since I had done something like this so I had forgotten a few things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had made it so that people could embed their book reviews right into the profile page. It would also show the rest of the community’s reviews. This embedding of the book review form page was done with a relatively simple data-success helper from Rails. I felt like this would do a good job of simply posting the review to the database and appending it to all the other reviews listed in the page. However, I felt that this was a little cheating and would not give a lot of headroom for future expansion of the product going forward. For some of the other features I wanted to get more detailed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the comments under a review, I went ahead and created a full on Backbone app that had its own particular set of routes and views that activated only if you hit the Show Review page. It lets you add comments onto the page and does something kind of like what the AJAX call did with the Add Review page on the Show Book page however I feel that the Backbone implementation could handle a lot more meat on its bones if I wish it to have in the future. This is probably going to be case as I go and implement Friending and friend commenting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Book shelves is challenging and I am working on this right now as we speak. We will talk more about it tomorrow as it is going to be the thing I hit head on!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/more-things&quot;&gt;More Things&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on July 04, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Pp]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/creating-pp" />
  <id>/creating-pp</id>
  <published>2013-07-03T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-07-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-projects&quot;&gt;Final Projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I spent more time on building up more features of PerfectPerusals, with the significant feature being the central API that would serve as the data consumption for the other parts of the application. It would presumably be the heart of a proposed iPhone or Android app and if I had the time and energy for it then I would be able to go write that too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal for today that I set yesterday was to build on the friending infrastructure that I set up yesterday in like ten minutes and create a full friend feed that would give someone access to a stream of events that a person’s entire set of friends have performed in the past two or three weeks. I had thought deeply about this throughout my morning run and shower. When I started the system I had created a number of model objects that would be separated throughout the system. My concern was that there was no relations between any of the model objects and if I should go and create a friend feed out of it then I would have to 1) Somehow gather them all together under one unified umbrella and like the Ring of Power unite them and 2) somehow create a single front end that would be able to go and consume all that varying data. Now looking back on it, it might have made more sense to be able to go and create a single Rails model Object that all the others - taggings, friendings, reviews and comments - and such would inherit from: Event. This event would then be easily gathered and exported. Of course the grass is always greener on the other side. Who knows what other problems that I could have came across then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The center point of everything that I was working on was the introduction of RABL, which is something that I had seen before scattered throughout the CareDox site but never really figured out. I was wrestling the alligator of as_json when I asked Paul for some help. He simply said that I should use RABL instead to export all that data. I decided that this would be a good idea and then for the next four hours spent them wrestling with RABL and trying to make it such that it would capably export all the data in a format that would be consumed by the front end Backbone that I set up on the dashboard home page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge with RABL is implementing all the logic that would be able to go and smooth out all the data that is getting thrown at it. I created some lmabda if statements that would be able to parse out the different data points. Thank Goodness this is Ruby and I could query the data structure for its class name. If this was on the Client side then it would all be called “Object” and then I would have to had to create something to work around that. Then after that the challenge was making it so that the data could be easily accessible and that the relevant data points are all available. For example, I wanted the API to be able to say that a Review was written by a certain writer. I had Rails export not only the Review object but also the associated writer “Reviewer”. But then since the Reviewer on the actual Review object is just a number then I also modified the RABL to query and export the name. Then the client side would have very easy access to all the data that it needs to have. The RABL became all the unified data points that I need. With a good API, things became must easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I Need to Remember&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After adding new searchable blocks, remember to run “rake sunspot:reindex” so that it will go through the database and reindex stuff. I spent like 35 minutes in the morning working on this as I fiddled with SunSpot throughout the entire part of the morning while munching on a bucket of fried chicken.
What I want to Work On Friday:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Complete following (if possible)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Friend messages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Friend recommendations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More stats?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/creating-pp&quot;&gt;Creating Pp&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on July 03, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deploying Pp]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/deploying-pp" />
  <id>/deploying-pp</id>
  <published>2013-07-02T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-07-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-projects&quot;&gt;Final Projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I spent more time on building up more features of PerfectPerusals, with the significant feature being the central API that would serve as the data consumption for the other parts of the application. It would presumably be the heart of a proposed iPhone or Android app and if I had the time and energy for it then I would be able to go write that too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal for today that I set yesterday was to build on the friending infrastructure that I set up yesterday in like ten minutes and create a full friend feed that would give someone access to a stream of events that a person’s entire set of friends have performed in the past two or three weeks. I had thought deeply about this throughout my morning run and shower. When I started the system I had created a number of model objects that would be separated throughout the system. My concern was that there was no relations between any of the model objects and if I should go and create a friend feed out of it then I would have to 1) Somehow gather them all together under one unified umbrella and like the Ring of Power unite them and 2) somehow create a single front end that would be able to go and consume all that varying data. Now looking back on it, it might have made more sense to be able to go and create a single Rails model Object that all the others - taggings, friendings, reviews and comments - and such would inherit from: Event. This event would then be easily gathered and exported. Of course the grass is always greener on the other side. Who knows what other problems that I could have came across then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The center point of everything that I was working on was the introduction of RABL, which is something that I had seen before scattered throughout the CareDox site but never really figured out. I was wrestling the alligator of as_json when I asked Paul for some help. He simply said that I should use RABL instead to export all that data. I decided that this would be a good idea and then for the next four hours spent them wrestling with RABL and trying to make it such that it would capably export all the data in a format that would be consumed by the front end Backbone that I set up on the dashboard home page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge with RABL is implementing all the logic that would be able to go and smooth out all the data that is getting thrown at it. I created some lmabda if statements that would be able to parse out the different data points. Thank Goodness this is Ruby and I could query the data structure for its class name. If this was on the Client side then it would all be called “Object” and then I would have to had to create something to work around that. Then after that the challenge was making it so that the data could be easily accessible and that the relevant data points are all available. For example, I wanted the API to be able to say that a Review was written by a certain writer. I had Rails export not only the Review object but also the associated writer “Reviewer”. But then since the Reviewer on the actual Review object is just a number then I also modified the RABL to query and export the name. Then the client side would have very easy access to all the data that it needs to have. The RABL became all the unified data points that I need. With a good API, things became must easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I Need to Remember&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After adding new searchable blocks, remember to run “rake sunspot:reindex” so that it will go through the database and reindex stuff. I spent like 35 minutes in the morning working on this as I fiddled with SunSpot throughout the entire part of the morning while munching on a bucket of fried chicken.
What I want to Work On Friday:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Complete following (if possible)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Friend messages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Friend recommendations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More stats?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/deploying-pp&quot;&gt;Deploying Pp&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on July 02, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Pp]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/creating-pp" />
  <id>/creating-pp</id>
  <published>2013-07-01T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-07-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;final-projects&quot;&gt;Final Projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I spent more time on building up more features of PerfectPerusals, with the significant feature being the central API that would serve as the data consumption for the other parts of the application. It would presumably be the heart of a proposed iPhone or Android app and if I had the time and energy for it then I would be able to go write that too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal for today that I set yesterday was to build on the friending infrastructure that I set up yesterday in like ten minutes and create a full friend feed that would give someone access to a stream of events that a person’s entire set of friends have performed in the past two or three weeks. I had thought deeply about this throughout my morning run and shower. When I started the system I had created a number of model objects that would be separated throughout the system. My concern was that there was no relations between any of the model objects and if I should go and create a friend feed out of it then I would have to 1) Somehow gather them all together under one unified umbrella and like the Ring of Power unite them and 2) somehow create a single front end that would be able to go and consume all that varying data. Now looking back on it, it might have made more sense to be able to go and create a single Rails model Object that all the others - taggings, friendings, reviews and comments - and such would inherit from: Event. This event would then be easily gathered and exported. Of course the grass is always greener on the other side. Who knows what other problems that I could have came across then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The center point of everything that I was working on was the introduction of RABL, which is something that I had seen before scattered throughout the CareDox site but never really figured out. I was wrestling the alligator of as_json when I asked Paul for some help. He simply said that I should use RABL instead to export all that data. I decided that this would be a good idea and then for the next four hours spent them wrestling with RABL and trying to make it such that it would capably export all the data in a format that would be consumed by the front end Backbone that I set up on the dashboard home page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge with RABL is implementing all the logic that would be able to go and smooth out all the data that is getting thrown at it. I created some lmabda if statements that would be able to parse out the different data points. Thank Goodness this is Ruby and I could query the data structure for its class name. If this was on the Client side then it would all be called “Object” and then I would have to had to create something to work around that. Then after that the challenge was making it so that the data could be easily accessible and that the relevant data points are all available. For example, I wanted the API to be able to say that a Review was written by a certain writer. I had Rails export not only the Review object but also the associated writer “Reviewer”. But then since the Reviewer on the actual Review object is just a number then I also modified the RABL to query and export the name. Then the client side would have very easy access to all the data that it needs to have. The RABL became all the unified data points that I need. With a good API, things became must easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I Need to Remember&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After adding new searchable blocks, remember to run “rake sunspot:reindex” so that it will go through the database and reindex stuff. I spent like 35 minutes in the morning working on this as I fiddled with SunSpot throughout the entire part of the morning while munching on a bucket of fried chicken.
What I want to Work On Friday:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Complete following (if possible)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Friend messages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Friend recommendations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More stats?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/creating-pp&quot;&gt;Creating Pp&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on July 01, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discussion]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/discussion" />
  <id>/discussion</id>
  <published>2013-06-28T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2013-06-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;talking-with-ned&quot;&gt;Talking with Ned&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we spent the morning in lecture as Ned talked to us about the ins and outs of finding work in the tech industry. It was needless to say very much of the type of conversation I would expect to hear from someone like Ned: There was a ruthlessless and calculating systematic-ness in all of it mixed in with his own little version of bizarrely encouraging pep talk. He told us that we undervalued ourselves and our skills. His words are strangely uplifting though I am not so sure how much they will be when we start on this crushing path of rejection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project that we were to build is a clone of Gist, which is something that I am not particularly familiar with. The thing that was challenging about this project was not that it was built in Backbone on Rails, of which the big picture I am pretty comfortable with, but it is about the little details of the project. Little things that made me greatly appreciate the job that Paul has when he decides on whether or not to create particular parts of the product. I am still working at it as we speak and hope to get more done when I get home tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/discussion&quot;&gt;Discussion&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on June 28, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>