<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Perfect Perusals</title>
<subtitle type="text">A Website.</subtitle>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io" />
<updated>2016-05-06T03:34:37-07:00</updated>
<id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/</id>
<author>
  <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
  <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/</uri>
  <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jumbled Thoughts on Tech in China]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/jumbled-thoughts-on-tech-in-china" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/jumbled-thoughts-on-tech-in-china</id>
  <published>2016-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2016-05-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am thinking about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theinformation.com/china-a-country-full-of-ubers&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;(Paywalled) today. Whilst in Shanghai and Hong Kong I was able to talk to a few friends who work in the country’s growing tech industry. It’s massive and growing quickly, but while cash burn and revenue/profitability has been the main talk across the seas in Silicon Valley, it has not really started shaking out in China. I wish I were able to say that it will, but I am loathe to make predictions. I am sitting in a coffee shop hyped up on caffeine, so I thought to write something down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Big Tech Companies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big tech companies in China play the proxy war game in a way that I don’t really see US tech companies doing. Google and Microsoft might tangle with each other in getting clients, but for the most part their interactions are mostly characterized &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2015/09/google-and-microsoft-end-all-patent-litigation/&quot;&gt;as one of cooperation&lt;/a&gt;. But the big Chinese companies (they are Alibaba, Tencent and Baidu) go after each other in such ways that would make &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sun_Tzu&quot;&gt;Sun Tzu&lt;/a&gt; proud. Most of it is between Alibaba and Tencent. When the two of them make an investment, the intent is usually:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Shore up their main moneymaker from attack (Alibaba’s is ecommerce - Taobao, Tencent is messaging - WeChat)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Attack their opponent’s main moneymaker (Tencent taking 15% ownership share in JD, the second biggest e-commerce site after Alibaba’s Taobao // Alibaba buying 18% of Sina Weibo, which is kind of like the Twitter of the Chinese internet)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fight a third enemy muscling onto their turf (Alibaba + Tencent joining forces to fight Uber)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Carve out their own space out of new, relatively untouched turf - Alibaba + Tencent making digital entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder why this is the case - why American companies aren’t so outright going after each other. It might be because there is so much employee cross-pollination (you don’t want to burn bridges). Apple and Google might be rivals but they’re also really close by to each other. It is easy for employees of the two companies to meet up and talk face to face. Alibaba and Tencent are in Zhenjiang and Shenzhen, 800 miles away from each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chinese Business Models Feel Familiar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to say that all business models have to be different from each other - it is pretty rare to come across a company with a “whoa, that’s smart” business model (Uber and Zenefits come to mind). That being said, after checking out Angelist, I felt like a vast majority of the startups I came across could be classified into buckets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Moving something from one place to another” - Taxis/Trucks and such&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Connecting people with money to people with knowledge” - expert networks and such&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an American I feel a bit puzzled. Why are there so many of these types of businesses? On one level, I can see the demand:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Moving things”: China is a location with crowded roads and straining infrastructure. People will pay for a private solution to their logistics issue (and there is the spectre of Alibaba, the major ecommerce player funding everything related to logistics)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Expert networks”: I guess this is because a lot of business in China itself is done through experts and introductions. People learn about things from smarter others, and thus sprouted a business model around making those connections? Maybe this cultural facet is why we see a lot more of these businesses in China than in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, why do you need so many of these companies around? Are these fundamentally very regional businesses - meaning that they hard to scale on a global scale?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that Chinese companies are famous for is copying. They copy their American counterparts and they copy each other too, and that leads to conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Capitalist Thunderdome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had read a bit about the “go for growth” attitude that Chinese startups but I never really noticed it until recently. I feel like there is just &lt;strong&gt;something&lt;/strong&gt; about China’s startup ecosystem. Something that makes it the most ruthless capitalist thunderdome on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example. Baidu is a rich company with Google like margins. Their core search product is terrible (I had to use it in China) but because it is protected from competition it mints money the same way Google does. I remember reading a hedge fund thesis recommending an investment in Baidu because the company has amazing margins (~60% or something like that). The thesis that was pitched to me was that once the company “finishes investing” and cuts costs then the company’s true profits emerge and the bottom line would soar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, those investments - about $3.2 billion up front with another &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.investors.com/news/technology/baidu-to-feed-500-million-to-takeout-delivery/&quot;&gt;$500 million coming&lt;/a&gt; - are going into a food delivery product called Baidu Takeout. Many times they give you coupons so that every time you buy something from Baidu Takeout, it actually costs less than how it would cost if you went to the actual store. I suppose that Baidu would love to charge more for this but there are so many startups out there doing this that they would lose traction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder what it is about China that makes its business battles so ruthless. It can’t just only be that the Chinese people are the super ultra holy-smokes competitive (are they the most competitive people on the planet? I am not sure), or that they are totally okay with breaking the beer bottle and diving head first into the bar fight (metaphorically of course) or that their government doesn’t do a good job of being a referee, defusing the battles before they get too intense, or that each of the startups have more money than God. It’s all of that together. Jesus it all comes together and BOOM. No wonder Uber &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/article/uber-china-idUSKCN0VR1M9&quot;&gt;is losing a&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theinformation.com/inside-ubers-mission-impossible-in-china&quot;&gt;billion dollars a year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where’s All This Money Coming From?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of UberChina. As I read this I am hearing of news that Didi Kuaidi, a ride hailing company that is in the lead in Uber, has just &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-05-06/uber-china-rival-said-close-to-raising-2-billion-in-new-funding&quot;&gt;raised $2B&lt;/a&gt;. I think this has been something I have noticed a whole lot more recently - just how much money is in China. Like sheer cash, it subsidizes everything and even leaks out of the country, where it buys up everything and anything. The government has money from its massive sovereign wealth funds (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_foreign-exchange_reserves&quot;&gt;$3.2 trillion&lt;/a&gt; last time I checked). Its people has bunches of money from their savings (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2015-05-01/chinese-consumers-cling-to-saving-suppressing-spending&quot;&gt;30% of their disposable income&lt;/a&gt;). Its companies (especially its insurance companies) has treeloads of money (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/fefee172-9e64-11e5-bfed-a24713ecdd4f.html&quot;&gt;$349 billion in premiums annually and $1.85 trillion in total&lt;/a&gt; in insurance premiums that have to be invested). And then there’s the Chinese shadow banking system, that weirdass tangle of alternative investment products and who knows how much money’s sloshing around in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China always had boatloads of money, but it has seemed lately that all that money has taken the extra effort to hit the rest of the world. It’s no longer bidding up things like oil and commodities (funding despots like Hugo Chavez) - it appears to be hitting companies (anybody remember &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/03/23/business/dealbook/the-unsettling-acquisitiveness-of-a-chinese-insurer-in-the-us.html&quot;&gt;An Bang&lt;/a&gt;?) and especially &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/gadfly/articles/2016-03-23/german-property-is-booming-as-shortage-and-low-rates-fuel-demand&quot;&gt;real estate&lt;/a&gt;. It is like a massive money cannon wielded by their government, and they point it at things and suddenly prices go up for everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not sure if this is a good thing - it reminds me of the Japanese real estate bubble, them buying Pebble Beach and Rockefeller center. But China has an unfree government that seems capable of doing utterly insane things - like when they forced companies to buy Chinese stocks to prevent a market crash. They have 1.3 billion people in the world and more money than God. A China like this has never happened before, and I wonder what that means for the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/jumbled-thoughts-on-tech-in-china&quot;&gt;Jumbled Thoughts on Tech in China&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on May 06, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things I Think I Think About Japan]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/things-i-think-about-japan" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/things-i-think-about-japan</id>
  <published>2016-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2016-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It might be quite played out by now, the trip to Japan and the resultant travel post about the country’s stunning beauty and wonderment. However, just because it is not a cliche does not mean it isn’t true. I have hardly seen before a more befuddling, beautiful country in my life. In Japan, we get everything that we are promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first time that I am traveling with a friend, my roommate Adam, who learned a smattering of Japanese for this trip. In the weeks leading up to this trip, the two of us hashed out what exactly we would see as well as the restaurants that would be on our “acceptable” list. Turns out we hit every landmark we came out to see and almost every restaurant we planned to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing this a few days after the trip has ended, with a few days to think about what happened, what I enjoyed, and what has really stuck with me once we deboarded from the plane. Here are a few thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;things-i-think-i-think-about-japan&quot;&gt;Things I Think I Think About Japan&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phones are Ubiquitous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had read on Wikipedia that Japan is famous for still being one of the most newspaper-heavy countries in the world. The analyses had found that in an age where newspapers around the world are declining into irrelevancy, paper newspapers in Japan remain heavily used. Wikipedia in fact still ranks Japanese newspapers &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_newspapers_in_the_world_by_circulation&quot;&gt;the first, second, and third&lt;/a&gt; most heavily circulated in the world. In other words, I expected a lot more newspapers than I actually got. I only saw a person purchase a newspaper at a stand once or twice my entire time there, and almost always by an older person (over 60).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are people doing with the extra time in subways or waiting in line? They are on their phones. I snuck at their screens. Sometimes they are playing games (especially if it is an older phone, like the flip phone type) or sometimes they are on &lt;a href=&quot;http://linecorp.com/en/&quot;&gt;Line&lt;/a&gt; (the dominant chat app in the country) or they are on Twitter (which is interesting especially to me. Twitter is super popular in Japan still).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trains are very Nice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay this is cheating. Every transportation system in Asia is ridiculously nice, comprehensive, and are never late. But I think Japan is the great grandaddy of them all and it super impresses with the immensity of its technical proficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/jp-trains.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Japan love them some trains&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is about $50 to ride the Shinkansen but I highly recommend it. It has more leg room than any plane. The seats are comfortable (and recline without bothering the guy behind you!) and the train hurls forward with an unbelievable speed that you barely notice from the inside. I am not sure how fast this thing goes, but it’s a surreal experience. You don’t even feel like you’re going that fast. I have encountered Shinkansens before in Taiwan, but seeing them in Japan is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Service Workers are Dedicated&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite part of the Shinkansen riding experience is the service workers. Every so often they come in with a little cart of goods that you might or might not want. But I love the little touches that just seem quintessentially Japanese. For example, when they are about to exit the car they step out of the car and then from outside the door they turn around and bow at you. They do this even if nobody is looking. I love this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is interesting that no matter what these workers are doing in Japan, they are doing it with dedication and attention to detail. I have heard this from other people, but it seems like Japanese are the hardest workers in the world. But it is more than just how hard they work at their task, but that they do it regardless of what the task is. Doesn’t matter if they are scrubbing floors, serving you your dinner, or counting the change for your ice cream at the counter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is something about my interaction with these people that bothers me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why are all the service workers women?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I almost hardly ever saw men working the cashiers or cleaning or stuff like that. It was almost always women. Pretty much the only time I was served by a man was when I bought mochi (which are delicious by the way. Go eat them), or bought something from the likely owner of the shop. In almost every other circumstance, if it was a cashier in a 7-11 or taking my order at a Yoshinoya, it was likely to be a woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not sure what to make of this observation. Is it such that men traditionally used to fill these roles eventually ascended to better roles and the women are filling in? Are women perhaps entering the job market, finding themselves disadvantage in relations to men and as a result having to settle? Are they making enough money in their work to provide for their families? Are they more often than not the sole provider?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Japan really focuses on ambiance music&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed this while I was visiting the amazing Osaka aquarium (the first aquarium in the world to feature whale sharks) but Japan really really likes to play ambiance music. The sort of music that you notice when you are in the elevator. It isn’t really recognizable as anything other than just ambiance music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/jp-whale-sharks.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Never gonna pass up a chance to share WHALE SHARKS&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of it is pretty unassuming and I presumed that there is some universal Pandora station that they are playing off of, but I managed to nab a Shazam while I was in the Kyoto Tower, and found that the the album’s name is “Kyoto Ambiance” (by Masafumi Komatsu) and the album cover is a photo of the Kyoto Tower itself. In other words, they are so hard core about their music that they went ahead and commissioned the pieces themselves, clearly with the song’s intent in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I should have anticipated this because …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maybe it is because the businesses really care about how you FEEL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/jp-wall.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thinking of including this in my post about vending machines but I figured that people wouldn’t really care. But this is a consistent pattern that I have noticed about Japanese advertising. They really really care about how you feel and about encouraging a feeling of “peace” and “reflection” in your time with them. They are also quite explicit about this intent. They pledge it on their adverts: “Don’t worry about your daily troubles because we are going to make them go away. Please relax with us.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would leave me feeling very tempted except for this …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everyone (ABC) Always Be Closing in Japan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beware your wallet while you are in Japan. Not because it might be liable to be pick pocketed, but because every little business wants your money. Everyone is selling something on the street in Japan from tiny stands with an old lady manning them or a huge bill board on the biggest, most famous crossing in the world to even the humble vending machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/jp-crossing.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their favorite tactic is to put someone on the street, shouting at the top of their lungs to go buy their product. This seems to be a bit outdated (especially since the Chinese here in China employ loudspeakers and recorded voices) but if it works for them I guess. There are many things done in Japan just because it’s been done that way for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I worry about the Japanese&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the Japanese work too hard. It is apparent to me in the fact that the men are almost never present during the day. I never see them with their wives. I only see them on their commute and at dinners late at night while they are drinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see them frequenting mall shops downstairs in the basement, huge rooms with food for sale which is kind of like a food court in the US except the food is always refrigerated because it is expected that the people not eat there but they should take it back with them home to heat up. This is expected because it is not good to eat there alone, I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I had a Japanese friend to speak to these things, but alas I was never able to successfully interact with them. They never spoke enough English to be able to and I didn’t know a lick of Japanese (they also seemed to me a bit standoffish in public interaction …). My new mission if I return to Japan - make a friend there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16 days. Four cities. 200 miles walked. Several dozen landmarks visited. Staying nearly 16 continuous days with someone can cause any two people extreme strain, but the two of us made it through. Japan has been beautiful, and while I am not planning to return any time soon, I hope that it would not be the last time in my life I would see its beauty in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/jp-me-adam.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;No regrets. Japan I hope to see you again.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/things-i-think-about-japan&quot;&gt;Things I Think I Think About Japan&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on May 01, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Direct Response Principles Demonstrated in Japanese Vending Machines]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/direct-response-principles-demonstrated-in-japanese-vending-machines" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/direct-response-principles-demonstrated-in-japanese-vending-machines</id>
  <published>2016-04-26T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2016-04-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;During a recent vacation to Japan, I could not help but notice the polite but fierce competitiveness of Japanese capitalism. Being a business in Japan is tough and it is not just about their labor laws - every shop and store shouts from the top of its lungs. Shops hire street shouters (usually women) to declare their wares and hand out flyers. There are billboards and posters everywhere - on the walls, subways, and buildings too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unbeknownst to most visitors, the battle is not only between men in shops but also the unmanned and automated: Vending machines. Japanese vending machines are myriad in almost every city block - hawking a variety of drinks ranging from water to green tea to coffee (black, latte, you name it, buddy) to even canned soups. Prices range from ¥100 to ¥160.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/vd-0.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The battle is joined!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much of these drink selections overlap with each other and even competing machines tend to oligopolistic collude on price within a particular block (those dastards!). So all that is left is basically location and - this is where I come in - “eye catchiness”. Namely, their direct response chops. For two years, I ran digital advertisements on Facebook for True&amp;amp;Co, a specialty lingerie company. Much of these advertisements were direct response advertisements, meaning that their intent was to motivate the user to do something. For True&amp;amp;Co, that motivation was to make the user sign up with our site and (preferably) make a first purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I will examine a number of Japanese vending machines (photographed in various states of hurry on the street) and note the direct response principles their creators invoked (or not) to acquire business. I believe that many of these principles are potentially applicable to your own advertising creative. We can talk about that too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So without (much) more ado, let’s dive in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;discussing-the-vending-machine-ad-unit&quot;&gt;Discussing The Vending Machine Ad Unit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Japanese vending machines are structured pretty much the same way (in other words, they feature a standardized ad unit).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/vd-1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Large rectangular billboard ad unit under the drink window to the left or right of the payment module. This is pretty much the core ad unit - all machines have this one, which can be digital at times (useful when playing video). I shall refer to this unit as the “&lt;strong&gt;core unit&lt;/strong&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Shorter, wider rectangular billboard unit positioned above the drink window. This one is also very common, but not universally so. It often rises above the height of the machine proper, being made of cardboard. I shall refer to this unit as the “&lt;strong&gt;header unit&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other machines add on the frills, taking away their clean look and making them look more like the Yahoo! landing page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Banners on the left or right of the drink window. When used, it shall be referred to as the “&lt;strong&gt;left or right skyscraper unit&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Banners at the very bottom of the machine, under the drink deposit tray. When used, I shall name this the “&lt;strong&gt;footer tray unit&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be frank, machines that feature the secondary expanded ad units tend to be the newer ones but make up a small percentage of the overall vending machine population as far as I can tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;call-out-your-price&quot;&gt;Call Out Your Price&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laughing at this tactic will leave you stranded on the high road as your competitors rush away with your customers! Despite me saying earlier that physically adjacent machines collude on price, many still call out their low prices on their core units, especially if that price hits a psychological mark like ¥100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/vd-2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note this one, which was photographed in Taito. While most of the machines I came across had their advert premises in Japanese, this one made its point pretty clear: With us, you can get coffee for ¥100. The message is made boldly clear in primary (nearly offensive) colors: Red on yellow. The number is the main feature of the core unit, big and noticeable. The secondary message is in English and plastered in the top left and bottom right (the start and end of where Westerns read text)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;call-out-your-brand--hedge-on-price&quot;&gt;Call Out Your Brand + Hedge on Price&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/vd-3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above machine, “Wonda”, was photographed in Taito as well. It demonstrates a more brand friendly approach to calling out price. The creators chose to fill its core unit with a brand name, that of a coffee brand called Wonda. To maximize the eye catchiness of the ad unit, the background is made a dark red and the text is emphasized by being boxed in by a white line. The subtitle of the logo has the brand’s slogan: “Wonderful Coffee”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly a branding message. The subtitle is too small to be readable by most passersby so the machine is relying heavily on the Wonda name to catch attention (I’m not sure how big of a brand it is in Japan).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However even with this branding message, the machine’s makers hedged their bets by calling out price in the footer tray ad unit: 100¥ again! It is clearly reaching for that psychological barrier, even if only a few of the drinks actually hit that price target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-attention-with-a-famous-person&quot;&gt;Get Attention With a Famous Person&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These Suntory Boss vending machines are everywhere in Japan, but I regret to inform you that the photos I have of them are rather limited. You might not be able to see it too easily but the image in the core unit is of a Japanese man (not sure who he is?) as well as that of the Western actor Tommy Lee Jones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/vd-4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two faces are well placed at the center of the ad unit and look out at you. Eye contact is better than no eye contact for most direct response image creative. They should be looking at the camera so to better captivate a customer’s attention once caught.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the Suntory Boss machines also feature the Jones + Japanese actor image creative on its header ad units. Others have just the Suntory Boss name emblazoned across its headers (see below). However with very few exceptions the core ad units are featured, which tells me it probably works well for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/vd-7.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suntory is well known for using famous names in its advertising (it is one of the first to pioneer the tactic). But to be honest, this tactic is beyond most regular advertisers. How often can we use a famous person’s endorsement to get people’s attention? Most other machines took the tactic of showing an attractive person’s face (see below for a standard example, using a guy and a girl to cover all bases!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;calling-out-novelty&quot;&gt;Calling Out Novelty&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/vd-5.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The human mind is always on the lookout for the next new thing and some of our most successful direct response messaging either called out the novelty of a new item, made note of some “growing” or “impending” trend, or proclaimed of some breakthrough innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This vending machine takes the tact of just telling people that it has new drinks, with emphasis on the NEW. While I am not the biggest fan of the color and font presentation of the word “NEW” on the core ad unit, it does the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the tray ad unit, I enjoyed the image effect of having the model thrusting the drink in your face. Nice action feel without actually having the action performed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-call-outs&quot;&gt;Design Call Outs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/vd-6.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This vending machine uses the same image creative unit from the tray unit in the previous example but that’s not why I am calling it out right now. The reason I like this machine so much is because its window has so many stickers on it that call out specific drinks. On the bottom right there is a red sticker that outlines something they want you to pay attention to. Same with the yellow stickers on the middle row to the left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our own digital advertising creative, we found that it helped a lot if we provided some visual cues that helped people understand what specifically we were selling them. Arrows are the best, but outlines tend to fit overall style principles much better (meaning the bosses like them better).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;expanding-the-canvas&quot;&gt;Expanding the Canvas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a common occurrence especially for the newer vending machines. Perhaps as advancements in printing came about which let people cut holes in their imagery for the trays and payment modules, advertisers can break out of the standard rectangular format and really go big on their messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/vd-8.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that Coca-Cola does this the most, using the extra real estate to tell us just how refreshing their drinks are, but they aren’t alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/vd-9.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love that the girl idols in question signed imagery of the vending machine itself! It is a bit too busy for my taste, but perhaps it works for the machine itself. It certainly catches the eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook is pretty strict on its ad image sizes so it is not an applicable principle for that format. At the same time, this reminds me a lot of the web page takeover ads that unsavory websites tend to have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/vd-10.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;This one is just haha.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might think that I am a bit crazy here but I think I really recognized a kindred spirit in these machines’ messaging and visual design. None of these machines were employed as ad units for other products like a movie or something as you might see on a subway support pillar. They are all dementedly focused on one thing: For you to buy from them and them only. Make no mistake, these machines are doing the same thing as your Clash of Clans ads are on Facebook - they’re doing direct response. And I admire that, their little passive battles out in the open of the Japanese streets.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/direct-response-principles-demonstrated-in-japanese-vending-machines&quot;&gt;Direct Response Principles Demonstrated in Japanese Vending Machines&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on April 26, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Throne: A Review]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/the-throne-review" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/the-throne-review</id>
  <published>2016-04-11T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2016-04-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Four or so months ago, I read in the Hollywood Reporter that South Korea had chosen the movie &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt4010918/fullcredits?ref_=tt_cl_sm#cast&quot;&gt;The Throne&lt;/a&gt; as its &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/oscars-south-korea-submits-throne-820021&quot;&gt;submission&lt;/a&gt; for the Oscar’s best Foreign Film of 2015. The summary greatly intrigued me because it focused on a tale I read a long time ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-historical-prince-sado&quot;&gt;The Historical Prince Sado&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crown_Prince_Sado&quot;&gt;historical records&lt;/a&gt; are relatively slim. The basic gist is that Crown Prince Sado was the favored prince of a long-reigning &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yeongjo_of_Joseon&quot;&gt;Korean king&lt;/a&gt;. Much like the Roman Emperor Caligula, he apparently started out intelligent and charming, but over time displayed deviant and sadistic behaviors. It was said that he was mentally ill, causing him to go into psychotic benders where he would murder many of the palace’s staff. Eventually the King could not tolerate these behaviors and realized that Sado had to be removed. However, a King executing his own son would scandalize and potentially destabilize the deeply Confucian country - communal punishment is a common policy. The King decided on an unusual punishment - he had Sado put into a rice crate with the lid nailed shut. The box was then left outside. Over the span of 7 days, Sado died from exposure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The historical records are rather slim - and do not go much into the details, but it allowed the movie much creative license as long as the main plot beats are met. The result is an amazing movie that touched me deeply. The movie took a lightly documented but infamous historical event and discovered a stunning tale about three generations of men. Such a story lets us see and feel for the living, breathing Crown Prince. But like a train on the tracks to its final destination, it is sad to know how this story will end before it even begins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story has a twisting time structure but it does not take long to figure out. It starts in media res with the sequence leading up to the major historical event - the Crown Prince, deeply troubled, emerges with a sword and marches into the King’s chambers - his father. How this is resolved it is not immediately shown, it cuts to the next morning in the palace Courtyard when the King orders the Crown Prince to commit suicide for the crime of attempting to murder the King. The Prince’s minders rush to his support and demand what is essentially a fair trial for the King’s attempted murder. The King waives these off and when it becomes clear that Sado will not commit suicide he is put into a large rice crate and left there in the palace courtyard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;father-and-son&quot;&gt;Father and Son&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is then that Sado’s son - the movie refers to him as the Sason - begs for his grandfather’s mercy on the behalf of Sado. He gets on his knees crying, promising that “whatever [his] father cannot do, [he] can do”. If “[Sado] cannot read books then [he] will read books”. The significance of this was made clear later. But the King is unmoved and as he hammers in the first nails, the movie cuts to a flashback. This structure repeats many times over the movie, with each face being the transition that moves backwards or forwards in time like as if it were being recounted by the character in question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sado as a young child is mischievous but obviously talented. His love for his father and desire to please him is clear. The King is at first pleased with his son but as time goes by notices that the Crown Prince is increasingly uninterested in his studies. The Prince falls asleep during Confucian tests (which consist of reciting memorized passages from books) and does not do well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was watching this, to me it seemed pretty clear that the Prince is a boy who doesn’t have a nose for books. He really wants to but he is more of an outside kind of kid. This creates tension between him and his father, who deeply believes in the adherence of Confucian principles when it comes to running the country. The King often proclaims that if the principles are violated then the country would collapse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-father-and-son-clash&quot;&gt;The Father and Son Clash&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The generational tension between the father who is disappointed in his son’s progress and the struggling son who feels that he is not given a fair chance is very clear. The two have very different perspectives on what it takes to be successful in life - and we as the audience are made sympathetic to those perspectives. The King came to power under contested circumstances - his brother died suspiciously - and believed that his success as a King came only through his moral adherence to the Confucian laws. He never really wanted to be a King and years later is all too aware of just how difficult it is. The next King had to meet his own exacting standards, and Sado could not keep up. As Sado enters his late teens and early twenties, the King declares his abdication (something he would do at least twice in the movie) but is convinced otherwise. Instead a middle agreement is worked out - Sado makes the general decisions and the King takes a step back but is in charge. What follows is a stunning scene where a few administrative missteps (bad beginner’s luck I would say) from Sado leads to an angered disavowal from the King, who started the scene placid, eyes closed, and patting his son’s arm lovingly and ended up in a fury. The country’s future is at stake and the job is hard, it is easy to understand why the King would fly off the collar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The King’s perspective is pretty good work by the movie but Sado’s is nothing short of stunning. The man makes a bad first impression in the movie, coming off as petulant, violent and slightly unstable - you kind of want to put him into the box. But in the movie’s flashbacks you see a man who deeply loves his father. I don’t think the movie ever portrays as him as being anything other than loyal to his father. He works unstintingly to earn his father’s approval and it says something about how good the actor is when you cannot sense a single iota of dishonesty in his deep prostrations before his father. When the King declares his will to abdicate the throne to Sado, the person most fervently asking for a nullification of the abdication is Sado. Sado does not appear to be very book smart, but his dedication is endearing. He stands prostrate before his father’s palace day and night, hoping that his father would change his mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the demons must as dictated by history must appear (he murders a palace official and spends days on end locked up in his room) you feel sympathetic for his plight. Or at least I did. Looking back on my own upbringing, I never felt like I had the devotion to earn my own father’s approval - which makes me especially weak for people who so desperately wanted it. For myself, I felt like I had always had it - my father loved me unconditionally - but at the same time I did well at school and was book smart. Perhaps if my father had been a football coach and wanted me to be good at football or some other sport (for which I still have two left feet), I would have felt differently. Did not wanting this from him make me a worser son, an undeserving son who has had too easy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-point-of-study&quot;&gt;The Point of Study&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something additional that I didn’t really see at the time as plainly until later but the movie made pointedly clear was the modern day criticism of Confucian principles as a way of education. Education is a big topic today and Korea (like other Asian countries) is famous for its brutally grinding, memory-based curriculum. Korean work culture is famous for literally working people to death doing tasks that really have no point. Education today is famous for teaching you things that you don’t really need to know today - things that a quick Google search can solve for you in seconds. The movie goes out of its way to take some very strong jabs at this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the irony of ironies (dramatic irony at least) that the Sason - Sado’s son and the King’s grandson - turns out to be everything in a son that the King wanted. The Sason even at a young age (just 10 when his father is killed) is fantastic at memorizing passages and understands the Confucian classics better than Sado ever can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it is that understanding of the classics that leads to one of the most insightful passages in the movie. Midway through the movie, Sado is in one of his psychotic breaks and conducts a revered ritual for his biological mother. The problem is that this ritual is reserved only for the reigning Queen, of which his biological mother is not. He does the bows in front of his mother and turns to see the Sason. He demands his son to do the bow too. The Sason knows that this is illegal but after consideration does the bow. Later on, the King asks the Sason why. It was against the literal letter of the Confucian law. The Sason replies that he did the bow because he realized that it was not about the letter of the law, but the human intention behind it - that Sado loves his mother very much and sees her as deserving the honors of a reigning queen. The King is stunned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grandson who did the demanded work the best ironically enough knows just how pointless it all is. The Sason learned at 10 what I did not start to learn until I was 25. It is the words of the movie speaking at us, and it follows on what I believe in and what I felt like I learned way later than I should have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;who-was-the-better-father&quot;&gt;Who Was The Better Father?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a wonderful sequence, the King quizzes his grandson on Confucianism in a scene that mirrors an earlier one in which he does the same for Sado. Sado fails miserably - skipping a passage - but the Sason passes with flying colors. In the next cut, Sado is speaking with his son, firing arrows at a range. Sado is incredulous, asking if he “really does like reading all that much”. You can see how Sado feels left out - his own father and son are essentially the same people and he is out there unwanted. Yet at the same time, Sado cannot dislike his child the same way the King dislikes him. I loved this scene - just the puzzlement in Sado’s eyes mixed in with the envy for his own son mixed in with a hint of fatherly pride and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the movie, Sado is dead and the King is elderly. He sits with the grown up Sason (now known as King &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeongjo_of_Joseon&quot;&gt;Jeongjo&lt;/a&gt;) and asks that Sado be forever forgotten. Such a memory only brings pain to the country. After the King’s death, the Sason becomes king himself and the first that comes to mind is his father locked in a crate, unable to respond to his desperate cries to come out. He immediately goes to pay his respects at his father’s grave, breaking his grandfather’s wishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking about this scene still brings tears to my eyes. The King might have been a great, long-reigning King - Wikipedia still has a rather favorable opinion of him - but to me Sado for all his failings and mental illness turned out to be the better father. He was a better father to his son because he gave his son something that the King could not give him, love and acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I type these words today, I am 28 years old - the same age at which my father had me. I don’t have children right now. Most of my friends presume that I won’t ever, but the truth is that I have never really thought about it. Sometimes I think about the sucky parts - being in a plane with one really helps bring that into focus. But sometimes a movie like this makes me think about the good parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all his temper and impatience, my father is an amazing father to me - selflessly generous, unusually accepting (for a Chinese dad at least), and endlessly loving. He taught me to become successful, and then paradoxically at the same time taught me to give away my success to the people I care for. And as I begin my fourth decade on this planet, it is starting to bother me to think that I could possibly live the rest of them out without really being able to be all that for a child of my own.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/the-throne-review&quot;&gt;The Throne: A Review&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on April 11, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Dirty Swift Curriculum]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/dirty-swift-curriculum" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/dirty-swift-curriculum</id>
  <published>2016-04-07T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2016-04-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Swift has been an amazing resource for people. It is a big improvement at least when it comes to readability over Objective-C. But for me the reality has been that my biggest challenge has not been tied to the language I am writing the app in but instead the various APIs that implement the assorted application behaviors people are familiar with on a day to day basis. Features and behaviors like swipe to delete, table views, and such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part, you can connect the behavior you want with the desired API relatively easily - either just through a guess (Tables = UITableView? Who would have thought it?) or a clever Google search. Others are not so obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been trying to write apps for 3 years now and throughout that time I have come across pains in the asses in implementing such and such feature. Whenever I came across a good resource that solved that pain in the ass, I made sure to bookmark it - because it is likely that I am going to come across that pain in the ass again and I don’t quite trust my memory to figure it out for me. Over time, my list of bookmarks have turned into an invaluable resource - a collection of great things that I can tap whenever I come across a problem I know I have solved before but don’t quite remember how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in this post, I have arranged my Swift curriculum list under a number of different desired features/processes/end goals. I might expand as time goes on (if that happens then I’ll update the date on this post) but right now these are the main concepts that my bookmarks are organized around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: This is all based on the assumption that you have some idea of Swift and also want to do all your interfaces programmatically - which is usually how I program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;overarching-navigation-app-structure&quot;&gt;Overarching Navigation App Structure&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://makeapppie.com/2014/09/09/swift-swift-using-tab-bar-controllers-in-swift/&quot;&gt;USING TAB BAR CONTROLLERS IN SWIFT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be hard to get started sometimes so this article gives you a spot to launch. Most apps are set up the same way: Tabs in tab bars that wrap individual UIViewcontrollers. This can be tough to set up programmatically so this is a way to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://makeapppie.com/2014/09/15/swift-swift-programmatic-navigation-view-controllers-in-swift/&quot;&gt;SWIFT SWIFT: PROGRAMMATIC NAVIGATION VIEW CONTROLLERS IN SWIFT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UINavigationControllers help people dig into details without losing their place. They are a core portion of any app. This article helped me set them up for success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/26033725/ios-how-do-i-swipe-between-views-using-swift&quot;&gt;SnapChat-like Swipe interface between ViewControllers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snapchat has a new way to navigate between ViewControllers that is not wrapped up in a tab. This is a theory on how to achieve it for your own app - if that’s what you are going for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/26033725/ios-how-do-i-swipe-between-views-using-swift&quot;&gt;iOS: How do I swipe between views using Swift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the soft-core version of the above set up, where you are still in the same UIViewcontroller but want to swipe between specific views. A few apps have this and this is a nice solution for replicating that behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;managing-data-json-serialization-passing-data-persistence-etc&quot;&gt;Managing Data (JSON, Serialization, Passing Data, Persistence, etc)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://roadfiresoftware.com/2016/02/debunking-the-myths-about-parsing-json-in-swift/&quot;&gt;Debunking the myths about parsing JSON in Swift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally use a library to help map data from JSON downloads to class objects, however if you want to do it without the help of a library then this was a great article for me. I like the part where it shows you a way to do it without using a bunch of if statements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raywenderlich.com/81615/introduction-to-realm&quot;&gt;Realm Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Realm is a nice database that I came across during my Googling. I have not really reviewed or worked with anything else. They have a nice API that is smooth and easy to understand. There are also some things they say about speed and performance but I have not really gotten the chance to test that. This is a great first article to get you up to speed with Realm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ioscreator.com/tutorials/use-settings-nsuserdefaults-ios8-swift&quot;&gt;Use Settings with NSUserDefaults in iOS8 with Swift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NSUserDefaults is a pain to deal with but you never really want to put User Default settings in your database right? This is a simple quick article to get you started. It helps me with things like, “Does this guy have the 2/3 point setting or the 1/2 point setting on?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thatthinginswift.com/completion-handlers/&quot;&gt;Completion Handlers in Swift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it embarrassing to say that I don’t know how to implement Completion Handlers in Swift? I had an idea of how it works from JavaScript but how it is done in Swift I like a lot more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/25759945/pass-data-when-dismiss-modal-viewcontroller-in-swift&quot;&gt;Pass data when dismiss modal viewController in swift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a little more subtle problem. I did not have a real idea of what I was looking for other than the particular behavior that I wanted. I wanted this to automatically pass information and data (in this case, a photo) from a dismissed viewcontroller to its parent controller. This one came up on Google on the 5th row down and introduced me (and now, you) to the concept of protocols. I had seen them before when dealing with UITableViews but this teaches me how to create my own. Exactly what I needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;understanding-and-building-with-asyncdisplaykit&quot;&gt;Understanding and Building With AsyncDisplayKit&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is one of the most popular libraries, a way to asynchronously generate user interfaces and display them. This allows for us to create data-rich applications without dropping frames and causing lag. It was tough to understand at first, but with the help of these articles, you can do it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lukeparham.com/blog/2015/3/23/asyncdisplaykit&quot;&gt;Intro to ASDK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great visual and easy to understand language. A good Way to step into the library with your tippy toes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-IPMNWqA638&quot;&gt;NSLondon Talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video was the way I first understood ASDK. Sometimes you just need someone to explain it to you in person. The person who did this lecture is an amazing teacher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raywenderlich.com/107310/asyncdisplaykit-tutorial-node-hierarchies&quot;&gt;AsyncDisplayKit Tutorial: Node Hierarchies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This takes you to the next step once you understand how ASDK works. This article helps you build your first UI elements and screens with AsyncDisplayKit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/AsyncDisplayKit/issues/709&quot;&gt;Layout nodes using ASLayoutSpec #709&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exchange can help you understand how to build interfaces using ASLayoutSpec, since ASDK does not support traditional AutoLayout. Once you get the hang of it, it is hard to go back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/facebook/AsyncDisplayKit/issues/718&quot;&gt;ASNetworkImageNode with unknown height don’t update ASCellNode’s height&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the way ASDK generates and renders and presents its images, sometimes images downloaded from the internet might not present themselves in the right way. This is because of its asynchronous nature. UI elements are rendered before the system knows the size of the downloaded image. As a result you have to do some refreshes and reloads. This code issue shows you how it is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;user-interface-and-animations&quot;&gt;User Interface and Animations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ioscreator.com/tutorials/swipe-table-view-cell-custom-actions-tutorial-ios8-swift&quot;&gt;TableViewCell Swipe for Custom Actions Tutorial in iOS8 with Swift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The swipe for actions action is famous for all apps. Seeing it on the standard iOS mail app, you cannot help but want to figure out how to do it for yourself. This is a page for learning how to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appcoda.com/ios-charts-api-tutorial/&quot;&gt;How to Use iOS Charts API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iOS Charts is a great Github library plugin that handles a lot of the complexity of presenting data. Charts are a thing you do not want to write from scratch. There is a lot to deal with - tick marks, drawing the lines, and such. All of it is ridiculously difficult. This webpage helps you use the library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://grokswift.com/custom-fonts/&quot;&gt;Custom Fonts in Swift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that SnapChat brought in a new font recently, Avenir I think. Fonts matter, and the ones that iOS brings to the table can get a bit dry at times. This web page taught me to bring in my own fonts to an app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shrikar.com/ios-8-custom-transitions-in-swift/&quot;&gt;Custom Transitions in Swift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The standard transition animation that you see when you push a new screen is very pretty but sometimes you just want something new. This webpage teaches you how to create and configure a new custom transition animation that looks slick, pretty, and really professional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://merowing.info/2015/12/details-matter---harnessing-the-power-of-coreanimation/&quot;&gt;Harnessing the Power of Core Animation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title of this page is great. Details matter. Having a great little animation would help other people love your app. This one teaches you how they managed to get the little bounces and hops in UI (like a little pop when people touch the textview of an app), the things that people won’t single out as being the thing that made them love it, but make them think, ‘hmm, this is pretty nice’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;other-things&quot;&gt;Other Things&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airpair.com/ios/posts/swift-storekit-in-app-purchases#5-how-to-configure-iap-in-apple-s-developer-portal-&quot;&gt;Definitive Guide to In-App Purchases in Swift, StoreKit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a little more advanced. I had read about a lot of libraries that help write the boilerplate code for setting up an in-app purchase selection but I wanted to write it myself. This helps me do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.objc.io/issues/5-ios7/getting-to-know-textkit/&quot;&gt;Getting to Know TextKit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of what I do on my iOS apps is read so naturally the apps that I want to write have a big reading and text component. Kind of like Instapaper and such but I never came across something that helped with that. This is a great starter to help read up on the components behind those apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.raywenderlich.com/114552/uistackview-tutorial-introducing-stack-views&quot;&gt;Introducing Stack Views&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a new addition to the iOS canon. I have not used it in a very meaningful context (did use it for a practice app in setting up the interface for some other type thing) but from what I hear it is fundamentally a port of an Android development component. You add subunits, give them some broad guidance on what to do, and they sort themselves accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I create an app, I have something in mind and try to create it in reality. At first I didn’t really think about proper ways of writing code, just doing whatever I can to just make it happen. That’s a bit slapdash but to me it is part of the learning process. You learn the fundamentals of creating an effect and then slowly work your way towards a more proper way to write code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I should have just taken a course or read a textbook - that is kind of the way that I am taking on data analysis and machine learning right now - but at the heart of it, I don’t really think I could have enjoyed it as much this way. Reading machine learning is fulfilling but more of a slog and I always have been a guy who wants to put his hands on things and start working. Doing it this way and building my curriculum this way has been way more goddamn fun. And in the end, that’s what it’s all about - fun.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/dirty-swift-curriculum&quot;&gt;A Dirty Swift Curriculum&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on April 07, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing CollegeScan]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/introducing-collegescan" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/introducing-collegescan</id>
  <published>2016-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</published>
  <updated>2016-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I am excited to introduce &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/collegescan-college-scorecard/id1087108329?mt=8&quot;&gt;collegeScan - a Client for the College Scorecard&lt;/a&gt;. This is my first published app since &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hakkerjobs-hackernews-client/id1028168255&quot;&gt;HakkerJobs&lt;/a&gt; and while it has been great to publish updates to those apps I am really happy about being able to launch a whole new app. I am excited to tell you more in this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/cs-icon.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-idea&quot;&gt;The Idea&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea came to me as I was playing around with the data.gov site. The first iteration of what would become collegeScan was some sort of elementary school tracker - a parent would be able to track the schools around their particular area. However what became clear was that the data for elementary schools was very fragmented. It is on a state by state basis and it is locked up in weird formats like tab delineated text files. To me, I realized that I would have to spend a lot of time working on just cleaning the data - and that felt to me not worth the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However while in the midst of the research, I came across the &lt;a href=&quot;https://collegescorecard.ed.gov/data/documentation/&quot;&gt;College Scorecard&lt;/a&gt;. Basically the government released about 20 years worth of data on colleges - the cost of them as well as their admissions data - with the goal of making the college selection process easier. Check out their &lt;a href=&quot;https://collegescorecard.ed.gov/assets/BetterInformationForBetterCollegeChoiceAndInstitutionalPerformance.pdf&quot;&gt;technical paper&lt;/a&gt; for the whole story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This information, just released in late 2015, seemed to me worth sharing with other people. I created a new project on xCode and rolled up my sleeves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-implementation&quot;&gt;The Implementation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;collegeScan is an evolution of the work I did on HakkerJobs with a lot of the improved tools that I worked on from other apps since then. They are both similar in that they are tabbed apps with each tab containing tableviews. There are similar features - saving certain items, browsing, and such. However, there are big improvements made when it came to getting, parsing, and presenting large amounts of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/cs-screenshot1.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas HakkerJobs uses multi-threading in order to download a lot of HN threads, collegeScan only has to make one API call. However the data that came back was large and deeply nested. Often the format would look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;metadata:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;total:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;16,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;page:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;0,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;per_page:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;results:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;id:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;447801,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;school.name:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;University of East-West Medicine&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;school.zip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;94085&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;id:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;459213,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;school.name:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&quot;Gurnick Academy of Medical Arts&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;school.zip&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;94403&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the results array would be a deeply nested JSON object. The data schema of the CollegeScorecard data was something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[year][type of data (like available academic program)][Detail]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such a deep nested object made parsing a pain. I adopted &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Hearst-DD/ObjectMapper&quot;&gt;ObjectMapper&lt;/a&gt; while building a previous project (a Reddit client that never got off the ground) and ported a lot of the learnings I had there to this. collegeScan uses ObjectMapper to map a large amount of data as well as a nifty feature (custom transformations) to help format that raw data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the UI, I went back to the Reddit Client (named LurkFish) and lifted a lot of the work that I did with &lt;a href=&quot;asyncdisplaykit.org&quot;&gt;AsyncDisplayKit&lt;/a&gt;. Check out the blog post that I &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/converting-to-ASyncDisplayKit&quot;&gt;wrote about taking ASDK to Hakkerjobs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;collegeScan’s inner guts works based on a Reddit client that I like to use (Antenna). A viewcontroller is tied to a school (or a type of query, the API call is basically the same). It is initialized with the necessary characteristics, customizes its correct query params and fires off for the data. Once the data is received and correctly parsed, it calls upon a number of a helper to parse and present the data. This data holds the dictionary of the API, something that took a lot of time to actually put together from the various documentation that I have found lying around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app also implements a lot of the new concepts that I have learned since HakkerJobs. There is the use of a Mirror to reflect and iterate on the various internal variables of the school data object (since each data table needs to have a label to explain the value). It also uses key-value to help make that job easier. There is an improved error handling system within the app - more guards and lets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s Next&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the first commit to the time I submitted to the Store was about 16 days, but I had worked on it pretty much every day. Even with that being said, it is a really pleasant change of pace compared to the aforementioned Reddit client - which I had worked on for over a month and still seemingly months away from a first deploy. While waiting for the first iteration of collegeScan to get approved on the store, I began work on a big new feature that I really wanted to get done: A comparison between two different colleges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/cs-compare.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There remains some work that need be done on the screens but I think I’ll be ready to push this new update shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am excited about this app. I think it has some great uses and I am always pleased to look up my alma mater on it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/introducing-collegescan&quot;&gt;Introducing CollegeScan&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on March 01, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things I Think I Think About Austin]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/things-i-think-about-austin" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/things-i-think-about-austin</id>
  <published>2016-02-20T00:00:00-08:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the second time that I find myself in Texas, but the first that I would be staying overnight. My friend Dan again let me know that for part of his work with trading the stock market that he would be coming out to his firm’s Austin office. He invited me to stay with him for the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/au-capital1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Split some costs and see Texas. What’s not to love? So on Monday I departed my parent’s place at 4 am and took an early morning flight into Dallas then drove 3 hours in a rented car to Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is going to start off a little differently. First, let me write a bit about what I knew about Texas going in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-few-things-i-thought-about-austin&quot;&gt;A Few Things I Thought About Austin&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) Super liberal enclave in the middle of yee-haw Texas.&lt;/strong&gt;
Texas is like the most conservative of conservative right? Well supposedly Austin is the only part of Texas that has consistently voted Democratic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Super cheap.&lt;/strong&gt;
Like seriously near Taiwan levels. Being in Dallas for such a short time but seeing prices so cheap there, I presumed that Austin would be similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) Great food&lt;/strong&gt;
I asked a friend and my cousin - who went to UT Austin for her masters - for things to do in Austin. Most of what came back was “Eat”. This sounds also a lot like Taiwan. Considering that I had ate a whole lot when I was in Orange County with my parents, I wasn’t too keen on doing this. “Just eat the tacos,” they told me. I was like, “I just came back from Orange County which isn’t chopped syrup when it comes to Mexican food.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s get it out of the way: Here’s some words about what I ate while I was here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-few-things-i-ate-in-austin&quot;&gt;A Few Things I Ate In Austin&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Huevos Rancheros&lt;/strong&gt;
This is what I ate most often for breakfast. Nothing else was open as early. I got up at like 6-7 AM every morning to have breakfast with Dan before he headed off to trade the markets at 8:30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/au-eat1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one was pretty good but it had a very strong tomatoey flavor. The refried beans were remarkable though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/au-eat6.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is from a different vendor, Magnolia Cafe on South Congress Ave (which my cousin tells me has a great mix of brunch places).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Migas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/au-eat4.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is something that I have never heard of before, but Migas are like huevos rancheros except they cook it with tortilla chips. What the heck? How does this work? Yet somehow it does. I enjoyed eating this. I am not a person who really enjoys crunchy foods but the chips worked out great. It is not the kind of thing that you see on the West Coast so I am real thankful for the chance to try it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brazilian&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/au-eat2.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This came from a single Brazilian food truck - Boteco on 1403 E 7th Street - that we tried out after everything started closing at 5 PM. They had a few appetizers but just one main dish which fortunately turned out to be amazing: A steak+eggs rice bowl with yucca flour. Yucca flour (is that how you spell it?) is this thing that, as the restaurant proprietor told me, that all Brazilians put on their leftovers to make it thick and heavy. As a result it helps you feel full at the end of the day. I am considering getting some myself. This and the “Dirty Sanchez” taco at Torchy’s Tacos were the best things I ate while I was in Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tacos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/au-eat7.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two different people recommended Torchy’s including my cousin, who threatened to vote for Trump if I didn’t try it out. They had a number of different tacos - all named rather bizarrely - but I took my cousin’s selections and was really pleased with what I got. The first one, called the Democrat, was real good but the real star was the Dirty Sanchez, a magnificent genius of a taco made from scrambled eggs, fried chile (how the hell does that work?), carrots, and cheese. I loved eating it every second I had it in my mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Louisiana Fried Foods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/au-eat8.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked two days of the week while I was here so I wasn’t in the mood for sightseeing. I just needed something to eat to satiate my hunger. I went around the corner and there was this place called the Big Easy Bar and Grill on 12th Street. The food there was pretty good Louisiana food. The reason I first walked in was because they advertised fried oysters and you know me, I love them fried oysters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is pretty good, with the blackened fish rather than the fried oysters being the real star of the show. At the same time, I ordered a jambalaya with red beans, rice, and sausage seasoned by cajun spices. Pretty good but all the while I was eating it I was thinking to myself, Jesus I can make this myself. So I went on Amazon right that very moment and ordered a bag of dried red beans. I will try it out later this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barbecue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/au-eat3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Texas is famous for BBQ and it was the thing I had a craving for when we first arrived in Austin. After eating at Sam’s BBQ I was done with BBQ for the rest of the trip. Didn’t even think about having it again. I got the mutton and the ribs. Great first impression - it is a delicious first bite - but after eating bite after bite of nothing but fat and fat you just get tired of it. Then you think you might get sick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was seriously worried that I was going to get off to a bad start to my Austin trip - after all that is how the BBQ at my Dallas trip ended (with 4 days laid low due to norovirus or whatever else it was I got but that was no normal gastro).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright with all the food done, a few things that I think about Dallas and Forth Worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-few-things-i-think-i-think-about-austin-and-fort-worth&quot;&gt;A Few Things I Think I Think About Austin and Fort Worth&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) Not as cheap as you might think&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gas is ridiculously cheap, about $1.40-1.50 depending on where in Austin (and in Fort Worth we were seeing some low $1.30s). However everything else is more comparable to SF, including the cost of food. If you are not eating cheap fried foods and fast foods (which you can get in SF anyway for about the same price), then you are paying about $10-15 for each meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Housing is a step level cheaper than SF, but at the same time houses aren’t exactly as cheap as one might think considering the salaries that you can expect to get here. I checked out RedFin while I was in Austin and houses in East Austin, where I stayed in my AirBnB and is supposedly on the up and up, and prices seemed to be about $400-500K, with a few starting to hit the $600K range. I didn’t check downtown Austin (which looks super nice and a lot like a cleaner, slightly more restrained SF) but I suppose that it is about the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now SF is still ridiculous with $1.5M and above, but salaries are high and if you are willing a little farther out in SF then you start seeing 700s. I don’t know what kind of world we are living in when we say $200K difference (when the average house price in the US is $180K) is “not that far off”, but this is how I feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) You gotta have a car, man&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Texas is goddamn big. I mean like seriously big. I read in the state museum of Texas that the single biggest business that they had at the start of the Republic of Texas was the selling of land. Well goddamn they right to make it do so because there is enough land here to settle every person on the planet (not joking. At the density of NYC, you can settle the entire 7B population of the planet on Texas).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that you gotta drive everywhere or else you are screwed. It is hard to get anywhere without a car and so everyone has one. There is just a huge sprawl and it is worse in Fort Worth than Austin but Austin has it pretty bad. I can’t imagine walking anywhere in Fort Worth. There are empty parking lots there more vast than anything that I have seen before. In Singapore or Taiwan, such land would have like 10 supertall towers or housing units. In Fort Worth, it’s just a parking lot. A parking lot for like those types of people who can’t pee at the stalls next to each other because it is so awkward so they all go and space each other out. There are lots on this lot that are just for those types of people to space themselves out! What?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) The Texas drawl is fun to mimic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People of course have differing levels of the drawl. Not everyone is from Texas, but the older people have it quite thick. I listened to a nice little old lady tell me about the open and closing hours of the State Museum of Texas and I could not help but be amused. It is not the best way to transmit information - it comes out at about the speed of a 24kb dial up modem with AOL. I was at the Lyndon B. Johnson Presidential Library (beautiful place) listening to tapes of LBJ speaking to people and Gawd he was taking so long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me everything to reply to this super nice, super polite old lady with her own drawl back at her. Oof, sorry SF guys when I come back and have that Texas drawl. I just cannot help it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) Moontowers. Beautiful name, beautiful sight.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we were driving about in Austin, Dan and I started to notice lights suspended up in the air. Too high up to be a regular light pole - they were over a hundred feet high but they aren’t descending so they cannot have anything to do with airplanes. I had seen them before too but figured that they were just regular radio towers until I saw a couple of them sharing the same street and that didn’t make sense. Just these intense bright lights … but tall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He asked me to Google it so I Googled, “tall light towers east austin” and right there was the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moonlight_tower&quot;&gt;Moontower&lt;/a&gt;. Here is what one looks like in the day:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/au-moontower.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(You can also how stupid cheap gas is there in Austin. WTF?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Austin is the only city in the country to still have moontowers. They were more popular where it was too expensive to have regular light poles but they pretty much do the same thing: Shine light on peeps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few details that I really like about these in particular:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;They are about 150 meters tall, which for Attack on Titan fans is as tall as the Walls. Gives you a real sense of the story’s immensity&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is a (false) urban legend that they were installed as a counter to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Servant_Girl_Annihilator&quot;&gt;Servant Girl Annihilator&lt;/a&gt;, a famous serial killer who operated a few years before Jack the Ripper and like Jacky was never caught. The Servant Girl Annihilator (who uses this word anymore?) was the subject of a fantastic article that I read a while back called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.texasmonthly.com/articles/capital-murder/&quot;&gt;Capital Murder&lt;/a&gt; in the July 2000 edition of Texas Monthly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) Everything shuts down at 5 PM or it goes all out, 24/7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had morning coffee at a great place called Bennu, where they were open 24/7 all the time. And like I mentioned above, I had breakfast at a 24/7 location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if they were not 24/7 then there was nothing open around the areas we frequented. This was especially the case in Fort Worth, in where everything was closed off as soon as the day started to fade. For miles we would drive and it would be nothing but just empty buildings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6) It was hot, but not too bad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the weather while I was there a lot like SoCal, a sort of dry heat. My friend tells me that it gets super hot in May and the summer. Considering that I have lived through SoCal summers where it got to 110 regularly, I can only imagine what Texas is like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a great trip and while I am not so sure that I would return (Dan says that he is going to go back in mid-March) it was a cool time. I am going to remember it, especially with all the photos that I took.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next after this (unless I take a random trip somewhere in March) is the mattress topper: Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/things-i-think-about-austin&quot;&gt;Things I Think I Think About Austin&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on February 20, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's Left]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/whats-left" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/whats-left</id>
  <published>2016-02-17T00:00:00-08:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/gravestones.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am in Austin this week for a brief work-away-from-home. Our AirBnB is cheap, partially because it is situated next to at least 4 or 5 cemeteries. Working in a nearby cafe, I can see gravestones right outside my window. I had managed to read one of these stones from my spot outside the fence: “World Traveler”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning I finished Paul Kalathi’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/When-Breath-Becomes-Paul-Kalanithi/dp/081298840X&quot;&gt;“When Breath Becomes Air”&lt;/a&gt; and after the final page, I could not help but picture in my mind his final resting place, a small plot overlooking the Pacific Ocean. I imagined being there with the salty air filling my lungs and the cymbal crash of the waves on the ever-loosening stones below. And behind me, eternally silent, the remains of a life. I wonder what it says on that stone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“World Traveler”. That’s it. That’s all left behind for a passing stranger, me. For a few moments, I burst into their eternity and that is all I walked away with. Where did they go? For how long? Who did they meet? That’s what the little voice in my head pondered as I paced away, beguiled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll never know, but I hope it meant so much more to the person who put it there. I hope it left them as much comfort as death can leave behind.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/whats-left&quot;&gt;What's Left&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on February 17, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Converting to ASyncDisplayKit]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/converting-to-ASyncDisplayKit" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/converting-to-ASyncDisplayKit</id>
  <published>2016-02-07T00:00:00-08:00</published>
  <updated>2016-02-07T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had been fascinated with &lt;a href=&quot;http://asyncdisplaykit.org/&quot;&gt;AsyncDisplayKit&lt;/a&gt; for a while now ever since I heard of the concept:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;AsyncDisplayKit is an iOS framework that keeps even the most complex user interfaces smooth and responsive … To keep its user interface smooth and responsive, your app should render at 60 frames per second — the gold standard on iOS. This means the main thread has one-sixtieth of a second to push each frame. That’s 16 milliseconds to execute all layout and drawing code! And because of system overhead, your code usually has less than ten milliseconds to run before it causes a frame drop.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;AsyncDisplayKit lets you move image decoding, text sizing and rendering, and other expensive UI operations off the main thread&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked with UITableViews extensively when I was creating my most recent published application - &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hakkerjobs-hackernews-client/id1028168255&quot;&gt;HakkerJobs&lt;/a&gt; but was not fully satisfied with the result. The original application had a hanging, “please wait” rotating item that floated on the screen while the app was busy downloading the data. As it did that, I locked user interaction with the table. It was not the best user experience and I did not enjoy working with it. ASDK seemed like a good solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time I took a crack at it though did not go well. I did not know how ASDK worked and could not get the application to run. I got as far as replacing some of the required UITableView delegate methods with the ASTable (ASDK’s version of UITableView) and subclassing ASCellNode (which is the ASDK version of UITableViewCell). Chastened, I deleted my ASDK branch from the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few more applications, I decided that I would pursue the matter again. I was working on a Reddit client and really wanted to make ASDK work this time. I watched a few videos and I think that got me to a better place. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RY_X7l1g79Q&quot;&gt;This one&lt;/a&gt; in particular was very helpful. Once someone had explained it to me, then I grasped the challenge better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;asdk-as-i-understand-it&quot;&gt;ASDK (As I Understand It)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ASDK exists because the standard SDK for building UI elements (UIKit) generates those elements on what is called the “main thread” instead of a “background thread” - these threads are possible because iPhones today have multiple cores. This is inefficient because processing things on the main thread blocks other processes. The result is that the consumer-facing interface drops frames and looks laggy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ASDK introduces the concept of the “node”, which sounds super fancy but really is just another NSObject that wraps a standard UIKit element (see the diagram below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://asyncdisplaykit.org/assets/node-view-layer.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefits of this is that the background thread decodes and sets up a whole bunch of cool things without stressing out your interface. This is a new and weird approach which means that there is a whole lot of things that you have to do differently from initiating a standard UITableView. With that being said, if you are familiar with it then switching from UITable to ASTable could be as easy as a drop-in replacement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-code---astable&quot;&gt;The Code - ASTable&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had two tabs in the app that I would have liked to switch out - there are more but we shall save those for later. They were UITableViewControllers. Being UITableViewControllers mean that they have three crucial delegate functions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;override func tableView(tableView: UITableView, cellForRowAtIndexPath indexPath: NSIndexPath) -&amp;gt; UITableViewCell

func tableView(tableView: UITableView, numberOfRowsInSection section: Int) -&amp;gt; Int

func numberOfSectionsInTableView(tableView: UITableView) -&amp;gt; Int
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swapping in an ASTableView (other than instantiating it and placing it in the view) is pretty easy actually. UITableViews are simply instantiated and added to the subview (you don’t need to invoke addSubview because if you are working with a UITableViewController, in which you can simply called tableView). However there are other things needed to get the right look:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    self.tableView.delegate = self
    self.tableView.dataSource = self
    self.tableView.registerClass(JobViewCell.self, forCellReuseIdentifier: &quot;Cell&quot;)
    self.tableView.rowHeight = UITableViewAutomaticDimension
    self.tableView.estimatedRowHeight = 400.0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first two lines help the VC understand where to go for information to figure its behavior and its data. The Delegate helps define behaviors (what happens if they touch a cell for example) while the DataSource helps define what info shows up (what info does the cell show, etc). The third line is to tell the tableView what cell they should expect to use (using an identifier called the reuseIdentifier). The fourth and fifth are so I can get the right positioning of UIKit elements (mostly UILabels) within the cell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was replaced. I turned the UITableViewController into a normal UIViewController, instantiated a ASTableView, and added it to the subview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    jobsTableView = ASTableView(frame: view.frame, style: UITableViewStyle.Plain, asyncDataFetching: true)
    view.addSubview(jobsTableView)
    jobsTableView.asyncDataSource = self
    jobsTableView.asyncDelegate = self
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New names for the functions but the concept is the same. I tell ASDK that I want a ASTable with async data fetching capability enabled. Then I give it itself as an asyncDatasource and delegate (previous hangups I had was that I wasn’t using asyncDatasource and asyncDelegate but instead regular delegate and datasource and also that I was not subclassing the ASTableDelegate and ASTableDataSource classes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Required delegate methods are next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-code---datasource-and-delegate-methods&quot;&gt;The Code - DataSource and Delegate Methods&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a barebones UITableView going, you need to fill in two methods, coming from the datasource that you want to display. The first one below&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;func tableView(tableView: UITableView, numberOfRowsInSection section: Int) -&amp;gt; Int
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an Objective-C function but easy to read even if you are coming from Swift. “func” means that this is a function. “tableView” means that it refers the UITableView and then within the paratheses it takes two variables - a reference to the tableView object itself (referred to as ‘tableView’) and a reference to the section. A tableView is divided into sections and then within each section are rows. This function simply tells the table how many rows it should draw within a section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The part that goes “-&amp;gt; Int” means that you have to return with an Int.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This required datasource function does not change when we swapped out the TableView with the ASTableView. For me it was the number of jobstory items that have been downloaded from the HackerNews source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second required data method that you need to override is the below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;override func tableView(tableView: UITableView, cellForRowAtIndexPath indexPath: NSIndexPath) -&amp;gt; UITableViewCell
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me walk you through this particular function. The NSIndexPath is sort of like a coordinate system for the table. It is made out of two components - the Section (indexPath.section) and the row within the section (if there is only 1 section), indexPath.row. Within this function you initiate a UITableViewCell (you don’t usually instantiate a brand new one, you let iOS do this nifty reuse trick where it recycles cells that vanish off screen, identifying with the “reuse identifier” that I mentioned earlier in this piece) and then you configure it with the information that you want to set it up with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one has to be replaced with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;func tableView(tableView: ASTableView, nodeForRowAtIndexPath indexPath: NSIndexPath) -&amp;gt; ASCellNode
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see that is pretty similar and for the most part it is. You instantiate a Node and then configure it with the particulars that you want it to eventually display. One thing in particular that is interesting is that you do not reuse the node like you do with the view cell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;func tableView(tableView: UITableView, didSelectRowAtIndexPath indexPath: NSIndexPath) 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only super important delegate method did require any change. This one dictates the behavior of the table once someone actually taps on a cell. I was surprised that I would not be required to make any change to the code here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was surprised that this worked out so well - and so little was actually required to set up. However now comes the tough one: the custom cells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-code---custom-nodes&quot;&gt;The Code - Custom Nodes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is rare that the out-of-the-box ASTableNode works for your purposes. Instead you have to subclass it and create your own custom NodeCell. This turned out to be easy. In the creation of the first iteration of HakkerJobs, there are tables populated with a custom cell I created. This cell is used throughout the entire app in various different functions. They look like the screenshot below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/as-old.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seems complicated but turned out to be relatively easy to replicate. Each cell had only three sets of information that it needed to display: The Title, the date of the job, and a classification label. I created a custom init function that took in an individual job listing (an Item) and then passed that Item to a worker function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;class ASJobsCell: ASCellNode {
    var titleNode: ASTextNode
    var dateNode: ASTextNode
    var typeNode: ASTextNode

    init!(item: Item) {
        titleNode = ASTextNode()
        dateNode = ASTextNode()
        typeNode = ASTextNode()
    
        super.init()
        setupSubNodesWithItem(item)
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the setupSubNodesWithItem function we have this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;func setupSubNodesWithItem(item: Item) {
    titleNode.attributedString = NSAttributedString(string: item.title, attributes: [
        NSFontAttributeName: UIFont.preferredFontForTextStyle(UIFontTextStyleHeadline)
        ])
    titleNode.placeholderColor = UIColor.blackColor()
    
    dateNode.attributedString = NSAttributedString(string: UIFactory.createDateFormatter().stringFromDate(item.time), attributes: [
        NSFontAttributeName: UIFont.preferredFontForTextStyle(UIFontTextStyleSubheadline)
        ])
    typeNode.attributedString = NSAttributedString(string: item.jobType, attributes: [
        NSFontAttributeName: UIFont.preferredFontForTextStyle(UIFontTextStyleSubheadline),
        NSForegroundColorAttributeName: UIColor.blueColor()
        ])
    
    addSubnode(titleNode)
    addSubnode(dateNode)
    addSubnode(typeNode)
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was shocked a bit by how easy it was to set this up. You instantiate the component subnodes and then add them to the main CellNode. But now comes the tough part, the positioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-code---viewcells-layouts&quot;&gt;The Code - ViewCells Layouts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not going to lie. The reason there’s only one type of cell used throughout the entire app is because figuring out layout and positioning issues was a real pain in the ass even when using a helper library like SnapKit. Here is an example of the JobViewCell:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    self.titleLabel.snp_makeConstraints { (make) -&amp;gt; Void in
        make.top.equalTo(self.contentView).offset(5.0)
        make.left.equalTo(self.contentView).offset(10.0)
        make.right.equalTo(self.contentView).offset(-10.0)
        make.bottom.equalTo(self.dateLabel.snp_top).offset(-5.0)
    }
    
    self.dateLabel.snp_makeConstraints { (make) -&amp;gt; Void in
        make.left.right.equalTo(self.contentView).offset(10.0)
        make.bottom.equalTo(self.contentView.snp_bottom).offset(-2.0)
        make.height.equalTo(20.0)
    }
    
    self.accessoryBadge.snp_makeConstraints { (make) -&amp;gt; Void in
        make.bottom.equalTo(self.contentView).offset(-5.0)
        make.right.equalTo(self.contentView).offset(-10.0)
    }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pain in the butt because that code is just for positioning. I gotta style it too with the proper font and color settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because ASDK offloads a lot of the expensive layout and positioning calculations to the background thread, a lot of this code becomes useable. Instead, the developers of ASDK have this fangled thing called LayoutSpecs, which appear to be sort of like blueprints that use flex box css lingo. After subclassing ASNodeCell - ASDK’s version of the UITableViewCell - I overrode this specific delegate function and wrapped the individual TextNodes in LayoutSpecs that give broad guidelines as to how the cell is going to look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;override func layoutSpecThatFits(constrainedSize: ASSizeRange) -&amp;gt; ASLayoutSpec {
    let verticalNodeStack = ASStackLayoutSpec(direction: ASStackLayoutDirection.Vertical, spacing: 8.0, justifyContent: ASStackLayoutJustifyContent.End, alignItems: ASStackLayoutAlignItems.BaselineFirst, children: [titleNode, dateNode, typeNode])
    
    return ASInsetLayoutSpec(insets: UIEdgeInsets(top: 5.0, left: 10.0, bottom: 5.0, right: 10.0), child: verticalNodeStack)
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I instantiated the verticalNodeStack, the ASStackLayoutSpec that wraps the raw elements (the titleNode, the dateNode, and the typeNode) together. It specifies the direction of the layout (vertical down) and the spacing in between the elements. Then you wrap the whole thing in an InsetLayout spec so that you get some spacing. That gets returned to the function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is still a lot more to do and this blog is long enough. I am surprised all in all that writing this post took longer than the actual changes that I have made. But in conclusion, ASDK for the Table requires you to think differently about how UITableViews work but it is now a lot simpler and ready for a smoother user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are curious as to how the final product looks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/as-new.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/converting-to-ASyncDisplayKit&quot;&gt;Converting to ASyncDisplayKit&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on February 07, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[My 5 Favorite Articles of 2015]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/my-favorite-5-articles-of-2015" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/my-favorite-5-articles-of-2015</id>
  <published>2016-01-24T00:00:00-08:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have a 2015 book post coming up ahead but I wanted to break this out into its own type of post. I read all the time, but most of my non-fiction reading is not in the form of books but in articles. Much of my most important learning has come from my article reading, so I figured it deserves a post separate from the book reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose these five articles because they made an indelible impression on me. Perhaps they conveyed advice that I eventually put to use within that year. Perhaps I relayed what I learned on to other people and they also found it impactful. Perhaps I just kept finding myself going back to this article again and again, reading simply because I found it so enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sick-systems-how-to-keep-someone-with-you-foreverhttpissendailivejournalcom572510html&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://issendai.livejournal.com/572510.html&quot;&gt;SICK SYSTEMS: HOW TO KEEP SOMEONE WITH YOU FOREVER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I first saw this was in a working and career context but I slowly realized that this would be applicable to almost any sort of attachment or relationship in between two people. Read this for yourself and see if you can see any of these behaviors in the relationships in your life. If you find too many of these in any one single relationship, then you might want to re-evaluate whether its worth having.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-renegade-trawler-hunted-for-10000-miles-by-vigilanteshttpwwwnytimescom20150728worlda-renegade-trawler-hunted-for-10000-miles-by-vigilanteshtmlnytmobile0r0&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/07/28/world/a-renegade-trawler-hunted-for-10000-miles-by-vigilantes.html?nytmobile=0&amp;amp;_r=0&quot;&gt;A RENEGADE TRAWLER, HUNTED FOR 10,000 MILES BY VIGILANTES&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As thrilling as any piece of writing can be combined with a 17th century story taking place 400 years too late. The circumstances behind this article shocked me. How can such a thing even take place in our “civilized” world? This felt like something right out of a pirate movie - and you would expect Blackbeard to show up with this treasure and gold pieces. Yet these guys have radios and IDs and motoring boats with gas engines. Reading this gave me a chill, it all feels so surreal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my last blog post about articles, I wrote about the capture of El Chapo. I figure then that it makes sense that there should be one thrilling chase article in any compilation that I put together. Here it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;japans--105-hour-workweekhttproadsandkingdomscom2015japans-105-hour-workweek&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://roadsandkingdoms.com/2015/japans-105-hour-workweek/&quot;&gt;JAPAN’S  105-HOUR WORKWEEK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People love Japan, but this story I think shed my eyes about their ups and brought me some clarity about their downs. To be frank, everyone works effing hard in Asia, but Japan seems to be taking this to a whole new level. They seem to be fine with it, but is that a sort of life that we can live? If we aren’t working as hard as they are, does that mean that we aren’t as competitive as they are in the global marketplace? My father likes to tell us that there are a thousand Asians in Asia just as smart as I was working ten thousand times harder and they are all trying to come here and take my job from me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s sort of exaggerating a bit (I’ve realized over the span of my career that you can be really smart and work really hard and still be an idiot), but you read something like this and it sort of wipes your smugness down for a moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;english-is-not-normalhttpsaeoncoessayswhy-is-english-so-weirdly-different-from-other-languages&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/essays/why-is-english-so-weirdly-different-from-other-languages&quot;&gt;English Is Not Normal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English is the only language that I have ever mastered, so being the self-examining n00b that I am, I found this article about the language and its peculiarities fascinating. Maybe it is just the weirdo part in me that loves trivia, but this article was great as a compilation of our beloved language’s weird quirks and what exactly went wrong to make it so happen that I could type out a sentence just kinda like the one I just crap out here yet people can still grasp the general overall message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-believerhttpwwwbelievermagcomissues201501readarticleschneiderphelan&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.believermag.com/issues/201501/?read=article_schneider_phelan&quot;&gt;The Believer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately I have found myself in danger of assuming that everything has been figured out. That everything has been tucked away into its dusty little cardboard box. That people have discovered everything that there is to be discovered within our world. The vastness of space beyond beckons, and that is the final frontier. Within the world of humanity there is only reality. I have felt this sort of pessimism, a pessimism that feels brought upon by a brooding realization that the “mass” of humanity - billions of human minds smashing away at problems - will invariably outclass any single person. The outcome of having billions of humans is that you have thousands of really smart humans and what they can come up with is always better than what any single human can do, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In so many fields, that’s right but not in this one. The Believer is an article about Srinivasa Ramanujan, a 19th century man who was the most remarkable mathematician to have ever lived. He grew up dirt-poor and with no education beyond an outdated math textbook, ascended faster than anyone has ever done before. He was so uneducated and so isolated that half of the things he discovered had already been discovered before, by other people years ago. It was like watching the entire progression of human mathematics unfolding in a single person. His scribblings continue to yield insights today, and this article talks about one of the last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a time when there is a huge focus on the group, on the society, and the ability of people to do great things &lt;strong&gt;together&lt;/strong&gt;, I think there is room to recognize that individuals can be capable of things beyond what the rest of us do. I don’t mean that in a sort of Ayn Rand-ian way - but just that sometimes, we have to let incredible things done by incredible people teach us that our world around us still holds many secrets to behold.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/my-favorite-5-articles-of-2015&quot;&gt;My 5 Favorite Articles of 2015&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on January 24, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflecting on 27]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/reflecting-on-27" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/reflecting-on-27</id>
  <published>2016-01-22T00:00:00-08:00</published>
  <updated>2016-01-22T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was coming home late tonight and maybe it has something to do with the quiet Friday night - it is my favorite time of the week because it is a time when I get to see other people at leisure - but I started to think and reflect for the first time in a while. You see, last week was my birthday and I turned 28.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really cannot believe it - the progression of a decade (which seems like an unfathomable amount of time) since my high school graduation year. You know, when I was 14 or 15 I had been so afraid of turning 18, turning into an adult and going to college by myself, that I had resolved to end my life before I ever got to that age. As you might expect, I didn’t do that and I blew through 18, 19, 20 … and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They say that you turn into an adult when you turn 25, and maybe that was true in my case. I don’t remember much of 25 or 26 but 27 was a momentous year. Reflecting on it now, it was the year when I jumped back into iOS programming, wrote a book on Instagram, and finally resolved to leave my job and take some career risks. Personally it was a year of much growth. I managed to move past my fixation on Jenny, make friends abroad (Heck, TRAVEL abroad), find myself immersed in moments of true connectedness with the vastness of our world, and even somehow be seen as a mentor (Have I really become that old?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I tally it all up, collate it together, and summate it at the bottom, I find that what has been most special for me this year - the key that turned the lock for my year of 27, has been the realization that I have to let go of the thinking that everything that I work for and optimize towards should have to do with the almighty dollar. That all the money that I’ve scrimped and saved for over those years have done nothing to protect me from getting hurt. That what is so much more important and enriching to my existence are the people around me. That it is totally worth it to stay late, bear with a two hour commute home, to have dinner with that one friend who I have not seen in a while. That I have been extraordinarily lucky to have genuinely good people around me who care for me and laugh at my jokes and cry at my pains and get mad at my injustices. I love all of you, each and every one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while 28 is going to be a new year of change and volatility - I have some crazy, totally unsolidified plans to freelance abroad in another country, to travel spontaneously, and definitely to write a few new books - one thing that I will work to keep from changing is this progress that I have made with other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I’ll leave this cheese-fest with a quote I have seen on my friend’s Facebook post - unchanged - for over 9 years. I looked at it many times over the years but never really stopped to consider it on a second level until recently, and now I realize I love it too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“The only true currency in this bankrupt world is what we share with someone else when we’re uncool. “ - Lester Bangs, Almost Famous&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/reflecting-on-27&quot;&gt;Reflecting on 27&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on January 22, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[For Yourself and Not For Others]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/for-yourself" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/for-yourself</id>
  <published>2015-12-19T00:00:00-08:00</published>
  <updated>2015-12-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I have been thinking about working hard and who we work for when we work really really hard. I didn’t really write this post with a message to deliver. I just wanted to put into words conflicting thoughts that have been going back and forth in my head. During one of my long trips home on the train, I was thinking about how hard some people work at their job. They are salaried, so it doesn’t matter how many hours they spend at their work but they come in as early as 7AM and work deep into the night. When you glance back at their workstation and they are there and not in some sort of meeting, they’re 100% focused on the task at hand. No distractions. No chatting. No deviation from the goal - which they visualize in their own heads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder why they work so hard. My father works hard because he knows no other way - he has always been a man with a brutal work ethic. I know some other people who work hard because they feel that the work that they do reflects on who they are and how they want to be perceived - and they want to be perceived as a person who puts out good work and can be relied upon. I know other people who work hard because they are competitive - hard work is the way that you get ahead in a tough tough environment. Others work hard because they know that their work will make a visible, notable impact on the world proper - their contribution to a lasting legacy. Some other people work for money - but that’s not interesting at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I do a self-examination, I find that I err more on the second reason - it makes me feel good when I sense that people like the work that I do. I like feeling needed. The last thing that I ever want to do for people is let them down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently in the process of winding down at my current job two and a half years after joining. There has been a lot of effort and strain put into my time there - and perhaps someday in the future I’ll be willing to write about it - but when I look back at what I have done there, I feel pride in the inherent value the work provided, but feel more glowered when I reflect on how that work has affected the people who I worked with at the time. For me, I do the work that I do because I do it for people I care for. When you lose the latter, I don’t see the point of going on the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I realize that shortly I am going to be released into the real world like an asteroid gone awry, I reflect that this reason to work hard is going to go away. The effort, blood, sweat and tears that I am going to dedicate myself to is not going for the sake of someone else working alongside me, but for my own self. When that seems to be the case, I wonder if I will be able to push myself in the same way, with the same drive and focus, with the same depth of detail and pursuit of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I probably won’t. I don’t think I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which on one hand is sort of a pity. One of the biggest problems in the world today - and I think one that is going to get a lot of people our age into trouble in the future - is that they don’t realize that ultimately they are working for themselves. They put more effort in their jobs or their work than in themselves, which is nice for the company (and the senior managers who run it, and the shareholders who ultimately benefit from it) but not great for them. So in twenty years the company can go and lay them off with 3 months’ pay? One thing that I have learned after so many years of working is that companies aren’t your friends (your coworkers can be your friends, though). They aren’t your buds. They’d pay you half as much as you are making right now if they can get away with it. That doesn’t change even if you own a tiny bit of it (employee share programs, ha!) Stocks and cash in the bank can get stolen and used up. The inherent value that you can bring with your skill set, well that never gets used up - as long as you put in as much work into it as you do for your employer. Even if it is just a tiny little thing, push yourself to take that one extra class, to pursue that one passion that might turn into something more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then on the other hand …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I really need to work as hard once I am out there by myself? I mean, is it really necessary? It was necessary when I was in my full-time, pushing to make deadlines, get this out, get that processed. Whatever. But once you are out there, what is pushing you? Only what you’ve set for yourself, and the needs that you and your body requires. And I think a stone heavy work ethic is ultimately bad. It is bad for our physical health and bad for our mental health and bad for our social health. And I have always believed this: When it comes down to it, people don’t need that much in the world to survive. When you don’t need much, you don’t need to work that hard to get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s one thing that I definitely felt as I talked to people in Taiwan, Shanghai and Singapore. People there work really hard, and that’s starting down a path with an unhappy ending. Everyone dies alone, but I think a really bad way to go is to have regretted that you’ve worked so hard to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/for-yourself&quot;&gt;For Yourself and Not For Others&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on December 19, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things I Think I Think About Singapore]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/things-i-think-about-singapore" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/things-i-think-about-singapore</id>
  <published>2015-12-06T00:00:00-08:00</published>
  <updated>2015-12-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After Taiwan, I had thought about a new place to visit. When it became clear that I would have time to travel through the November Thanksgiving holiday, I sat down with a few recommendations. Eventually I decided to pick Singapore because I knew a few people there already. I would be able to meet them and have them show me around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/sg-skyline.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have just returned so you know what that means: A whole new post on what it was like there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-few-things-i-think-i-think-about-singapore&quot;&gt;A Few Things I Think I Think About Singapore&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) Singapore is Rightly Famous For Its Multi-Culturalism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being from America, I am familiar with seeing a lot of different faces in the crowds around me. Singapore has a very close feel to that. You will see a diversity of faces from white people to Chinese people to Indian people to even a few black people from time to time. Make no mistake, Chinese faces are the dominant demographic here but it is not overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to San Francisco, Singapore has a lot of enclaves that feel like transplants out of a different country. I enjoyed visiting some of these places including Little India and a small Persian (Arabic?) area that sold some amazing carpets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have heard many times that the best way to explore a new area is to get out there on the streets. For the first few days I avoided the public transportation system and went where I wanted to go on foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Singaporean Salaries are Nowhere Near American Salaries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can say that Singaporeans salaries are higher than what they are in Taiwan but still far below what they are in the US (and definitely below what you will find in SF). At the same time, living costs are a step lower too, perhaps something closer to what you would might expect in a mid-class United States city (Pittsburgh?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) Singaporean Architecture is Quite Creative&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can describe SF architecture as rather bland. Most of them deign to feature a few Roman columns so to break up the mood but for the most part, these buildings were built at a time when the technology did not afford the capability to go crazy in the design. Singapore in many places is a young city and the architecture reflects this. You get sights like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/sg-funnybuilding.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I appreciate the bold aesthetic of the buildings but cannot help but wonder what it would be like to have to travel down mind-bending twists of architecture just so that you can get to the bathroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) Condoms are Advertised Like Candy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that my father told me about Singapore was that I could not chew gum there or else I would get whipped (the second thing he told me was to go find a girlfriend). So gum is not being sold there, what do Singaporeans sell instead? Chocolates? Candy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope, it’s condoms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas in the US, condoms are sold perhaps behind the counter or down some aisle in the CVS drugstore (and you may have to ask the pharmacist to open up the glass box to get at it for you), condoms are sold in Singapore right up there with other “grab-ables” like mints. I found this immensely amusing. Equally amusing was the reactions of the Singaporeans themselves when I pointed this out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) I Hate Layovers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent 21 hours in Shanghai before flying onwards to Singapore and while I did get to have beautiful sights of the Bund (see below), I had a horrible time just spending 21 hours in a single city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/sg-shanghai.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then the worse thing is going home. You are on your way home, you want to get there directly. Why do you wanna wait? Instead, I found myself trying to catch a few winks on the Shanghai airport bench while waiting out my 7 hour layover sentence. Ugh. I’ll shell out next time to go direct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6) Miles and Miles of Malls, Connected All Underground&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend Chris told me to meet at Suntec City and to “start from City Hall”. Okay, that’s fine I think and so I message to say that I had just started getting to the underground mall. The response: “Oh shit you just started?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought to myself, “I ain’t that far off, right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m18!1m12!1m3!1d3!2d103.85769703982227!3d1.2979600226853254!2m3!1f0!2f90!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f75!3m3!1m2!1s0x31da19af0abb8bdb%3A0xf81a12d025cb11e1!2sSuntec+City!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sus!4v1449445844066&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;border:0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dude, I was so wrong. It took 20-25 minutes to get to the meeting spot. I was baffled by just how far the mall stretched. It never seemed to end. Later on I realized that this is not an exception. All of these malls are connected to each other, long stretches of air conditioned hallway. That is why some people can say that it can thunder pour rain but never notice it. They are never above-ground!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7) The Thundering Rains Are Freaky as Shit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the rain, the first time I came across a Singaporean monsoon I was scared out of my wits. The rain came down with such force that I thought it would never end. It simply poured like nothing I have ever seen before. And the thunder! And the lightning!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Locals told me that this was a normal thing. It rains quite infrequently in Singapore. The rains might seem strong but they die off quickly. That would have saved me a couple bucks on Uber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8) It Honestly Helps So Much That Everyone Speaks English&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was waiting in line for a ticket when the lady in front of me and in Chinese asked me if I had any idea about when it would stop raining. Without thinking, I responded in English and caught myself. Amazingly enough the lady immediately switched to English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This came to save my butt many times when ordering food, getting a ticket to some place, or traveling somewhere being lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9) Singapore’s Signs Are So Helpful&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike in other places (especially America), when there is a sign, it honestly points to where the end goal is. I found myself looking up at the various planted signs and diligently following them like a zombie. Unlike with American signs, Singaporean signs don’t just point in the general direction of the destination. They actually point you down the path. I appreciate that. Thank you Mr Sign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10) Imported Food is Expensive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/sg-strawberries.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Berries are an especially egregious example, but fresh fruit in general seems to cost more in Singapore than it is in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10.5) Singaporean Food Is Good With a Mix of Diversity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food in Singapore is well known for coming from a number of different cultures and I think I really appreciated that. You can never get tired of the food choices. There is always something for your own tastes. Are you thinking of pricey/fancy or scrungy/earthy? Indian? Singaporean? Chinese? It’s all here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/sg-food1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of my favorites are in the above photo from the top left: Stingray, some sort of meat taco, la mian from Din Tai Fung (ah the famous DTF), and Satay skewers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to just pure Chinese style food, Taiwan comes out ahead (but I am no food judge or anything), but you cannot beat Singapore for diversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11) How Can Anyone Trust The Electronics People Buy?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no brand name electronics stores in Singapore that I am aware of. No Best Buy or Radio Shack (RIP) or any of the sort as well as no Amazon Prime - a heart breaker. Most people buy electronics from mom and pop shops with lots of brands that I have never heard of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12) It Gets Super Crowded in Singapore At Times&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of people in Singapore. Some of the people there who have been there a while tell me that it has gotten quite worse in the past few years and there are a few signs that the infrastructure is a bit stressed. The public transportation is bit grungier than I expected (worse than Taiwan’s, which I didn’t expect) and check out how packed this aquarium is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/sg-crowd.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be hard to find a place to just get away from everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13) Just Like the Brits, They Like to Queue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14) Singapore Loves Taiwan!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw this and found it infinitely amusing. Singaporeans love Taiwan as much as I do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/sg-taiwan.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15) The Sentosa Aquarium is beautiful&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/sg-aquarium1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite all the crowds (not a place I would recommend if you have agoraphobia), I loved visiting Singapore. My grandmother jokingly said that I would have finished the whole tourist perspective the same day I stepped off the plane but the sheer novelty of being away from the US sustained much of this trip. I enjoyed it deeply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;6&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:62.5% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/-tlF52R9je/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;My last photo from Singapore. It&amp;#39;s not about what you do, but who you meet. Thank you so much @qqbear88 @chrisss107 and @kikrumbs for making my time here something I&amp;#39;ll never forget.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Jonathan Yu (@eroticbroccoli) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2015-11-30T14:23:24+00:00&quot;&gt;Nov 30, 2015 at 6:23am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/things-i-think-about-singapore&quot;&gt;Things I Think I Think About Singapore&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on December 06, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things I Think I Think About Dallas Y'all]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/things-i-think-about-dallas-yall" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/things-i-think-about-dallas-yall</id>
  <published>2015-11-14T00:00:00-08:00</published>
  <updated>2015-11-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Couple of weeks ago my friend Daniel let me know that he was flying into Dallas and invited me to meet him there. It would be a fleeting flight (ho ho ho) and a bit pricey but the opportunity was tempting. I eventually accepted and on Saturday November 14th flew out to the Lone Star State.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/dal-flag.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I am writing a retrospective on the plane returning to San Jose. While I did not spend a lot of time there and am unlikely to return there in the immediate future, I thought that I would write some thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;things-i-think-i-think-about-texas-yall&quot;&gt;6 Things I Think I Think About Texas Y’all&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) Texas has the biggest sprawl I’ve ever seen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had thought that the Taiwanese countryside had a lot of space in between buildings but Texas and Dallas really takes the cake. I took this picture from the airplane, marveling just how much countryside and meadow there is to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/dal-sprawl.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can start with the airport, which is huge with rolling hills that stretch for miles. The rental car area feels miles away from the actual terminals (necessitating some sweating in the end as Daniel and I rushed to make my early flight after returning the car), with buses taking people from one part of the airport to another. For comparison, when we dropped off the car rental at the Philadelphia airport, we rushed to the terminals by crossing a street and cutting through a parking lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is far away from everything else, forcing people to drive everywhere - almost everyone here drives a massive truck. Huge trucks = huge parking lots, which lead me to my next point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) There’s just so much land here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is just so much space and land here that as a San Francisco based urbanist, it feels like an embarrassment of riches. You would be driving through the city a few miles away from the presumably expensive downtown area (which doesn’t feel bustling at all) and you come across these random empty lots of land. And then even when they are landscaped, you just have these immense voids of trees, shrubs and sidewalk that feel almost disgusting …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/dal-park.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These huge tracts of land - while they may certainly feel ordinary and right to a native Texan - so violate my norms of urban living that I feel this urge to purchase them hand over fist. I want to break out my wallet and buy all the land I can, like one of those contestants on Supermarket Sweep, hefting deeds off the shelf and tossing them into my cart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? Because after looking at San Francisco and NYC, this near-shameful plenty of land can’t last. It can’t right? Land is a scarce resource and Texas is the second biggest state in the country. It has to get used up some time in the future, right??? Then who will be laughing then because at that point I will be the biggest land owner in the state! MUHAHA!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) The houses are also BIG&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn’t able to get a whole lot of pictures but here is one semi-obscured example of the type of house that you can expect to see in Dallas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/dal-house.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After seeing a number of these houses, I feel like each of them are about the size of the billionaire mansions that I saw with Daniel whilst we were driving through the New Jersey and Pennsylvania countryside. Each of them are boxy shaped with windows and balconies with immense front, side, and back lawns quipping perfectly manicured grass. Such a house would be an anathema in New York City or San Francisco, torn down in an instant because it would be against code. Here, they seem to stretch as far as the eye can see (and the car can drive).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw a number of these for sale but couldn’t grab a flyer or some sort to look for a quoted price. San Francisco homes a tenth of the size of these places go for about $800,000 (and rising) if you are lucky. I have heard prices of $400,000 (and daresay … $300,000??) but I simply cannot believe it. It’s like they’re giving it to you for FREE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) Dallas has a lot more greenery than I expected&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have noticed from the two earlier photos that I have published above but there is a whole lot of greenery here in the state. So I have no idea where I got the idea - maybe all the Western movies I watched as a kid - but the mental image I had of Texas was of a dry desert like area. Kind of like Southern California but even more so and with more cactuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This does not seem to be the case as there is plenty of plants, grass and greenery here. The air today (and it might just be the effects of winter) felt cool and moist like as if a mist had rolled through just before my plane landed in the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where is this water coming from? Isn’t Texas supposed to be a desert state? How did they find the water to make things like what you see below …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/dal-fountains.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does it come from the Rio Grande? From underneath the soil? Is it from the Gulf of Mexico? Are they taking it out of the sky? Is the state at risk of a drought? I didn’t see any rivers. Would they be taking it from the rivers? Is it fair to the river otters that play in those rivers? I ponder these questions as I sit here writing on my plane to San Jose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) Asians are rarer here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first place I have traveled to where I felt like a legitimate minority. Taiwan, I felt lost in a sea of Asians. NYC, there are plenty of us to go around. Even Vegas has a bunch of us hanging about - making weekend trips from the Bay Area. Keep in mind I was here for 5 hours, but I clearly noticed a lot less of my type hanging about - so much that when I saw an Asian girl crossing the street near the Dallas Art Museum I pointed to her with an exclamation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not like people treated me any differently or anything. If I were to travel to some place like Budapest or Poland, I think I might be a true curiosity there. Texas, there are Asians of course, so I didn’t get oogled or anything but we appear to be significantly less represented. It takes longer for me to see a kin on the street. Most of the people here are Latino, white or black. And yes they got awesome mustaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6) BBQ is good … but it is also affordable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I live in San Francisco, the best culinary place in the country, but when you talk about spendthrift value and taste, Texas gets pretty good going. I went to a BBQ ribs place in SF with my friend Audrey and shelled out $25 for a meat plate without blinking an eye. The same meat plate here costs about half of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/dal-bbqplace.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Above is a picture of me taking a picture of the BBQ place, which apparently has been in business since 1910. That’s a damn long time)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got this awesome meat plate below which tasted excellent albeit was a little cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/dal-meatplate.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beans did taste a bit too sharp and sour for my preference, but it can be acquired over time. The onion rings were HUGE, as big as my fist, but I definitely should have tried something else like the coleslaw. With all that being said and also the fact that I am no connoisseur, but I gave that plate five out of five. For sure would go back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am happy that I got to spend time here. Dallas might seem like just another part of the US of A but I really enjoyed pondering and noticing the differences even between these two mega cities in the country. Would I go back? Maybe, but definitely with a car. You cannot live here without driving. It is just too big, too sprawling, and too far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Daniel for the impetus to come out of the San Francisco bubble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It being a day after the horrible things that happened in Paris, I thought that this was a nice gesture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/dal-building.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, I am on the plane again, heading to two cities in Asia. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/things-i-think-about-dallas-yall&quot;&gt;Things I Think I Think About Dallas Y'all&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on November 14, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things I Think About A Little Life]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/a-little-life-review" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/a-little-life-review</id>
  <published>2015-11-08T00:00:00-08:00</published>
  <updated>2015-11-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Little-Life-Novel-Hanya-Yanagihara/dp/0385539258/ref=sr_1_1&quot;&gt;“A Little Life”&lt;/a&gt; has been the most talked about book of the year. The first reviews that I came across had been tepid but offered some good amount of praise. However at the end, reviewers seemed to have come to a consensus that the book is worth the 720 page read. I figured that I should go read it - starting once the audiobook had been released in early October. All in all, I listened from October 10 to November 7th, a total of 28 days. I listened about an average of 2.5 hours a working day during my commute. I took a short 5 day break in between October 20th to October 25th so that I could listen to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/24106033-career-of-evil&quot;&gt;Career of Evil&lt;/a&gt;, the new Cormoran Strike book by Robert Galbraith - JK Rowling. That was a much needed break because “ALL” (as I will now shorten it to be) was a thoroughly draining experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book follows four friends in New York City. They had just graduated from grad school - the school is not named but it is implied to be Harvard - and they are now starting their lives. They are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Malcolm (Half black, half white): He wants to be an architect. He has rich parents and lives with them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JB (Black): He wants to be an artist. The book notes that his father is dead, but his mother and grandmother consider him their favorite and only child.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Willem (white): He wants to be an actor. The book notes that his parents are both dead and hail from Sweden.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jude (race unsure): He is an orphan, grows up to be a lawyer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While they start out the book struggling to make something of their lives, they end up all very successful. JB becomes a famous artist and painter. Malcolm starts his own architect firm and makes beautiful buildings. Willem is a famous actor who stars in many big movies of all types. Jude becomes a brilliant lawyer who makes millions of dollars. The book never focuses on their success and the author has said that she considers their careers an example of “effort-less success”. The story never really focuses on the difficulty of their careers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While at the start the book focuses equally between all the four friends - occupying their heads and thoughts and exploring their pasts - it very quickly focuses on two in particular: Willem and Jude. JB gets middle treatment and Malcolm basically vanishes as his life turns out to be the most traditional. Malcolm eventually marries a nice woman named Sophie and though they don’t have kids, they live happily. JB gets into some drug trouble but comes out alright in the end. He has a beautiful retrospective of his work and ends up with a nice man (he is gay).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So basically the whole book is about Willem and Jude. They have been the closest friends of the four. Willem - who has a remote but pretty ordinary, happy life - has always stood by Jude, who is smart and funny and soft spoken but seems crippled by his past - physically and emotionally. The book focuses on Jude - I believe that his life is the one the title refers to - reveals that he has suffered at the hands of some cruel people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot about the book that is extraneous detail but suffice it to say is that it is a miracle that Jude manages to survive this and grow out of it to become a successful, high functioning person. That being said, there are still a lot of things wrong with him. For one thing, he is a cutter. He cuts his arms and body so ferociously and steadily and the description of it is so rich and deep that it is incredibly disturbing. It is a persistent thing throughout the entire book, and it disturbs a lot of his own friends. However the cutting is never eradicated throughout the entire book, he simply cannot stop. It keeps him from being violent to others - and I like that metaphor and can recognize that the concept is so alien to us readers that we accept it on its own terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jude also has self esteem and communication issues. He is constantly self aware of the irrationality of his actions and how they are hurting the people around him. Many times he knows what he needs to say but he cannot say it. So he is constantly saying sorry. If I was his friend I would get pretty pissed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is such a huge book that is hard to write a review. How can I encompass a book that is just so overwhelming and just covers so much of a person’s life? And then it ends it in such a way that you feel just so sad. Here are a few motifs and themes that I could not help but notice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Running and the freedom of running&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Self loathing&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Dirtiness, illness, disease, decay&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The drawbacks of success&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can feel that this review is a big confusing mess too. Ugh I don’t want it to be that way but dude just read this book.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/a-little-life-review&quot;&gt;Things I Think About A Little Life&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on November 08, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running in the Rain]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/running-in-the-rain" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/running-in-the-rain</id>
  <published>2015-11-02T00:00:00-08:00</published>
  <updated>2015-11-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I must be feeling particularly self congratulatory today if I am thinking about writing a post like this - a weird but not too weird habit that I have been recently taken up - but I feel like you dear reader must be a bit tired of all the coding posts that I have put up lately. I know, my coding posts are not that coherent. They tend to be just the ravings of a man who has been in the bear’s lair for a while and as a result has ended up a bit too hairy and hoary for his own good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It rained for the first time in several months today this morning. Sucks that it happened during a Monday morning, but the entire West Coast has been in need of rain so I didn’t really mind. In fact, I had been a little excited to get out there that morning and let me tell you why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in 2012 or 2013 I had lived on a shoestring budget and with very little possessions. Didn’t own more than two pair of shoes. I went to work and exercised in the same shoes. This caused a problem if it rained during my morning run because those shoes would get soaking wet and then I would have to spend the rest of the day working in these wet disgusting things. But what was I to do when it was raining? What can I do? The solution that I figured for myself was classic Jonathan - just go out there and run barefeet. I didn’t need to buy new socks or anything. I just go out there and run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recall back in high school I once ran a race against this classmate named Kevin Nousome. He was a small little man with a squeaky voice. Didn’t seem like a runner. I was at the time quite proud of my sprinting and challenged him to a race. We lined up on the yellow gravel sand and I realized that he wasn’t wearing shoes! I thought it was the most bizarre thing, and figured that I was going to paste him. I had shoes after all. Yet he pasted me instead. I can remember it now. I started off with a bang and then quickly saw him on his short little legs just pacing off several lengths ahead of me. I had never seen a little guy run so fast - let alone barefoot - and the sight of it was so ridiculous that I couldn’t keep from laughing. I never finished the race because I was bowled over on the ground guffawing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That mental image comes back to me a lot as I make my rounds in the rain without any shoes, making sure to gingerly avoid rocks and such. I feel the impact of my heel’s skin hitting the concrete path, the sting of it somewhat assuaged by the cool temperature of the wet surface. I can hear the repeated, rhythmic clap of the foot setting down and planting. I feel myself taking shorter but quicker strides, but overall I don’t feel that I am going any slower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes people - whatever peopel who find themselves outside in the rain at 5 AM - would pace by me and wonder why this guy would not have any shoes on. “Hey you don’t have any shoes!” someone once shouted from his car. It was so weird of him to do that. Of course I don’t have shoes. Why would I not be aware of that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find the best ideas of the day come to me while I am jogging. It is the only time of the day that I truly have to myself, without the sound of the music I play or the audiobooks that I listen to. Just quiet. Just concentration with my own thoughts. But the mornings when I am jogging barefoot in the rain are something extra special. I just wanted to share that with you, friend. You should try it too, maybe.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/running-in-the-rain&quot;&gt;Running in the Rain&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on November 02, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[RedditTV]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/redditTV" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/redditTV</id>
  <published>2015-10-18T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2015-10-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I like to read Reddit on my spare time and I came across a post that talked about possibly making a Reddit TV app for the new upcoming Apple TV. I had also thought that this was a great idea and secretly thought that I would go ahead and tackle that as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got pretty deep into the development of the app before coming across a show-stopping feature blocker that pretty much cripples the app for use in production. I decided that instead of consigning the work to the dustbin that I would put it out there &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jonathanstyu/redditTelevision&quot;&gt;into the world&lt;/a&gt;. At least it shows that I was just sitting around with my hands under my pants all this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-the-app-is-structured&quot;&gt;How the App is Structured&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is structured in a way similar to that of my other apps: There are two viewcontrollers: One shows a menu with a number of videos in a UICollectionView. The other is what is shown when someone actually clicks on a video. This is where we should see a video playing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to make it easier to handle the download and other certain factorized logic, I created two files called UIFactory and URLFactory. The UIFactory never got a chance to do much. In my basketball app mostly what it did was to put together repetitive programmatically generated UIKit visual items like buttons. In this case all it does is generate a randomly selected background color. Because tvOS is so new, we have to do a lot of things from scratch. There are no available CocoaPods, including my normal menagerie of color utility tools. This means you gotta roll up your sleeves and bring your own beers to the party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MenuViewController has the UICollectionView, which is instantiated in MenuVC-Coll.swift file. Most of the stuff in the file is ordinary and normal for UICollectionView. However, the interesting thing is the code below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;func collectionView(collectionView: UICollectionView, canFocusItemAtIndexPath indexPath: NSIndexPath) -&amp;gt; Bool {
        return true
    }

func collectionView(collectionView: UICollectionView, shouldHighlightItemAtIndexPath indexPath: NSIndexPath) -&amp;gt; Bool {
    print(&quot;Hello!!! \(channels[indexPath.row])&quot;)
    return true
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code above addresses the focus engine, the newest and most exciting thing about tvOS. Problem is that there are not a lot to read about making it work outside of the rather sparse code provided by Apple. The closest I got to it was &lt;a href=&quot;http://nerds.airbnb.com/tvos-focus-engine/&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; from AirBnB engineering. I think it will help but the gist of what I got is that the tvOS focus engine has a bunch of additional methods that you gotta call so that you can work on the effects that you want to create when someone focuses on the particular cell. This function can then be passed down to the individual cell that is in the Collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;thumbnail = UIImageView()
thumbnail.adjustsImageWhenAncestorFocused = true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So apparently now the behavior has been set that when the cell is focused on, the thumbnail image expands to indicate that the cursor is on it. Cool default behavior, Apple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the app is a pretty simple UICollectionView. I am coming across some sort of bug with the UICollectionViewCell is displaying the wrong thumbnail. This is likely due to the code reusing and recycling a cached image before the image is properly downloaded from the source. I am honestly just too lazy to deal with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-show-stopper&quot;&gt;The Show Stopper&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I did not progress with this app is that it cannot play YouTube videos. The usual accepted way to display YT video in an app is to create a UIWebView and have it play the video. This is how the general YT iOS plugin works. The difference is that Apple removed UIWebView from tvOS. This is likely for performance and usage reasons. The only available video player works by using an underlying mp4 file. I don’t have access to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reviewed some StackExchange answers to figure out how to get around this. I came across &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/32528624/how-to-play-youtube-content-on-tvos&quot;&gt;this thread&lt;/a&gt; that discusses using some sort of workaround that cracks open the YouTube link’s stream and accesses the underlying video file. Naturally this is hella against the TOS. Then Apple finally chimed in and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;There is no support for WebViews on tvOS, and so an iframe implementation will not work. TVML does not offer this capability.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my former coworker Paul used to say all the time, “Goddammit”. I am sure that at some point that YouTube is going to figure out a way to handle this but until then I am going to leave it as it is. Maybe other people can take a look at it and get something useful out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;thoughts-on-tvos&quot;&gt;Thoughts on tvOS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“TVML is Some Scary Shit”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am no HTML and JS master, okay, so take this with a grain of salt. But I don’t like switching between too many windows and IDEs and right now when I am trying to develop in TVML I am switching between Chrome, XCode, iOS Simulator, TextMate and whatever code samples I have on the screen right now. That is just too much. Does XCode do some sort of support for code highlighting for its TVML language? It doesn’t even format the spacing all that well there. Not my most pleasant coding experience and code completion is not present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What They Took Out Kinda Makes Sense&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean it sucks that they took out UIWebView (and I suppose you can make some sort of argument about keeping some crippled version behind on it - and the total list can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://ericasadun.com/2015/09/10/apple-tv-lessons-6-uikit-differences-for-tvos/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) but of what else they took out, much of it makes sense to me. For example, they took out UIActionSheet, which is something I had used fairly often but it makes sense to me. How can you manipulate a menu like that with a TV remote? (See below) So it makes sense to dump it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There’s Still A Lot of Overlap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is good and I briefly considered turning the tvOS app into an iOS one before going nah and moving on with my life - there is already a redditTV app on the App Store and it’s pretty good. I think if I were to come across a new idea then I would probably find it pretty easy to move back into that world - focus Engine notwithstanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using the iOS Simulator is Infuriating&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this was the most irritating part of using the whole thing. It pops up fine and all but then in order to navigate around you have to go and click into the menu to find this crappy ass remote so that we can move around the cursor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/crappy-remote.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Crappy Ass Remote&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You got to hold down the OPTION button and then paw about with the cursor over the digital remote field. “Cursor” is the appropriate term for what it is and the appropriate term for who I am while using it. It does not work for a while and then suddenly does. Then it stops working because the cursor is off the TV remote field. Just … ugh. Is this what it is going to be like with the actual thing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####Conclusion (or TLDR)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tvOS sounded fun and I had a lot of fun writing what I got through so far. If I can come up with an idea for the future then I would definitely work on the SDK again. I hate that remote. YouTube won’t work without UIWebView so without UIWebView this app doesn’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/redditTV&quot;&gt;RedditTV&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on October 18, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing ThunderFonts]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/introducing-thunderfonts" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/introducing-thunderfonts</id>
  <published>2015-10-07T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2015-10-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Things have been just so busy lately with stuff at work that it has been hard to get a new post out. I apologize to my nonexistent readers. In this new post I would like to introduce yet another app: ThunderFonts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/tf-icon.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is right now submitted to the App Store and might not get approved, but I thought that it would be fun to write about again and reflect on the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea for ThunderFonts came from me stumbling across this little plugin on GitHub, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Yalantis/Koloda&quot;&gt;Koloda&lt;/a&gt;, which gives you this out of the box Tinder swipe item. I looked at it under the hood and found it really well written. IT takes in a lot of cool visual effects like from Facebook Pop so to give that feeling of smoothness and transition. In order to write something like that myself it would have taken me a very long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I start a new XCode project, I give it a funny name that is basically the reason to make this thing. In this case it is going to be TinderFonts. It is a way to swipe between a lot of different fonts on the iOS system and learn a bit about them. Simple concept, and I hoped that it would be Store-ready within a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had in my mind a very simple visual setup. A swipe interface and a rolling collection view right below it that would show the right-swipes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/tf-page.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was surprised just how quickly it took to get the basics. I had a working swipe interface within 2 days of creating the project and dumped in a few cards (with fonts on them) a few days later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began to hit on problems though when implementing the less heralded features like the part where it saves a card that you have created to the internal store. The problem was that since I was generating the card randomly with random numbers I could not really easily just save the settings. There was no sanctioned iOS way to turn a UIView into a JPG or PNG other than to programmatically take a screenshot. This caused problems because the way I first conceived it, the screenshot would be taken as the card vanished off the swipe board. I had to rejigger the code so that it would take the screenshot the second that the card appeared. If the person swiped left then the image was discarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/tf-swipe.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the real fascinating thing about this project is just how much of the components I really enjoyed using. This is the first time I used a UICollectionView, which is the little image card that you see at the bottom of the screen. I was worried that it would be hard to make but it turns out to be super easy. I wanted to put in iADs page at the bottom. That turned out to be super easy too. Apple’s API for that turned out to be as simple as pie. Just initialize the thing and drop it in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;other-thoughts&quot;&gt;Other Thoughts&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The problem with not building anything yourself is that you are not sure what is going on within the component. I built almost everything with HakkerJobs. I did not do the same with this one. I pulled together all sorts of plugins and while it certainly did a whole lot to get the project up faster than ever, it did make the whole thing feel a bit cheaper than if I were to make it myself.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Autolayout is a real pain sometimes. I generate all the components on my screen programmatically, which lets me avoid Interface Builder. This is my preference. However, in order to adapt to all sorts of different device sizes, I create autlayouts programmatically - most often using SnapKit to build the preferences. The problem is that because all of these layouts are created in relation to each other, it can be sometimes that a subview does not layout properly because its superview is still being generated. I had to spend a lot of time reading the Apple API to learn when specifically to place the autolayout code so that when the relative restrictions come into effect the superview exists and has the proper sizes. Viewdidload is too early, viewdidappear is too late, gah!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed making ThunderFonts but I don’t think there was a lot to do with it once I had the basic thing going. I had imagined that I would do these dazzling animations and video gifs and all but I lost interest in that very quickly. I was ready to do something else. That being said, a lot of the code that you see here is going to get recycled into my next project - which I am still throwing myself at right now. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/introducing-thunderfonts&quot;&gt;Introducing ThunderFonts&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on October 07, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[9 Articles To Move You]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/9-articles-to-move-you" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/9-articles-to-move-you</id>
  <published>2015-08-30T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2015-08-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Because we don’t always have internet on a flight (though that is changing), I spend a lot of time perusing the Instapaper archives on my phone and reading/re-reading anything interesting. Over the years that I have had that account, I have read a whole bunch of things. In this article, I want to share the few that have really stood out to me that most people don’t already know about. Don’t we all have the urge to share what we have with others?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t really have a criteria for choosing what goes in here - there is going to be a lot of variation - other than some vague, ineffable feeling that reading this has made me feel more connected to human society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-did-jesus-do1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2010/05/24/what-did-jesus-do&quot;&gt;What Did Jesus Do?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a religious person, but I used to be. While the fervor of God has left me, what has not vanished is the yearning to be closer to Jesus. This time though, as a person and a historical figure. Who was he? What did he do? What was he like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article does a better job than any other I have ever read at rendering the man. The Jesus that comes through in these words feels human but still ever so tantalizingly far away. It is remarkable the techniques, research, and insight brought to bear on better understanding the brief life of a man who died nearly 2,000 years ago. This is not an article JUST for atheists. Anyone of faith should read this too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passage of Choice: &lt;strong&gt;“While accepting a historical Jesus, the scholarship also tends to suggest that the search for him is a little like the search for the historical Sherlock Holmes: there were intellectual-minded detectives around, and Conan Doyle had one in mind in the eighteen-eighties, but the really interesting bits—Watson, Irene Adler, Moriarty, and the Reichenbach Falls—were, even if they all had remote real-life sources, shaped by the needs of storytelling, not by traces of truth.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-unfinished2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2009/03/09/the-unfinished&quot;&gt;The Unfinished&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Foster Wallace seems to be like one of those artists whose art becomes super popular after he dies. It seems like everyone has passed around the little college graduation speech “This is Water” on Facebook some time or another. I never read “Infinite Jest” (though I tried to read “The Pale King” and found it rather dry) but you do not need to in order to really enjoy this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is so amazing about it is that it is more than just a biography of DFW, but also an in-depth analysis of his work and what he stood for. It is the Cliff’s Notes for what he writes about and when you read it you can suddenly sound super-smart (or like an angsty emo teenager) for repeating it at brunches. I sound mean but it comes from a loving place in my heart - it really is some eye opening stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passage of Choice: &lt;strong&gt;“His goal had been to show readers how to live a fulfilled, meaningful life. ‘Fiction’s about what it is to be a fucking human being,’ he once said. Good writing should help readers to ‘become less alone inside.’ Wallace’s desire to write ‘morally passionate, passionately moral fiction,’“&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-brevard-woman-disappeared-but-never-left-home3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tampabay.com/news/humaninterest/a-brevard-woman-disappeared-but-never-left-home/1181888&quot;&gt;A Brevard Woman Disappeared, But Never Left Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get dark a bit, shall we? This story has never left me from the very moment that I first laid eyes on it. It is the real life chronicle of a now-forgotten human being. Had it not been for this web article, I would have never heard of this woman and she would be forever lost in the sands of time. Kathryn Norris lived a sad life tormented by mental illness. This article brings you into her existence as it slowly spirals towards its heart-breaking end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My greatest fear in life is to lose awareness of my own self. I am especially afraid of dementia and mental illness. I have always prided myself in my own clear thinking. It might be random and scatterbrained, but it knows where it is. Kathryn’s brain stopped working right, her unwitting body marched right to its malfunctioning signals, and society failed to stop both of them. I don’t ever want this to happen to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passage of Choice: &lt;strong&gt;“‘I have learned I attach myself to one person,’ she said, ‘and they become my safety person.’ And if there’s no safety person? ‘I stay within my home.’“&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-hunt-for-el-chapo4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2014/05/05/the-hunt-for-el-chapo&quot;&gt;The Hunt For El Chapo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that Mr. Chapo is free again, this article rings a little hollow but don’t let the present get you down. This is probably the most exciting piece of writing that I have read in years. More thrilling than any cyber-crime or Dan Brown piece of fiction out there. It is clipped, brusque, peppered with the right quotes and the right moments. Narrow escapes, brutal gunfights, and a mysterious, elusive rabbit. You want to read this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are making a movie out of this article, and I am going to tell you that they made a great choice in picking the source material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passage of Choice: &lt;strong&gt;“There is a saying in the Mexican drug trade that it is better to live one good year than ten bad ones.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-then-steve-said-let-there-be-an-iphone5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mobile.nytimes.com/2013/10/06/magazine/and-then-steve-said-let-there-be-an-iphone.html?pagewanted=all&amp;amp;_r=0&quot;&gt;And Then Steve Said, ‘Let There Be an iPhone’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our society can be cut into two time periods - before the iPhone and after. I believe that when it is all said and done the iPhone will be the most impactful consumer device ever created in the century. When you watch the 2007 keynote, it is amazing to think about just how similar the original iPhone was to the iPhones of today. The old one does feel a bit dated, but the intention and capability do not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story is elegantly written, a compelling chronicle of how history was made. It gives a great sense of just how hard hard things are. So many things had to go right for the iPhone to exist. So much can go wrong that it really shouldn’t exist. Yet here it is. While there is a sort of “Steve Jobs is gone, uh oh” attitude in the whole thing which I do not totally appreciate, what you can really enjoy is just the sprint of effort taken towards making this incredible product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passage of Choice: &lt;strong&gt;“When you look back at how the iPhone came to be, it’s clear that it had everything to do with the unreasonable demands — and unusual power — of an inimitable man.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;life-in-the-dark6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aeon.co/magazine/science/can-life-exist-on-a-planet-without-a-star/&quot;&gt;Life in the Dark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to always be reading writing that expands your mind and broadens our own limitations. I think too many times, people take that to mean spiritually or emotionally. They find their values tested, their own expectations taken to the limits. That is fine and a form of growth too. However sometimes we need to have our own scientific imagination tested too. This article was able to do that for me in a more elegant, clear way than any other that I have read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is really hard to convey a complex idea to a person who is not familiar with it. Great leaps and realizations do not come about alone. They are built towards and quietly grown before abruptly exploding into revelatory prominence. This article does a great job of forwarding an insane idea - an idea that removes the one thing that we will always have in our lives - the very sun itself. Can life live without a sun? Can we even comprehend such a thing? This article seeks to do this, and take you along for the ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passage of Choice: &lt;strong&gt;“Instead of having one ‘photosynthetic’ tree growing 1,000 apples, it would need 1,000 ‘chemoautotrophic’ trees growing one apple each.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;envy7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theguardian.com/books/2003/jun/22/extract?cat=books&amp;amp;type=article&quot;&gt;Envy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is rather old, about 12 years now. It has no names, but I think it is not that hard to guess (and if you want to, you can do a quick Google search). It is an essay about a woman who despite having so much, who seems to be so obviously talented, still feels incredibly unfulfilled as compared to her partner, a now-famous novelist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is really naturally easy for me to get jealous. It is true. I am a jealous person. I resent other’s people success and I revel in their failures. Sometimes I try to give a reason for this - that I am a person who is himself beset with failure - and so that it is just projection. But then there are the days where I realize the truth: That I am just envious, and I am a terrible person for feeling it. I’ve never came across another piece of writing that so clearly, coherently puts down how I feel into words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passage of Choice: &lt;strong&gt;“No, this was a genuinely excellent piece of work by a man who had dedicated his life to doing such work and was now being rewarded for it: proof that the system was not essentially corrupt and misguided, incapable of recognising true merit, after all. Where was the comfort in that?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;from-idea-to-appstore-in-2-weeks8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alasdairmonk.com/journal/from-idea-to-appstore-in-2-weeks/&quot;&gt;From idea to AppStore in 2 weeks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is kinda weird that in between of all of these inspirational, knowledge-filled articles that we have something like this. It is just a normal blog post right? In one way you are right. It is indeed just another blog post - like the type you will find frequently on HackerNews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is different for me though. Reading this blog post changed something in me. Before, I think I had just dabbled in programming. I played around with it. It was interesting, but I figured that I did not major in it during school so I had no chance or hope of being a career programmer. After reading, I knew that I could do it. It was possible. They say in How I Met Your Moment the “breaking glass” moment. It is that moment when you realize something. Reading this blog post was the breaking glass moment for me. I realized I didn’t need to get permission from a past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passage of Choice: &lt;strong&gt;“But you will do it, and you’ll have the weakened fingers and strained bloodshot eyes to prove it.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;breaking-bad-news9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://moreintelligentlife.com/content/ideas/breaking-bad-news?page=full&quot;&gt;Breaking Bad News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saved the most powerful for last. I have never read this the whole way through and not broken down crying and sobbing. This article is everything that I have ever believed reading should be. Reading should be informative, enlightening, &lt;strong&gt;life-expanding&lt;/strong&gt;, and connective. This is a piece about death, but not the person who dies, but the ones who death leaves behind. This is about delivering grief from the perspective of a person who is intimately involved, but unable to truly empathize. How would you do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Death is something we all have to eventually experience - and I got a good reminder of that yesterday. Yesterday afternoon I was glancing down at my phone at the intersection, waiting for the light to turn green. I glanced up through my sunglasses, saw the countdown at 13 already, and stepped abruptly without looking at my surroundings. A large truck goes in to make a right but sees me there and hits the brakes hard. The truck hits me, not badly but enough to jerk. I look up and see the driver, a nice family man in there, with two little girls. I’m okay. It’s my fault. I nod to him, trying to tell him that I am okay and hurriedly scramble off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While safely on the other side, I look back at the truck and think, “What just happened?” Had the driver been not so aware, if he had been spacing as much as I had been, then I would have been killed. One second of daze and then that’s it. And then someone would have to tell people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at home, I took out this article and re-read it again. I thought about my family, my friends, and my loved ones. And then of course I am crying again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passage of Choice: &lt;em&gt;The last line.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/9-articles-to-move-you&quot;&gt;9 Articles To Move You&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on August 30, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing HakkerJobs]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://jonathanstyu.github.io/introducing-hakkerjobs" />
  <id>http://jonathanstyu.github.io/introducing-hakkerjobs</id>
  <published>2015-08-16T00:00:00-07:00</published>
  <updated>2015-08-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Yu</name>
    <uri>http://jonathanstyu.github.io</uri>
    <email>jonathan@jonathanyu.net</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/jumpshot-2-basketball-stat/id1018699409&quot;&gt;JumpShot 2&lt;/a&gt; on July 13, 2015 but just when it was hitting the App Store, I was already thinking about the next app that I should make. This would be the fourth app that I would make and the second that would tap into an online API. I needed an idea and this one came to me while I was browsing the monthly automated thread: “Who is Hiring?” Hackernews. I found myself irritated that it was not all that easy to read the content that came out of it. It is a web thread, yes, but at the same time it has a lot of valuable information inside. But it is all about in a mumbo jumbo and not that easy to work with, not to mention read. I wanted at least a better way to read all those listings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One month later, I am introducing to you &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hakkerjobs-hackernews-client/id1028168255&quot;&gt;HakkerJobs&lt;/a&gt;, a Hackernews client specifically for finding jobs. A few days ago I submitted it to the App Store. Who knows if it gets approved, but I wanted to sit and reflect a bit on the effort that went into making it and what I have learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jonathanstyu/jonathanstyu.github.com/master/images/HJ-Preview.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lessons&quot;&gt;Lessons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The key is to do it fast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JumpShot 2 had been such a long and grueling slog (the entire project went 5 months in between initial commit and last commit) that I was not sure if I wanted to do another programming project. I thought about going out and starting on a new book or something. It was only because the idea was so compelling that I decided to dive back into Xcode again. I was not sure if I wanted to spend another few months fiddling with code. For a long time I had no idea why I found going fast such a powerful concept but I felt that &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsomers.net/blog/speed-matters&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; really nails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you work quickly, the cost of doing something new will seem lower in your mind. So you’ll be inclined to do more.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Underwriting this concept, I wrote HakkerJobs within a month. The unskinned, no-feature prototype was committed in 20 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of reasons HakkerJobs got done so much faster. One is that the app does not need to extensively use fancy-shmancy layouts. It is a blunt simple thing: It reads a feed, presents it thoughtfully, and lets you do stuff with it. The things that did take time to organize and arrange though I used a few libraries (but not too many as see below) like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/SnapKit/SnapKit&quot;&gt;SnapKit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, I reused a lot of code from Jump Shot 2. If you could look at the code behind the app you would find a lot of similarities. Certain products and features that took hours for me to understand when going through it the first time I quickly recognized and fixed with a simple copy-and-paste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, I just spent more time at HakkerJobs. Instead of working on it during the weekends, I wrote code - even just a little bit - during my commute home from San Francisco. I was tired a lot, but much better to get this done so quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build as much as you can on your own (the less plugins the better)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest problems that I came across came at the end of finishing Jump Shot 2. I had used a vast array of plugins and downloads to make the app do what it needed to do which led to HUGE errors when archiving and compiling the final app product. So much of the code was not mine, I had no idea what was broken! But I could not do anything about it because I had already designed the feature around this plugin (called a Cocoapod). At the end of it, I had this crippling Xcode compiling error that took a full 3 days to resolve - and I only resolved it by creating an ENTIRELY NEW Xcode project and transferring the core files to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This in addition to a new upcoming transition that was making everything a bit more challenging. Xcode 7 had been released along with iOS 9 and Swift 2.0. Brand new code that changes everything across the board. Not all of the projects that I had been relying on would capably bridge the transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, I wanted to keep only the things that were absolutely necessary. I kept things that helped me with layouts (SnapKit) and simple things like customer onboarding (Like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ealeksandrov/EAIntroView&quot;&gt;EAIntroView&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s Next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the app gets some traction and people like it, the next things that I would need to work on is obviously filtering. People want to be able to easily filter through jobs that don’t meet their criteria (job tasks, location, salary, etc.). Problem is that I am not quite sure how to do that. The job posts are in natural language with little structure (oh why, people, why?!). Sometimes there are multiple jobs, multiple criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until I come across my next app or thing idea, I will be tweaking and tinkering with some natural language libraries like NSLinguisticTagger (already built in the app but not used yet) to see where I can take this next.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io/introducing-hakkerjobs&quot;&gt;Introducing HakkerJobs&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Yu at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonathanstyu.github.io&quot;&gt;Perfect Perusals&lt;/a&gt; on August 16, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>